<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <event name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR" unique="true">
    <text>You arrive at a smoldering Engi research station, its distress call unanswered - attacked by pirates or Mantis most likely. There may be someone left alive, or else something of value left on board.</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Board the station.</text>
      <eventList name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_LIST1">
        <event>
          <text>You send an away team to investigate, but there's nothing save for the acidic stench of burnt Engi parts. This place is dead.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Your away team reports a wounded Engi and a functioning drone schematic. Then someone yells. The station reactor is overloading and they're running out of time!</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Save the Engi!</text>
            <eventList name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_ENGI">
              <event>
                <text>One of your crew valiantly grabs the Engi and throws it into the airlock right before the reactor blows and the automatic blast doors slam shut. You have no choice but to mourn their sacrifice and move on.</text>
                <removeCrew>
                  <clone>true</clone>
                  <text>The brave crewmember's clone strides from the Clone Bay, rather full of themself after such a heroic act.</text>
                </removeCrew>
                <choice hidden="true">
                  <text id="continue"/>
                  <event>
                    <text>The Engi who was saved offers to join your crew.</text>
                    <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
                    <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
                  </event>
                </choice>
              </event>
              <event>
                <text>Your crew return safely to the airlock with the injured Engi and you put some distance on the station before it blows. The Engi, impressed by your crew, volunteers to join you.</text>
                <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
                <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
              </event>
            </eventList>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Save the drone schematic.</text>
            <eventList name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_DRONE">
              <event>
                <text>Your away team heads home with the goods, but as they transfer back to the ship a small explosion blows the airlock and one of the crew is sucked out into space!</text>
                <removeCrew>
                  <clone>true</clone>
                  <text>Fortunately, your crewmember was close enough to the ship for the Clone Bay to revive them.</text>
                </removeCrew>
                <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
              </event>
              <event>
                <text>The Engi don't feel things the same way other species do. They'd want the tech to be saved. Your crew return safely to the airlock with the drone control and you put some distance on the station before it blows.</text>
                <autoReward level="LOW">drone</autoReward>
              </event>
            </eventList>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Save yourselves!</text>
            <event>
              <text>It's a tough order, but your crew's lives are the priority. They drop everything and return to the ship unharmed. You put some distance on the station before it blows.</text>
              <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
            </event>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Ignore it.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The place looks in bad state, probably nothing of use there. Time to move on.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="sensors" lvl="2">
      <text>(Improved Sensors) Run another scan.</text>
      <event name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_SCAN">
        <text>Scans reveal the station's reactor is overloading! Not only that, but an injured Engi and a functioning drone schematic are still on board! There's not time for both...</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Save the Engi!</text>
          <event>
            <text>Your away team heads straight for the Engi and returns with time to spare. You put some distance on the station before it blows and the Engi is so impressed by your crew that they volunteer to join you!</text>
            <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
            <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Save the Drone Schematic!</text>
          <event>
            <text>The Engi don't feel things the same way other species do. They'd want the tech to be saved. Your away team heads straight for the goods and returns with time to spare. You put some distance on the station before it blows.</text>
            <autoReward level="LOW">drone</autoReward>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="ADV_SCANNERS">
      <text>(Warped Scanners) Run another scan.</text>
      <event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_SCAN"/>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>