<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NEUTRAL_ENGI">
    <event load="ENGI_IMMEDIATE_SURRENDER"/>
    <event load="ALISON_MANTIS_CREW"/>
    <event load="ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS"/>
    <event load="ENGI_LOOT"/>
  </eventList>

  <eventList name="NEUTRAL_ENGI_RESEARCH">
    <event load="ENGI_IMMEDIATE_SURRENDER"/>
    <event load="ALISON_MANTIS_CREW"/>
    <event load="ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS"/>
    <event load="ENGI_LOOT"/>
    <event load="ENGI_SEX"/>
    <event load="ENGI_SELLING_SENSORS"/>
  </eventList>

  <changelog>
    <entry>ENGI_SURRENDER has an option to attack the Engi ship</entry>
    <entry>If you choose to explain that you're friendly in ENGI_SURRENDER, you have a chance to also get a free map reveal</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="ENGI_IMMEDIATE_SURRENDER" unique="true">
    <text>An Engi ship in the vicinity, seeing you jump in armed to the teeth, immediately broadcasts its surrender: "Subject goal: wealth. Engi motivation: survival. Transfer of goods acceptable?"</text>
    <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_CIRCLE" hostile="false">
      <surrender chance="0.5" min="2" max="2" load="ENGI_SURRENDER"/>
      <escape timer="40" min="22" max="22" load="PIRATE_ESCAPE"/>
      <destroyed load="DESTROYED_DEFAULT"/>
      <deadCrew load="DEAD_CREW_DEFAULT"/>
    </ship>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Explain that you're friendly.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>The Engi seem relieved, and eager to get underway. They set off without saying goodbye.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The Engi are satisfied with your explanation. "Beneficial. Subject goal: long, long journey. Remains compatible with transfer of goods from Engi." They send over the gear willingly, and you feel better for it.</text>
          <autoReward level="RANDOM">stuff</autoReward>
          <reveal_map/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Accept their offer of surrender.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Engi obediently transfer over the goods and get on their way. Money for nothing.</text>
        <autoReward level="RANDOM">stuff</autoReward>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the ship anyway.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ALISON_MANTIS_CREW" unique="true">
    <text>You arrive just in time to see an unusually well-armed Engi ship destroying a small pirate craft. A teleporter signal is detected...intruder on deck!</text>
    <choice>
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event>
        <text>A young Mantis in a charred uniform has teleported onto the deck. He begs for sanctuary from the Engi, and offers to serve in exchange for your protection. The Engi have already traced the teleporter signal and are offering a deal in exchange for the prisoner.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Side with the fugitive and fight the Engi ship.</text>
          <eventList name="ALISON_MANTIS_CREW_HELP">
            <event>
              <text>It was a trap! The Mantis sabotages your ship before teleporting away.</text>
              <damage amount="3"/>
              <damage amount="1" system="random"/>
              <damage amount="1" system="room"/>
              <ship load="ENGI_MANTIS_CONTROLLED" hostile="true"/>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>He expresses his thanks and prepares to help you fight his pursuer.</text>
              <ship load="ENGI_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
              <crewMember amount="1" class="mantis"/>
            </event>
          </eventList>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Agree to offer up the Mantis in exchange for a bounty.</text>
          <eventList name="ALISON_MANTIS_CREW_REJECT">
            <event>
              <text>The Engi captain is delighted, and quickly arranges for the transfer of the prisoner.</text>
              <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>Fury sparks in the eyes of the Mantis. He won't go easily, and causes serious damage before he can be captured.</text>
              <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
              <damage amount="4"/>
              <damage amount="1" system="room" effect="fire"/>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>The pursuing ship responds with a completely unintelligible message. The young Mantis jerks to attention and assumes a battle stance. It was a trap!</text>
              <boarders min="1" max="1" class="mantis"/>
              <ship load="ENGI_MANTIS_CONTROLLED" hostile="true"/>
            </event>
          </eventList>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added a distress signal to ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS" unique="true">
    <text>You receive a distress call from a nearby Engi ship. "Assistance requested. Danger present. Imminent destruction."</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <choice>
      <text>Respond to the call and move in to assist.</text>
      <eventList name="ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS_LIST">
        <event>
          <text>You receive another message from the ship, this time with a Mantis at the comm-log. "Foolish meatsacks," he yells. Sensors indicate the ship is moving in to attack and boarders teleport from the station.</text>
          <ship load="ENGI_MANTIS_CONTROLLED" hostile="true"/>
          <boarders min="1" max="2" class="mantis"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You approach to find a Mantis ship assaulting a small Engi space station. You prepare for a fight!</text>
          <ship name="MANTIS_ENGI_STATION" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_MANTIS" hostile="true">
            <destroyed>
              <text>The Mantis ship breaks apart.</text>
              <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>Attempt to contact the Engi.</text>
                <event load="SAVE_ENGI_STATION"/>
              </choice>
            </destroyed>
            <deadCrew>
              <text>No more life signs detected on the Mantis ship. You hasten to contact the Engi.</text>
              <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>Attempt to contact the Engi.</text>
                <event load="SAVE_ENGI_STATION"/>
              </choice>
            </deadCrew>
            <crew>
              <crewMember type="mantis" prop="0.80"/>
              <crewMember type="engi" prop="0.20"/>
            </crew>
          </ship>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Keep your distance.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="SAVE_ENGI_STATION">
    <event>
      <text>The Engi station is stripped bare and there are signs of a fierce battle. The Mantis must have left the distress call active to lure other ships into a trap.</text>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The station was in the process of being evacuated. A number of civilian Engi offer their gratitude as they finalize their preparations to leave. They offer some fuel as a reward.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">fuel_only</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The station hails you, "Gratitude. Expected probability of defeat without assistance... 86.2 percent. Request suitable reward."</text>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Request fuel.</text>
        <event>
          <text>"Request granted. Fuel transferring."</text>
          <autoReward level="HIGH">fuel_only</autoReward>
        </event>
      </choice>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Request a weapon.</text>
        <event>
          <text>"Request granted. Weapon transferring."</text>
          <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
        </event>
      </choice>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Request a drone.</text>
        <event>
          <text>"Request granted. Drone schematic transferring."</text>
          <drone name="RANDOM"/>
        </event>
      </choice>
      <choice req="engi" hidden="true">
        <text>(Engi Crew) Threat unresolved. Current mission imperative: Protocol 52.34.</text>
        <event>
          <text>They respond, "Understood. Re-establishment of Federation highest import. Transmitting hidden base coordinates. Repairing hull and attaching ship to ship ordnance."</text>
          <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
          <quest event="HIDDEN_FEDERATION_BASE_LIST"/>
          <damage amount="-10"/>
        </event>
      </choice>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>They thank you for the assistance and when you tell them of your mission, one of the Engi asks if they can assist your crew. You welcome them aboard.</text>
      <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
    </event>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ENGI_SEX" unique="true">
    <text>What appeared to be a single damaged ship is in fact two ships that have smashed into each other... there is a flurry of comm signals and damage, and it's hard to determine what occurred. The vessels appear to be... Engi? They look locked together by the impact and can't free themselves.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attempt to help the ships by prying them apart.</text>
      <event>
        <text>To your surprise, one of the Engi vessels attacks! One ship detaches itself, surprisingly still quite whole, and opens fire - it looks like it's somehow identified you as hostile!</text>
        <ship name="ENGI_SEX_SHIP" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_CIRCLE" hostile="true">
          <destroyed>
            <text>With the ship destroyed, the remaining Engi ship hails you frantically and explains the situation to you.</text>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event>
                <text>Apparently, you interrupted the equivalent of a "consolidation" of two ships that were using each other's parts to construct a new vessel. The Engi were not truly hostile, their targeting computers had not finished adjusting. There's nothing to be done about it now. You leave the remains for the surviving ship.</text>
              </event>
            </choice>
          </destroyed>
          <deadCrew>
            <text>With the ship disabled, the remaining Engi ship hails you frantically and explains the situation to you.</text>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event>
                <text>Apparently, you interrupted the equivalent of a "consolidation" of two ships that were using each other's parts to construct a new vessel. The Engi were not truly hostile, their targeting computers had not finished adjusting. There's nothing to be done about it now. You leave the remains for the surviving ship.</text>
              </event>
            </choice>
          </deadCrew>
        </ship>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Ignore the damaged vessels.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="engi">
      <text>(Engi) Have your Engi crewmember hail the vessel and assess the damage.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Your Engi crewmember refuses. In a halting use of adjectives and nouns, followed by some animated holographic aids, the Engi explains the ships are... using each other to, loosely translated, "achieve a union." For some reason, this consolidation of ship matter sounds embarrassing and personal.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <event>
            <text>You elect to leave the two Engi ships... to their "business." After questioning your Engi crewmember, however, you do manage to salvage what scrap parts you can from the perimeter, even though you feel slightly dirty for doing so.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ENGI_LOOT" unique="true">
    <!--text taken from NOTHING_ENGI event -->
    <text>The complex arrangements of ship hulls and FTL drive capacitors floating abandoned in space suggest the Engi were here not too long ago; but no longer.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Search the abandoned hulls.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>You chose a ship to loot at random. It turned out to contain a functioning drone schematic.</text>
          <drone name="RANDOM"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The first ship you stumbled upon was loaded with high quality FTL fuel. You decided not to waste more time here and prepare to jump.</text>
          <autoReward level="HIGH">fuel_only</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Before you managed to get to the closest abandoned ship, an Engi patrol appeared out of nowhere: "Purpose unknown. Question mark." You are prompted to explain yourself.</text>
          <ship load="ENGI_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>"Well, I just wanted to loot some Engi ships."</text>
            <event>
              <text>The Engi ship finds your response offensive and powers its weapons and drones.</text>
              <ship hostile="true"/>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>"I'm leaving already."</text>
            <event/>
          </choice>
          <choice req="engi" hidden="true">
            <text>(Engi) Current mission: 155.02. Target location: 63.14. Assistance required.</text>
            <event>
              <text>The Engi ship responds, "Affirmative. Dispatching necessary resources."</text>
              <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
              <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
            </event>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Don't risk it: charge the FTL drive.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <text>Added Engi ship selling sensors event heavily inspired by Arsenal+ event.</text>
  </changelog>
  <event name="ENGI_SELLING_SENSORS" unique="true">
    <text>An Engi research ship offers a variety of sensors, scanners and detectors for sale. You're looking for options that would fit your ship class.</text>
    <ship load="ENGI_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
    <choice req="sensors" max_lvl="0" blue="false">
      <text>Install the sensors system.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Engi are quick to install a sensors system. While useful for gathering information, you doubt it will be able to function in nebula.</text>
        <system name="sensors"/>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-30" max="-25"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="sensors" max_lvl="1" blue="false">
      <text>Upgrade the sensors system.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Engi are quick to upgrade your sensors system. While useful for gathering information, you doubt it will be able to function in nebula.</text>
        <upgrade amount="1" system="sensors"/>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-20" max="-15"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="sensors" max_lvl="2" blue="false">
      <text>Upgrade the sensors system.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Engi are quick to upgrade your sensors system. While useful for gathering information, you doubt it will be able to function in nebula.</text>
        <upgrade amount="1" system="sensors"/>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-30" max="-20"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Buy a Lifeform scanner.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You transfer the payment but it takes some time for Engi merchants to bring the goods to your ship.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-25" max="-20"/>
        </item_modify>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <eventList>
            <event>
              <text>The Engi install their newest invention, an augmentation, very useful for traversing nebula. Satisfied with your purchase, you prepare to make an FTL jump.</text>
              <augment name="LIFE_SCANNER"/>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>The Engi bring a Slug in a tight capsule, hardly able to move. They have very different interpretations of a 'Lifeform scanner'. Finally free from torturers, the SLug agrees to join your crew for a time.</text>
              <crewMember amount="1" class="slug"/>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>This treatment is unacceptable! Attack the Engi.</text>
                <event>
                  <ship hostile="true"/>
                </event>
              </choice>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>Leave the Engi alone. At least, the SLug is safe with you now.</text>
                <event/>
              </choice>
            </event>
          </eventList>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>