<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Green Planet event to Engi sector</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="ENGI_GREEN_PLANET" unique="true">
    <text>You arrive at a green planet with great plains and rolling waterfalls. It would be of little interest to the Engi nearby.</text>
    <img planet="PLANET_GREEN"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Send the shuttle to the planet.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <!-- metal-eating animals -->
          <text>Your team landed in a shuttle and spreaded out to explore the planet. After a few minutes, a cloud of dust appeared on the horizon. Using optic magnifiers, you could make out a herd of giant long-legged alien beasts.</text>
          <choice blue="false" hidden="true" lvl="0" max_group="0" req="engi">
            <text id="continue"/>
            <event>
              <text>As soon as the animals saw a shuttle made of metallic parts, they charged. The herd moved so fast, that your team was too late to react and the animals managed to eat large parts of shuttle's hull before being driven away. You would need to use all spare scrap to repair the transport.</text>
              <item_modify>
                <item max="-12" min="-15" type="scrap"/>
              </item_modify>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>The exploration team did not find anything useful on the planet and returned with empty hands, understanding why Engi had so little interest in settling there.</text>
                <event/>
              </choice>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice blue="false" hidden="true" lvl="1" max_group="0" req="engi">
            <text id="continue"/>
            <event>
              <text>As soon as the animals saw an Engi, they charged. The herd moved so fast, your team did not have enough time to react. The animals ate the Engi and galloped away, uninterested in attacking anyone else.</text>
              <removeCrew class="engi">
                <clone>true</clone>
                <text>You are sure that the eaten crewmember is already being cloned back on the ship.</text>
              </removeCrew>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text id="continue"/>
                <event>
                  <text>The exploration team did not find anything useful on the planet and returned with empty hands, understanding why Engi had so little interest in settling there.</text>
                </event>
              </choice>
            </event>
          </choice>
        </event>
        <event>
          <!-- windy desert -->
          <text>Even though it seemed that the planet would be full of life after initial scans, after landing the team found nothing but a devastated desert. The winds on the planet are so strong, that organic life is eroded away.</text>
          <choice hidden="true" lvl="2" req="sensors">
            <text>(Advanced Sensors) Scan the landing site thoroughly.</text>
            <event>
              <text>Scanning indicated that there is an abnormal amount of rare metals deep within the soil near the landing site. After hours of drilling, your team excavates a cache left by someone years ago. Probably, pirates.</text>
              <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true" req="LIFE_SCANNER">
            <text>(Lifeform Scanner) Scan the planet again.</text>
            <event>
              <text>It turns out, that the planet is not barren after all. The atmosphere is full of microscopic organisms, that fly very fast, causing the winds. Using the nets, your team captures some of the creatures who are revealed to have high concentration of rare metals in their bodies.</text>
              <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true" req="slug">
            <text>(Slug) A crewmember senses something in the air.</text>
            <event>
              <text>It turns out, that the planet is not barren after all. The atmosphere is full of microscopic organisms, that fly very fast, causing the winds. Using the nets, your team captures some of the creatures who are revealed to have high concentration of rare metals in their bodies.</text>
              <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Leave the planet.</text>
            <event/>
          </choice>
        </event>
        <event>
          <!-- flying reptiles -->
          <text>After landing on the planet, your team learns that it is inhabited by flying reptiles of enormous size. Scanning the surface shows that the lair nearby contains useful materials including rare metals.</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Visit the lair.</text>
            <event>
              <text>Your team approaches the reptile's lair. It is a cave in a giant mountain, far above the surface. Entering the cave using powered exoskeletons will not be difficult, but someone must distract the reptile.</text>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>Order one of your crewmembers to distract the reptile.</text>
                <event>
                  <text>A volunteer makes a distraction, while the rest of the team sneaks into the cave. The reptile eats the sacrificed crewmember alive and returns back to the lair. Your team grabs whatever they can, and gets safely to the shuttle, almost detected by an animal.</text>
                  <removeCrew>
                    <clone>true</clone>
                    <text>The clone of the lost crewmember is ready on the ship, making a note to themselves to never volunteer to distract giant monsters ever again.</text>
                  </removeCrew>
                  <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
                </event>
              </choice>
              <choice hidden="true" req="warped">
                <text>(Warped) Sneak into the cave.</text>
                <event>
                  <text>The Warped successfully sneaks into the cave using their cloak. Your crewmember picks up as much equipment as they can carry, choosing what they deem most valuable: food and everything shiny.</text>
                  <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
                </event>
              </choice>
              <choice hidden="true" req="BATTLE">
                <text>(Anti-Personnel Drone) Use a drone as a distraction.</text>
                <event>
                  <text>The drone makes an excellent distraction, letting your team into the dangerous cave without losses. The team does not have much time, so they grab whatever they see first, what will be used as scrap later.</text>
                  <item_modify>
                    <item max="-1" min="-1" type="drones"/>
                  </item_modify>
                  <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
                </event>
              </choice>
              <choice hidden="true" req="BOARDER_LIST">
                <text>(Boarding Drone) Use a drone as a distraction.</text>
                <event>
                  <text>The drone makes an excellent distraction, letting your team into the dangerous cave without losses. The team does not have much time, so they grab whatever they see first, what will be used as scrap later.</text>
                  <item_modify>
                    <item max="-1" min="-1" type="drones"/>
                  </item_modify>
                  <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
                </event>
              </choice>
              <choice hidden="true" req="BOARDER_ION_LIST">
                <text>(Ion Intruder) Use a drone as a distraction.</text>
                <event>
                  <text>The Ion Intruder distracts the reptile successfully, and even manages to stun it when devoured. Your team has enough time to enter the cave, pick the most valuable equipment there, and leave safely.</text>
                  <item_modify>
                    <item max="-1" min="-1" type="drones"/>
                  </item_modify>
                  <autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
                </event>
              </choice>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>Leave the planet.</text>
                <event/>
              </choice>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Leave the planet.</text>
            <event/>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Jump away.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>