<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <event name="ENGI_ENTERTAINMENT">
    <!--text taken from NOTHING_ENGI event -->
    <text>Even though each "individual" Engi is made up of trillions of nano-machines, their culture still revolves around traditional social interactions. A nearby station seems to be constructed for entertainment of passing Engi travellers.</text>
    <choice>
      <text>Pay an entrance fee.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You pay a small fee and make your way into the station. Most of the Engis are just resting at the bar, and "talking" using emoticons, fragmentary phrases and, mostly, numbers. The main event seems to be going on in the conference hall. It should be worth visiting.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-9" max="-7"/>
        </item_modify>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Visit the conference hall.</text>
          <event load="ENGI_ENTERTAINMENT_STAGE"/>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="slug">
      <text>(Slug) Explain that you absolutely have to get in for free.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The bouncers reluctantly agree and let your crew into the station.Most of the Engis are just resting at the bar, and "talking" using emoticons, fragmentary phrases and, mostly, numbers. The main event seems to be going on in the conference hall, largest room on the station. It should be worth visiting.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Visit the conference hall.</text>
          <event load="ENGI_ENTERTAINMENT_STAGE"/>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>There is no time for entertainment.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <event name="ENGI_ENTERTAINMENT_STAGE">
    <text>You enter the hall, and it looks like you interrupted some sort of a stand up show. The Engi comedian, performing on a makeshift stage, tries really hard at making fun of your crew, but his attempts fall short.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Go on stage yourself.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You have no idea how to entertain the Engis and none of your jokes reach the audience. In the end, you say: "Protocol 8.06". Everyone cringes. You leave the station very embarrassed.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="mantis">
      <text>(Mantis) Send your crewmember to the stage to perform next.</text>
      <event>
        <text>As the Mantis moves towards the stage, the previous comedian drops the mic and runs away in fear. The audience, visibly afraid, makes a line to the exit. The Mantis makes a great performance... to an empty hall. After some time, security kicks you out.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="rock">
      <text>(Rockman) Send your crewmember to the stage to perform next.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Rockman goes up on stage and makes a silly face. Then another one. It seems that the entire comedy culture of Rock people is based on body language. No one in the hall even looks at the stage. You leave the station with empty hands.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="slug">
      <text>(Slug) Send your crewmember to the stage to perform next.</text>
      <event>
        <text>With telepathic abilities, Slugs are good at reading the room. Your crewmember is able to entertain the Engi audience. One of the newfound fans wants to join your crew.</text>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="engi" repair="2"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="pavonian">
      <text>(Pavonian) Send your crewmember to the stage to perform next.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You were sceptical at sending the Pavonian at first, but they make an amazing performance, somehow managing to entertain even the nerdiest of Engis. One of those offers to join your crew.</text>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="engi" repair="2"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>