<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="HOSTILE_ENGI">
    <event load="ENGI_MANTIS_FIGHT"/>
    <event load="ENGI_REBEL_FIGHT"/>
    <event load="ENGI_PIRATE_FIGHT"/>
    <event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL"/>
    <event load="ENGI_LEPTOD_FIGHT"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ENGI_MANTIS_FIGHT">
    <textList name="ENGI_MANTIS_FIGHT">
      <text>A mixed radar signal turns out to be a Mantis attack ship scavenging the remains of an Engi carrier. They turn and fight.</text>
      <text>You come across a Mantis raider taking pot shots at a defenceless Engi supply station. Discovering its weapons aren't much of a match for the station's armour, it turns on your ship. Battle stations!</text>
      <text>The area looks clear, and you prepare to jump off, but a Mantis scout jumps in behind you! They're as surprised as you are, but their weapons are already online.</text>
      <text>You find a Mantis ship harrying a small squad of Engi. They make it to the node and jump off, leaving you toe to toe with their pursuer!</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ENGI_REBEL_FIGHT" unique="true">
    <text>The Rebel fighter here would seem to suggest elements of the Rebel fleet are already making incursions on Engi space. You move to engage.</text>
    <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ENGI_PIRATE_FIGHT" unique="true">
    <text>There must have been rich pickings for pirates around here up until war broke out. The pirate you encounter here looks worn down, but hungry. You'll have to fight!</text>
    <ship load="PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Increased rewards for defeating enemy ship in DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL" unique="true">
    <text>The distress signal originates from a small Engi ship under attack by a Rebel fighter - but when the Rebels see Federation markings they turn to attack!</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <ship name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_REBEL" hostile="true">
      <destroyed>
        <text>The Rebels destroyed, you pick the bones of their ship and wait for the small Engi ship to catch up.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL_RESULT"/>
        </choice>
      </destroyed>
      <deadCrew>
        <text>The Rebels destroyed, you pick the bones of their ship and wait for the small Engi ship to catch up.</text>
        <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL_RESULT"/>
        </choice>
      </deadCrew>
    </ship>
  </event>
  <event name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL_RESULT">
    <text>The Engi vessel turns out to be very poorly equipped - barely a runabout, really. They're trying to outrun the Rebels, and need all the help they can get.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Give them 25 scrap.</text>
      <eventList name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL_LIST1">
        <event>
          <text>The words they use are "Need = fulfilled", but you take it for gratitude. They take the next jump in their long journey home.</text>
          <item_modify>
            <item type="scrap" min="-25" max="-25"/>
          </item_modify>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The Engi are grateful. They don't have any supplies or weapons to spare, but they do send over a self-teleporting med-bot disperser they hope they won't need.</text>
          <weapon name="BOMB_HEAL"/>
          <item_modify>
            <item type="scrap" min="-25" max="-25"/>
          </item_modify>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The Engi are grateful. They don't have much by way of supplies but they do offer a drone schematic for your use.</text>
          <drone name="RANDOM"/>
          <item_modify>
            <item type="scrap" min="-25" max="-25"/>
          </item_modify>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Give them 40 scrap, 2 missiles and 2 fuel.</text>
      <event>
        <text>They wouldn't get more than a few jumps with that load-out. You provide them with all the munitions and supplies they should need for the journey home. "Generosity magnitude unpredicted. Well-being syntax error [value too high]. Accept this token."</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-40" max="-40"/>
          <item type="fuel" min="-2" max="-2"/>
          <item type="missiles" min="-2" max="-2"/>
        </item_modify>
        <augment name="NANO_MEDBAY"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Give them nothing.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Engi can't feel fear, so they bear you no ill will when you explain you're unwilling to help. They set off on their journey and you do the same.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ENGI_LEPTOD_FIGHT" unique="true">
    <!--text taken from ENGI_NOTHING event -->
    <text>The Engi seem to have avoided this particular node, along with every other life-form. You keep your eyes peeled for reasons why, but spin up the FTL without event.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event>
        <text>A hostile Leptod ship de-cloaks and attacks you with advanced weaponry, becoming undetectable again shortly.</text>
        <ship load="LEPTOD_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>