<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NOSHIP_ENGI">
    <event load="ENGI_FIND_AUGMENT"/>
    <event load="ENGI_FIND_DRONE"/>
    <event load="ENGI_GIFT"/>
    <event load="ENGI_TRADER"/>
    <event load="ENGI_FLEET_DELAY"/>
    <event load="ENGI_STATION_REQUIRES_WORKERS"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ENGI_FIND_AUGMENT">
    <textList>
      <text>Even though the Engis were not made for close combat, the Federation owes them a lot in terms of military research. The Engi station at the beacon offers a breakthrough combat augment for free.</text>
      <text>A friendly Engi research station contacts you: "Combat testing required. Transferring equipment."</text>
      <text>A tiny Engi scientific vessel, that you mistook for a drone at first, contacts you: "Collected military equipment. Model unsuitable. Ejecting."</text>
    </textList>
    <augment name="RANDOM"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ENGI_FIND_DRONE">
    <textList>
      <!--text taken from FIND_DRONE event -->
      <text>A small Engi research vessel is trying to fend off a Mantis ship. You move in to engage, but after a quick scan of your ship the Mantis ship retreats. The Engi offer you a drone schematic as thanks for your timely arrival.</text>
      <text>You encounter a swarm of advanced Engi surveying drones flying through space completely autonomously. One of the drones decides to leave the swarm and starts to orbit your ship instead.</text>
      <text>Seeing that you're representing Federation, a local Engi research station offers one of its drones built for combat for free.</text>
    </textList>
    <drone name="RANDOM"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ENGI_GIFT">
    <textList>
      <text>An Engi vessel hails you. "Identity: Federation? Outlier probability. Implies... revival. Implies... hope. Assistance suggested." They offer some supplies.</text>
      <text>You cross paths with an Engi cargo vessel hurrying home before the Mantis fleets attempt to take over this sector. They're happy to offload some of their cargo to get home faster.</text>
      <text>You make contact with an isolated Engi science station who are staying put despite the likelihood of Mantis invasion. They suggest you trial some experimental technology.</text>
      <text>This was the site of a recent battle. Either a show of Mantis force, or the Engi here weren't disposed to go peacefully. You pick through the pieces.</text>
    </textList>
    <autoReward level="LOW">stuff</autoReward>
  </event>

  <event name="ENGI_TRADER" unique="true">
    <!--text taken from NOTHING_ENGI event -->
    <text>There are a number of merchant ships passing through the area despite the threat of Mantis invasion. No doubt interested in buying the efficient technology of the Engi. One of the trading ships makes an offer.</text>
    <choice>
      <text>Trade.</text>
      <event load="TRADER_LIST"/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Ignore.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ENGI_FLEET_DELAY" unique="true">
    <text>You notice an Engi colony hiding on the other side of a nearby moon. It turns out they're excavating an equipment cache from the Federation-Mantis War, and they suggest it might be used to lure the pursuing Rebel fleet.</text>
    <choice>
      <text>Booby trap the cache.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You transfer down some missile warheads and the Engi rig them to blow before setting a distress signal to attract the fleet's attention.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="missiles" min="-2" max="-2"/>
        </item_modify>
        <modifyPursuit amount="-2"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Secure the cache.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You have the Engi complete their excavations and bring the supplies on-board.</text>
        <drone name="RANDOM"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Engi station requires workers event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="ENGI_STATION_REQUIRES_WORKERS" unique="true">
    <text>You jump in to find a big industrial Engi station broadcasting a message. "Assistance required. Insufficient workforce. Station security compromised." You could send a part of your crew to find out if they need any help.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Send one crewmember to the station.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Your crewmember leaves in a small one-man shuttle for the Engi station. The remaining crew is looking forward to seeing them again.</text>
        <removeCrew>
          <clone>false</clone>
          <text>As your crewman is still alive and helping on the Engi station, it would be against Federation regulation to create a clone to continue with you on your journey.</text>
        </removeCrew>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <eventList>
            <event>
              <text>After hours of wait, an Engi worker arrives to your ship and requests a permission to work for the Federation. "Subordinate left. Substitution arrived." It seems that your former crewmember could not return.</text>
              <crewMember amount="1" class="engi" repair="2"/>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>You wait for your crewmember to return. After several hours you receive a message. "I am staying here. The pay is better, social benefits, and stable oxygen production." The Engi station compensates your loss with resources.</text>
              <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
            </event>
          </eventList>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Ignore them.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>