<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NOSHIP_ROCK">
    <event load="ROCK_FREE_ITEMS"/>
    <event load="ROCK_FREE_MISSILES"/>
    <event load="ROCK_FIND_WEAPON"/>
    <event load="ROCK_ZOLTAN_MERCHANT"/>
    <event load="ROCK_RACIST_STORE"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ROCK_FREE_ITEMS">
    <textList>
      <text>You stumble upon the remains of a tiny Rock ship, probably destroyed by Rebels. You find no life signatures and collect scrap material.</text>
      <text>An unusually friendly Rock station contacts you and offers some resources to help the Federation.</text>
    </textList>
    <autoReward level="LOW">stuff</autoReward>
  </event>

  <event name="ROCK_FREE_MISSILES">
    <textList>
      <!--text taken from NOTHING_ROCK-->
      <text>No one bothers your ship as you float among numerous space stations and mining platforms. The Rock certainly run efficient operations. One of the Rock ships offers some excess ammunition for free to help the Federation.</text>
      <text>A Rock ship sends some missiles to you. Thankfully, in ammo crates this time. The Rock captain is glad to help against the Rebels.</text>
    </textList>
    <autoReward level="HIGH">missiles_only</autoReward>
  </event>

  <event name="ROCK_FIND_WEAPON" unique="true">
    <text>A fortified Rock military station is giving away weapons to smaller ships for them to be able to protect themselves. Your ship counts as small and helpless so you get a weapon for free.</text>
    <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ROCK_ZOLTAN_MERCHANT" unique="true">
    <!--text taken from NOTHING_ROCK-->
    <text>You see a Zoltan merchant and ask about his wares. He responds, "Sorry, but it took years to gain their trust. I can't be seen communicating with you. I hope you understand." He cuts communications.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Offer to pay some scrap in advance to open the store.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Zoltan merchant checks the radar to find any Rock ships nearby and, having found no one, reluctantly opens the store.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-15" max="-12"/>
        </item_modify>
        <store/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Leave.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Rock racist store event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="ROCK_RACIST_STORE" unique="true">
    <!--text taken from NOTHING_ROCK-->
    <text>You see a small trading post and ask about refuelling but they respond, "Go away! We don't serve your kind here."</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Offer to pay some scrap in advance to open the store.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The trading post reluctantly agrees to show their wares to you.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-15" max="-12"/>
        </item_modify>
        <store/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" lvl="1" max_group="0" req="rock">
      <text>(Rock) Send a crewmember to negotiate.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>Seeing the Rockman, the trading post reluctantly agrees to sell you fuel.</text>
          <choice>
            <text>Buy fuel.</text>
            <event>
              <text>The trading post sends you some fuel and you pay for it with scrap.</text>
              <item_modify>
                <item max="6" min="4" type="fuel"/>
                <item max="-12" min="-18" type="scrap"/>
              </item_modify>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Refuse to buy anything.</text>
            <event/>
          </choice>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>"Traitor to the holy words! You shall be submerged into the waters of hell for this!" Traders, peaceful at the first glance, attack your crewmember. He barely manages to get back to the ship in one piece.</text>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" lvl="2" max_group="0" req="rock">
      <text>(2 Rockmen) Send 2 crewmembers to negotiate.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Seeing fellow Rockmen, the trading post agrees to sell you fuel and ammunition.</text>
        <choice>
          <text>Buy fuel.</text>
          <event>
            <text>The trading post sends you some fuel and you pay for it with scrap.</text>
            <item_modify>
              <item max="6" min="4" type="fuel"/>
              <item max="-10" min="-15" type="scrap"/>
            </item_modify>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice>
          <text>Buy missiles.</text>
          <event>
            <text>The trading post sends you ammunition and you pay for it with scrap.</text>
            <item_modify>
              <item max="6" min="4" type="missiles"/>
              <item max="-12" min="-18" type="scrap"/>
            </item_modify>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Refuse to buy anything.</text>
          <event/>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" lvl="3" max_group="0" req="rock">
      <text>(Rockmen crew) Send a team to negotiate.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Seeing that your team is mostly composed of Rockmen, the trading post agrees to bargain with you.</text>
        <store/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>