<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NEUTRAL_ROCK">
    <event load="ROCK_LOOTING"/>
    <event load="ROCK_MANTIS_HUNTER"/>
    <event load="ROCK_MANTIS_FREIGHTER"/>
    <event load="ROCK_ATHEIST"/>
    <event load="ROCK_SLUG_ARGUMENT"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ROCK_LOOTING" unique="true">
    <text>You find a disabled rock transport floating near the beacon. You consider stripping it of useful parts but are uncertain why it's there in the first place.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Strip the ship.</text>
      <eventList name="ROCK_LOOTING_STRIP">
        <event>
          <text>You salvage what you can from the ship. No one bothers you during the operation.</text>
          <autoReward level="low">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>A Rock patrol ship jumps in while you are salvaging the ship. They message you, "Filthy pirates! Prepare to die!" You doubt explaining your mission will convince them of your need.</text>
          <ship load="ROCK_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
          <autoReward level="low">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Leave it alone.</text>
      <eventList name="ROCK_LOOTING_LEAVE">
        <event>
          <text>The Rock people are not known for setting traps but you hasten to leave anyway.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The Rock people are not known for setting traps but you hasten to leave anyway.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Before you have a chance to leave, a Rock patrol ship arrives and you intercept their comm chatter, "...appears we've finally found them. Their killing spree ends now!" Before you can plead your innocence they move in to attack.</text>
          <ship load="ROCK_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="slug">
      <text>(Slug Crew) Check for lifeforms and keep a lookout for ships while looting the wreck.</text>
      <eventList name="ROCK_LOOTING_SLUG">
        <event>
          <text>You salvage what you can from the ship. No lifeforms or ships are detected nearby.</text>
          <autoReward level="low">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You begin the salvage operation but before long your crew warns you of an approaching ship. You hasten to leave before they get within firing range.</text>
          <autoReward level="low">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ROCK_MANTIS_HUNTER" unique="true">
    <text>A Mantis ship here is adorned with Rock body parts! It would be a gorier display if they had internal organs, but the message is clear enough: this is a hunter of a very specialized kind.</text>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="false"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attack!</text>
      <event>
        <text>No species deserves a Mantis hunter on their back - time to make the galaxy a little safer. Engage!</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Ignore them.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Mantis take no interest in your ship - they're lying in wait for the next Rock ship to venture through. You're able to spin up the engines and jump at your leisure.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="ROCK_ARMOR">
      <text>(Rock Ship) Ram the bastards.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Before they have a chance, you ram your ship into theirs, causing irreparable damage to their engines. Luckily, your ship's armored hull is hardly dented from the impact. The Mantis ship careens away and you move in to attack.</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
        <status type="limit" target="enemy" system="engines" amount="0"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="rock">
      <text>(Rock Crew) Put your Rock crewmember on the comm.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The two aliens face one another over the vidscreen. "Cave-dwelling pebble-man!" yells the furious Mantis captain. "See, I paint my ship with your companions! I paint my ship with you!"</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ROCK_MANTIS_FREIGHTER" unique="true">
    <text>A curious sight greets you at this beacon: a disabled Rock freighter drifts in space while two Mantis craft battle it out - presumably over who deserves the spoils.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Wait, then attack the surviving Mantis.</text>
      <eventList name="ROCK_MANTIS_FREIGHTER_LIST">
        <event>
          <text>The Mantis craft are both too busy slaughtering one another to notice you. Eventually the smaller ship gets the upper hand, but they must have blown a fuse in the assault and their weapons system is inoperable. Now is the time to attack!</text>
          <ship load="MANTIS_ROCK_MANTIS_FREIGHTER" hostile="true"/>
          <status type="loss" target="enemy" system="weapons" amount="2"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The Mantis craft may have their differences, but when it comes to you they are of one mind. The smaller ship suffers a power failure as it moves to engage, but the larger one lets off a volley of fire and moves in to attack!</text>
          <ship load="MANTIS_ROCK_MANTIS_FREIGHTER" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Ignore them.</text>
      <event>
        <text>There's quite enough action here already - prepare for light speed.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="REPAIR">
      <text>(Repair Drone) Repair the Rock ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>While the two Mantis fight you approach the Rock ship and send a repair drone through one of the many breaches. It fixes the ship up enough to make at least a single jump. You're surprised when, instead, they embark on a kamikaze run on the two Mantis, which results in the obliteration of all three!</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="drones" min="-1" max="-1"/>
        </item_modify>
        <choice>
          <text id="continue"/>
          <event>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="SHIP_REPAIR_LIST">
      <text>(Hull Repair Drone) Repair their hull.</text>
      <event>
        <text>While the two Mantis fight you approach the Rock ship and use a drone to fix up the ship. Once the breaches are fixed the life support flickers back on. In a matter of moments they are already in pursuit of one of the Mantis ships. Meanwhile the second Mantis turns toward you.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="drones" min="-1" max="-1"/>
        </item_modify>
        <ship load="MANTIS_ROCK_MANTIS_FREIGHTER" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <ship name="MANTIS_ROCK_MANTIS_FREIGHTER" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_MANTIS">
    <destroyed>
      <text>In the time it took you to eliminate the Mantis ship the Rock must have repaired their FTL drive and jumped away. You pick the bones of both Mantis vessels.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
    </destroyed>
    <deadCrew>
      <text>In the time it took you to eliminate the Mantis ship the Rock must have repaired their FTL drive and jumped away. You pick the bones of both Mantis vessels.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
    </deadCrew>
    <crew>
      <crewMember type="mantis" prop="0.80"/>
      <crewMember type="engi" prop="0.20"/>
    </crew>
  </ship>

  <event name="ROCK_ATHEIST" unique="true">
    <text>You encounter a small craft with minimal propulsion; its Rock crew-member explains that the Rock home-world is run on lies and propaganda that keep the populace in check, and that they want no part of it.</text>
    <ship load="ROCK_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Tell them their god sent them here to join your crew.</text>
      <event>
        <textList name="ROCK_ATHEIST_BAD">
          <text>They barely hear out your appeals before yelling, "These are the lies I sought to escape!" Looks like they're charging weapons!</text>
          <text>They listen to your appeals and whisper, "Traitors to truth. You're no better than them!" Chaos ensues.</text>
        </textList>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Promise to share with them the truths they've been denied.</text>
      <eventList name="ROCK_ATHEIST_GOOD">
        <event>
          <text>Your promises gain their attention and they agree to serve with you, for a while.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1" class="rock"/>
        </event>
        <event count="2">
          <text>They seem tempted by your offer, but decide they can't risk being lied to again. They close frequencies and jump away.</text>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="sensors" lvl="2">
      <text>(Improved Sensors) Show them to your data suite.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>The Rock captain is impressed by the data you've collected and agrees to stay with you until they find their footing in the galaxy.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1" class="rock"/>
        </event>
        <event count="2">
          <text>The Rock captain is impressed by the data you've collected and offers a modest reward in exchange for the information.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>