<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="HOSTILE_HAZARD_ROCK">
    <event load="ROCK_FIGHT_ASTEROID"/>
    <event load="ROCK_PIRATE_ASTEROID"/>
    <event load="ROCK_PIRATE_SUN"/>
    <event load="ROCK_BOARDERS_ASTEROID"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ROCK_FIGHT_ASTEROID">
    <textList name="ROCK_FIGHT_ASTEROID">
      <text>A Rock mining vessel is harvesting the mineral-rich asteroids in this locality, and their scouts take your presence to be a transgression. Battle stations!</text>
      <text>A rookie Rock cargo ship has taken its orders too literally and took the most direct route to their destination... right through an asteroid field. They're confused and fire wildly as you jump in.</text>
      <text>The captain of a Rock freighter lost in the asteroid field hails you: "Our co-ordinates led us here, but only death greets us. What must be must be. Death to all." You power up the battle systems and wonder how long they've been stuck here.</text>
    </textList>
    <environment type="asteroid"/>
    <ship load="ROCK_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ROCK_PIRATE_ASTEROID">
    <textList name="ROCK_PIRATE_ASTEROID">
      <text>Minute fissures in the shields spark and crackle as the ship jumps into the wake of a huge asteroid. More asteroids follow, as does a lost and aggressive Rock pirate ship.</text>
      <text>You exit the jump surrounded by dirt and rocks. Before long a blast is deflected by your shield, but that was no asteroid... Incoming pirate!</text>
    </textList>
    <environment type="asteroid"/>
    <ship load="ROCK_PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ROCK_PIRATE_SUN">
    <textList name="ROCK_PIRATE_SUN">
      <text>Unusual solar activity in this region means you need to get out, quick. The Rock pirate nearby apparently thinks otherwise as they move to attack your ship.</text>
      <text>A Rock ship is silhouetted against a sun in supernova. They hail: "Even out here you follow us! We only wish to be left alone!" Out of panic or anger, they charge their weapons.</text>
    </textList>
    <environment type="sun"/>
    <ship load="ROCK_PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ROCK_BOARDERS_ASTEROID">
    <textList name="ROCK_BOARDERS_ASTEROID">
      <text>You arrive in an asteroid field and immediately begin evasive maneuvers when a loud clunk reverberates through the ship. At first you think the hull has been hit, but the noise came from some Rock intruders teleporting aboard the ship!</text>
      <text>Your shields are being taxed as they deflect the debris from an asteroid field. As you weave your way between the rocks, you happen upon a Rock pirate stronghold. You register teleport signatures and hear shouts aboard the ship.</text>
    </textList>
    <boarders min="1" max="2" class="rock"/>
    <environment type="asteroid"/>
    <ship load="ROCK_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
  </event>
</FTL>