<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NOSHIP_ROCK">
    <event load="ROCK_STARSHIP_MINE"/>
    <event load="ROCK_RACIST_STORE"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ROCK_STARSHIP_MINE" unique="true">
    <text>The burnt out hull of a Rock mine layer drifts by. Behind the wreck drifts a live mine; an automated drone that drills into ships' hulls before exploding. It locks onto your ship's signature and heads your way!</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attempt evasive maneuvers.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The ship's turning circle proves too wide and the mine bites down onto the hull. You can hear it now, chewing through the armor.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Send someone out there to defuse it.</text>
          <eventList name="ROCK_STARSHIP_MINE_DEFUSE">
            <event>
              <text>Your crewmember dons a space suit and exits the airlock. They make quick work of the basic device and return inside to relief all round. The mine makes good scrap pickings too.</text>
              <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>Your crewmember dons a space suit and exits the airlock. When they open up the mine housing, though, they panic. The red wire or the blue?! 3... 2... 1...</text>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>Red!</text>
                <event load="ROCK_STARSHIP_MINE_DEFUSE2"/>
              </choice>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>Blue!</text>
                <event load="ROCK_STARSHIP_MINE_DEFUSE2"/>
              </choice>
            </event>
          </eventList>
        </choice>
        <choice req="WEAPONS_MISSILES">
          <text>(Missile Weapon) Attempt a controlled detonation using a missile.</text>
          <event>
            <text>After drawing straws, a crewmember goes out to fix a modified warhead to the mine. You detonate the missile in a way that dislodges the mine. It blows up shortly after. The ship takes some damage in the blasts, but you're still sailing.</text>
            <damage amount="3"/>
            <damage amount="1" system="random"/>
            <item_modify>
              <item type="missiles" min="-1" max="-1"/>
            </item_modify>
            <choice>
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event>
                <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
              </event>
            </choice>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice req="COMBAT_BEAM_DRONE_LIST">
          <text>(Beam Drone) Use a drone to cut away the mine with a precision beam.</text>
          <event>
            <text>Carefully guided from the bridge, your beam drone removes the mine's grappling arms and sends it drifting off into space, where you shoot at it until it detonates at a safe distance.</text>
            <item_modify>
              <item type="drones" min="-1" max="-1"/>
            </item_modify>
            <choice>
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event>
                <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
              </event>
            </choice>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="engines" lvl="5">
      <text>(Improved Engines) Reverse thrusters!</text>
      <event>
        <text>It stresses the inertial dampeners, but you reverse course and outrun the mine. You prepare to jump off.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="ROCK_STARSHIP_MINE_DEFUSE2">
    <event>
      <text>You open your eyes and everything is still where it was a moment ago. You did it!</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The weapon detonates. Everything goes dark, the bridge illuminated by flames pouring from the hull, your bomb disposal volunteer spinning off toward a nearby sun. You put out the fires and prepare to move on.</text>
      <removeCrew>
        <clone>true</clone>
        <text>Fortunately, your crewmember was close enough to the ship for the Clone Bay to revive them. Sheepish and apologetic, they rejoin the crew.</text>
      </removeCrew>
      <damage amount="5"/>
      <damage amount="1" system="room" effect="breach"/>
    </event>
  </eventList>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Rock racist store event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="ROCK_RACIST_STORE" unique="true">
    <text>You see a small trading post and ask about refuelling but they respond, "Go away! We don't serve your kind here."</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" lvl="1" max_group="0" req="rock">
      <text>(Rock) Send a crewmember to negotiate.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>Seeing the Rockman, the trading post reluctantly agrees to sell you fuel.</text>
          <choice>
            <text>Buy fuel.</text>
            <event>
              <text>The trading post sends you some fuel and you pay for it with scrap.</text>
              <item_modify>
                <item max="6" min="4" type="fuel"/>
                <item max="-12" min="-18" type="scrap"/>
              </item_modify>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Refuse to buy anything.</text>
            <event/>
          </choice>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>"Traitor to the holy words! You shall be submerged into the waters of hell for this!" Traders, peaceful at the first glance, attack your crewmember. He barely manages to get back to the ship in one piece.</text>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" lvl="2" max_group="0" req="rock">
      <text>(2 Rockmen) Send 2 crewmembers to negotiate.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Seeing fellow Rockmen, the trading post agrees to sell you fuel and ammunition.</text>
        <choice>
          <text>Buy fuel.</text>
          <event>
            <text>The trading post sends you some fuel and you pay for it with scrap.</text>
            <item_modify>
              <item max="6" min="4" type="fuel"/>
              <item max="-10" min="-15" type="scrap"/>
            </item_modify>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice>
          <text>Buy missiles.</text>
          <event>
            <text>The trading post sends you ammunition and you pay for it with scrap.</text>
            <item_modify>
              <item max="6" min="4" type="missiles"/>
              <item max="-12" min="-18" type="scrap"/>
            </item_modify>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Refuse to buy anything.</text>
          <event/>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" lvl="3" max_group="0" req="rock">
      <text>(Rockmen crew) Send a team to negotiate.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Seeing that your team is mostly composed of Rockmen, the trading post agrees to bargain with you.</text>
        <store/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>