<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <event name="START_BEACON_ROCK">
    <textList name="START_BEACON_ROCK">
      <text>The Rock people have a particularly aggressive stance toward alien races trespassing in their space. You should tread carefully here.</text>
      <text>The Rock people are a powerful and proud race. It is not unheard of to have a peaceful journey through their lands, but don't count on it.</text>
    </textList>
  </event>

  <event name="STORE_ROCK">
    <textList name="STORE_ROCK">
      <text>You cross paths with a Rock ship returning from a rare diplomatic mission. Equally surprising, the captain responds to your hails and agrees to a mutual trade.</text>
      <text>You come across a Rock trading post. It's rare they deal with outsiders, but they need to sell the last of their stock, and will pay their dues for their transgression when they return home.</text>
      <text>With the local Rock settlements so unwilling to trade with other life forms, an opportunistic Mantis crew has postponed its piracy activities and set up shop to catch any passing trade.</text>
      <text>The Rock tolerate few aliens in their space, but even they seem to respect the wisdom of the Zoltan - a few of them have established a trading post in the husk of an abandoned capital ship.</text>
      <text>You receive a hail on Federation frequencies: "You're Federation?! We- we weren't sure we'd ever see a friendly face again. There's little business here, perhaps you'd like to trade?"</text>
    </textList>
    <store/>
  </event>

  <event name="NOTHING_ROCK">
    <textList name="NOTHING_ROCK">
      <text>You receive a message meant to degrade you as aliens. You half expect an attack but it seems to have come from a small civilian shuttle.</text>
      <text>No one bothers your ship as you float among numerous space stations and mining platforms. The Rock certainly run efficient operations.</text>
      <text>You arrive and detect signs of battle. A few ships are taking passes at each other near a small station. You don't know if it's a territory issue, a contest or a rite of passage but you decide it's best to stay out of it.</text>
      <text>There's not much at this beacon. Just a few abandoned depots, stripped clean.</text>
      <text>A few freighters pass by but they refuse all communications. Must not want to sully their reputation by talking with foreigners.</text>
      <text>You see a Zoltan merchant and ask about his wares. He responds, "Sorry, but it took years to gain their trust. I can't be seen communicating with you. I hope you understand." He cuts communications.</text>
    </textList>
  </event>

  <ship name="ROCK_SHIP" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_ROCK">
    <surrender chance="0.7" min="3" max="4" load="ROCK_SHIP_SURRENDER"/>
    <destroyed load="DESTROYED_DEFAULT"/>
    <deadCrew load="DEAD_CREW_DEFAULT"/>
  </ship>

  <ship name="ROCK_PIRATE" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_ROCK_PIRATE">
    <surrender chance="0.7" min="3" max="4" load="ROCK_SHIP_SURRENDER"/>
    <destroyed load="DESTROYED_DEFAULT"/>
    <deadCrew load="DEAD_CREW_DEFAULT"/>
    <crew>
      <crewMember type="rock" prop="1"/>
    </crew>
  </ship>

  <event name="ROCK_SHIP_SURRENDER">
    <textList name="ROCK_SHIP_SURRENDER">
      <text>The Rock ship hails: "Enough! We were told aliens were a threat to our ways, and you have proved as much. Take this and leave us in peace."</text>
      <text>Their systems suffering, the Rock ship attempts to make contact: "Alien vessel. Cease your attack. We will pay."</text>
      <text>The Rock ship moves into a defensive position and transmits a white flag signal. They seem willing to buy their lives.</text>
    </textList>
    <choice>
      <text>Accept their offer.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="false"/>
        <autoReward level="RANDOM">stuff</autoReward>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>We will not accept surrender!</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>