<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="HOSTILE_ROCK">
    <event load="ROCK_SHIP"/>
    <event load="ROCK_PIRATE"/>
    <event load="ROCK_BOARDERS_SHIP"/>
  </eventList>

  <eventList name="HOSTILE_ROCK_HOLY">
    <event load="ROCK_SHIP"/>
    <event load="ROCK_PIRATE"/>
  </eventList>

 <event name="ROCK_SHIP">
    <textList name="ROCK_SHIP">
      <text>You encounter a Rock vessel and attempt to open trading frequencies, but they take it as an act of cultural transgression and open fire.</text>
      <text>You jump into the middle of a Rock excavation project on a nearby moon. Unimpressed with your intrusion they move to defend themselves!</text>
      <text>You intercept chatter from an approaching Rock ship: "Weapons, moving in to engage, arm the tubes." There is no talking to these guys.</text>
      <text>As you jump in, a vast figure appears on the view-screen. The Rock captain rubs the green, moss-like appendage on his chin and then orders his crew to open fire.</text>
      <text>It looks quiet, but you realize your computer is being scanned. A hidden Rock vessel hails you: "Why do you fill your computer with lies?! These are not the holy words!" Before you can interject they open fire.</text>
      <text>You notice a Rock ship performing combat exercises. However, they quickly change their course to engage your ship. They apparently treat unregistered alien ships as handy target practice.</text>
      <text>A loud 'thud' resounds through the ship after jump completion - you've just shunted a Rock fighter and he's already preparing to fire!</text>
      <text>You're intercepted by a Rock salvage operation. They don't seem to mind that you're still on board while they junk your ship.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="ROCK_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ROCK_PIRATE">
    <textList name="ROCK_PIRATE">
      <text>As a naturally warlike species with few inter-galactic diplomatic ties, the Rock people have garnered quite a reputation as fearsome pirates. You stumble across one of their ships and they promptly live up to type.</text>
      <text>A Rock ship flies past your windows and you recognize outcast decorations on the hull. These must be pirates!</text>
      <text>A motley collection of Rock ships are stationed around this beacon - they look to have resorted to a pirate's life. Defensive maneuvers!</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="ROCK_PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ROCK_BOARDERS_SHIP">
    <textList name="ROCK_BOARDERS_SHIP">
      <text>You passively scan a small Rock station that is next to the beacon. However they must not have appreciated your curiosity. A Rock ship pulls away from the station and you register an incoming teleporter signal as well!</text>
      <text>You find a Rock ship docked with a damaged Mantis fighter. Before you have a chance to hail them, the ship moves in to attack you and you register teleporter symbols from the disabled ship. They're using Mantis tech to board you!</text>
    </textList>
    <boarders min="1" max="3" class="rock"/>
    <ship load="ROCK_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
  </event>
</FTL>