<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="DISTRESS_BEACON_LANIUS">
    <event load="LANIUS_DISTRESS_FIGHT"/>
    <event load="LANIUS_DISTRESS_TRAP"/>
    <event load="LANIUS_SLUG_DISTRESS"/>
    <event load="LANIUS_MANTIS_DISTRESS"/>
    <event load="LANIUS_ROCK_DISTRESS"/>
    <event load="WOONA_LANIUS_KNOCK_KNOCK"/>

    <event load="DISTRESS_SATELLITE_DEFENSE"/>
    <event load="DISTRESS_STATION_FIRE"/>
    <event load="FRIENDLY_BEACON"/>
    <event load="TRAP_BEACON"/>
    <event load="STRANDED_BEACON"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="LANIUS_DISTRESS_FIGHT" unique="true">
    <text>You immediately do a short-range scan after arriving at the beacon. It appears to be coming from a small civilian vessel under fire from a Lanius ship. Not all Lanius are content with simply scavenging the wrecks of previous battles.</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <ship load="LANIUS_CIVILIAN" hostile="false"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Fight the Lanius ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You move in to intercept the ship. Detecting a greater threat, the Lanius prepare to fight.</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Avoid the conflict.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Your crew seems unhappy to leave the civilians to such a fate but you try to convince them of the greater good. You don't speak of your own misgivings, however.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="anaerobic">
      <text>(Lanius Crew) Have your crew admonish their captain.</text>
      <eventList name="LANIUS_DISTRESS_FIGHT_LANIUS">
        <event>
          <text>After a discussion that your translator fails to comprehend, the enemy ship powers down its weapons. You learn that your crewmember sucessfully reminded them of their treatise promising to leave the property of sentient aliens alone. If this is a widespread rule of this race, there appear to be many who disagree with it. You attempt to hail the civilian ship now that it's safe.</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text id="continue"/>
            <event load="SAVE_CIVILIAN_LIST"/>
          </choice>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The ship refuses all hails, even from one of its own kind. It appears to have gone completely rogue. Before you can react, it begins to target your ship. Prepare for a fight.</text>
          <ship hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Removed LANIUS_DISTRESS_EMPTY event</entry>
    <entry>Removed LANIUS_DISTRESS_TOOLATE event</entry>
  </changelog>

  <event name="LANIUS_DISTRESS_TRAP" unique="true">
    <text>You are too late - whatever once was emitting the distress signal from this system drew a Lanius ship as well as your own. Having consumed the original target, the Lanius turn their attention to your vessel.</text>
    <ship load="LANIUS_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
    <distressBeacon/>
  </event>

  <event name="LANIUS_SLUG_DISTRESS" unique="true">
    <text>The distress signal from this system is coming from a Slug vessel under attack by the Lanius! The Slugs beg for assistance as the Lanius tear into their hull plating.</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the Lanius ship.</text>
      <event>
        <ship load="LANIUS_SLUG_DISTRESS_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Leave the Slugs to their fate.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You leave the Lanius ship alone, and prepare to jump to the next beacon.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="LANIUS_SLUG_DISTRESS_END">
    <event>
      <text>The Slugs, taking advantage of the firefight, have fled the system. So much for gratitude.</text>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The Slugs reluctantly thank you for your help, protest they had the whole situation under control, attempt to make you pay for them helping you, and an hour later, finally relent and give you some supplies.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
    </event>
  </eventList>
  <ship name="LANIUS_SLUG_DISTRESS_SHIP" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_LANIUS">
    <destroyed>
      <text>The ship explodes, leaving behind a collection of useful scrap material.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Contact the Slugs.</text>
        <event load="LANIUS_SLUG_DISTRESS_END"/>
      </choice>
    </destroyed>
    <deadCrew>
      <text>There are no more life-signs remaining on the ship. You strip it of useful materials.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Contact the Slugs.</text>
        <event load="LANIUS_SLUG_DISTRESS_END"/>
      </choice>
    </deadCrew>
  </ship>

  <event name="LANIUS_MANTIS_DISTRESS" unique="true">
    <text>The Mantis ship in this system looks like its distress beacon is malfunctioning... likely due to the Lanius ship mining their hull and sub-systems! It doesn't look like the Mantis ship will last much longer.</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the Lanius ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Lanius don't seem to have noticed you yet - but they will. Launching into the fray, you target the Lanius vessel!</text>
        <ship load="LANIUS_MANTIS_DISTRESS_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Leave the Mantis to their fate.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Mantis ship is quickly overcome by the Lanius vessel, and you move away as the Lanius feed on the remains.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="LANIUS_MANTIS_DISTRESS_END">
    <event>
      <text>The Mantis hiss and click, angry at being saved, and angry at themselves for needing to be saved. They part ways with some scrap metal that is no longer attached to their hull and a few missiles they can no longer use.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">missiles</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The Mantis ship has sustained too much damage - there are no survivors. You gather what resources you can from the wreckage.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
    </event>
  </eventList>
  <ship name="LANIUS_MANTIS_DISTRESS_SHIP" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_LANIUS">
    <destroyed>
      <text>The ship explodes, leaving behind a collection of useful scrap material.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Contact the Mantis.</text>
        <event load="LANIUS_MANTIS_DISTRESS_END"/>
      </choice>
    </destroyed>
    <deadCrew>
      <text>There are no more life-signs remaining on the ship. You strip it of useful materials.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Contact the Mantis.</text>
        <event load="LANIUS_MANTIS_DISTRESS_END"/>
      </choice>
    </deadCrew>
  </ship>

  <event name="LANIUS_ROCK_DISTRESS" unique="true">
    <text>A distress beacon pulses weakly from a Rockman ship in this system... their hull (and their crew) are being mined by the Lanius, lasers and weapons tearing through the ship!</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the Lanius ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Rockmen need your help - you target the Lanius ship and grimly prepare for battle.</text>
        <ship load="LANIUS_ROCK_DISTRESS_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Leave the Rockmen to their fate.</text>
      <event>
        <text>As you make your escape, the Rockman's ship's engines explode, and you watch the Lanius ship slowly feed on the remains - and the crew.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="LANIUS_ROCK_DISTRESS_END">
    <event>
      <text>The Rockmen give an awkwardly-translated message that seems to indicate something about gratitude. They then jump away without another word.</text>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The Rockman ship jumped away during the battle, but it left much of its hull and spare parts floating behind - you salvage what you can, and prepare to jump.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
    </event>
  </eventList>
  <ship name="LANIUS_ROCK_DISTRESS_SHIP" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_LANIUS">
    <destroyed>
      <text>The ship explodes, leaving behind a collection of useful scrap material.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Contact the Rockmen.</text>
        <event load="LANIUS_ROCK_DISTRESS_END"/>
      </choice>
    </destroyed>
    <deadCrew>
      <text>There are no more life-signs remaining on the ship. You strip it of useful materials.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Contact the Rockmen.</text>
        <event load="LANIUS_ROCK_DISTRESS_END"/>
      </choice>
    </deadCrew>
  </ship>

  <changelog>
    <entry>New event: Lanius knock-knock</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="WOONA_LANIUS_KNOCK_KNOCK" unique="true">
    <text>A distress signal is coming from something is outside your ship! Knock-knock.</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Who is there?</text>
      <event>
        <text>Lanius.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Lanius who?</text>
          <event>
            <text>Lanius phyxiate you.</text>
            <boarders breach="true" min="1" max="1" class="anaerobic"/>
            <choice>
              <text>Ugh...</text>
              <event/>
            </choice>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>