<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="DISTRESS_BEACON_ORCHID">
    <event load="ORCHID_DISTRESS_EMPTY_SHIP"/>
    <event load="ORCHID_DISTRESS_COLONY_FIRE"/>

    <event load="DISTRESS_STATION_FIRE"/>
    <event load="REFUGEE_DISTRESS"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ORCHID_DISTRESS_EMPTY_SHIP" unique="true">
    <ship hostile="false" load="ORCHID_SHIP"/>
    <text>A distress signal is coming from an Orchid ship, drifting far away from common interstellar routes. You try to communicate but there is no answer.</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Board the ship.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>You board the ship to find the aftermath of explosion and fire. You can only guess what was the reason of the accident. Most of equipment is burnt, and there is no one alive, but you still manage to find some useful scrap and resources.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The only person alive on the ship is a dehydrated Orchid. The ship ran out of water and life support systems broke down. The whole crew is dead except one resilient Orchid who was reanimated after irrigation.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1" class="orchid"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The boarding team went into the ship to look for survivors. After a while, your crew went into uncontrollable rage. They were returned back to the ship as soon as possible, but one of the crewmembers was affected so strongly that went mad upon coming back to the ship.</text>
          <choice hidden="true" req="orchid">
            <text>(Orchid) Let the Orchid calm the madman.</text>
            <event>
              <text>The Orchid sprays soothing pollen, and the madman gradually comes to their senses. The whole team sighs in relief.</text>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true" req="CREW_STIMS">
            <text>(Mantis Pheromones) Treat the madman with pheromones.</text>
            <event>
              <text>As soon as a fresh portion of pheromones enters the crewmember's lungs, they get better.</text>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text id="continue"/>
            <event>
              <text>There is no other way but to kill the poor fellow.</text>
              <crewMember amount="-1" class="traitor"/>
            </event>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Ignore it.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ORCHID_DISTRESS_COLONY_FIRE" unique="true">
    <text>A distress signal is coming from the surface of a planet near the beacon. The wildfire is spreading towards a small Orchid colony which lacks the resources to put fires out, or evacuate in time.</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Help to evacuate as many civilians as you can.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The ecosystem on the Orchid planet is so vulnerable to fire that even your whole crew wasn't enough to save the Orchid colony in time. You succeeded in helping the more resilient individuals but most of the Orchid seeds and saplings were lost to the fire.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>This incident is no concern to us.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="FIRE_EXTINGUISHERS">
      <text>(Fire Suppression) Use the augmentation to save the colony.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Fire Suppression system is deployed in the colony and helps tremendously holding wildfires in key points back while all living Orchids evacuate. One of the Orchids is so impressed by your performance that they ask to join your crew.</text>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="orchid"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="CREW_STIMS">
      <text>(Mantis Pheromones) Use the augmentation to speed up evacuation.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Affected by pheromones, your crew and Orchid civilians move a lot faster, leaving no one behind. After the colony is evacuated, one of the Orchids is so impressed by your performance that they ask to join your crew.</text>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="orchid"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="crystal">
      <text>(Crystal Crew) Block wildfire spreading to win some time.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Your crewmember erects giant crystalline walls in mere seconds. The flames are slowed down and all of the colony manages to escape to safety. One of the Orchids is so impressed by your performance that they ask to join your crew.</text>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="orchid"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="BOMB_LOCK">
      <text>(Lockdown Bomb) Block wildfire spreading to win some time.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The bomb is used to erect giant crystalline walls in mere seconds. The flames are slowed down and all of the colony manages to escape to safety. One of the Orchids is so impressed by your performance that they ask to join your crew.</text>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="orchid"/>
        <item_modify>
          <item max="-2" min="-2" type="missiles"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="DRONE_SPEED">
      <text>(Pavonian Overclocker) Deploy superior drones to help.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The killer drones are reprogrammed and used for help. They carry seeds, saplings, and valuables, put out fires and save the day in the end. One of the Orchids is so impressed by your performance that they ask to join your crew.</text>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="orchid"/>
        <item_modify>
          <item max="-2" min="-2" type="drones"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>