<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NEUTRAL_ORCHID">
    <event load="ORCHID_FIGHT_CHOICE"/>
    <event load="ORCHID_UNDER_ATTACK_PIRATE"/>
    <event load="ORCHID_UNARMED_TRADER"/>
    <event load="ORCHID_SLAVES"/>
    <event load="ORCHID_SLUG_TAUNT"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ORCHID_FIGHT_CHOICE">
    <textList>
      <text>An Orchid ship stationed nearby is barely able to hide their hostility towards you but still keeps their distance.</text>
      <text>An Orchid fighter awaits you. They send a simple message: "One wrong move and we open fire."</text>
      <text>Some Orchids find only plant lifeforms pure, and all animal and mechanical life disgusting. A ship nearby refuses to communicate, being openly hostile toward you, but without direct confrontation.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="ORCHID_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Fight the Orchids.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Avoid the conflict.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ORCHID_UNDER_ATTACK_PIRATE">
    <textList>
      <text>An unarmed Orchid vessel is trying to flee from a ship with the markings of a space pirate that is chasing behind.</text>
      <text>A tiny Orchid ship contacts you. Without saying a word, they signal at the pirate that is following them.</text>
      <text>You initially thought that a damaged Orchid ship was alone at the beacon but then realize that they're under attack from space pirates.</text>
    </textList>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Help the Orchid ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You fire a warning shot and the pirate ship changes direction to face you. "That ship is even bigger! Let's loot this one instead." The Orchid vessel stopped far beyond firing distance to watch the battle.</text>
        <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_PIRATE" hostile="true">
          <destroyed>
            <text>The pirate ship breaks apart. You hasten to contact the Orchid ship.</text>
            <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text>Contact the Orchid ship.</text>
              <eventList name="ORCHID_SAVED_LIST">
                <event>
                  <text>The Orchid ship has taken heavy damage before you came to help. Its crew is dead, but you are able to recover a functioning drone from the wreck.</text>
                  <autoReward level="LOW">drone</autoReward>
                </event>
                <event count="2">
                  <text>The Orchid ship offers you some resources as a reward for saving them.</text>
                  <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
                </event>
                <event count="2">
                  <text>As you fought the pirate, the Orchid ship charged the FTL-drive and jumped away.</text>
                </event>
              </eventList>
            </choice>
          </destroyed>
          <deadCrew>
            <text>No more life signs detected on the pirate ship. You hasten to contact the Orchid ship.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text>Contact the Orchid ship.</text>
              <event load="ORCHID_SAVED_LIST"/>
            </choice>
          </deadCrew>
        </ship>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Do not intervene.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ORCHID_UNARMED_TRADER" unique="true">
    <text>A tiny Orchid trading vessel awaits you at the beacon. Learning that you are Federation, they offer some of their supplies to help the cause.</text>
    <choice>
      <text>Accept their offer.</text>
      <event>
        <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Extort additional resources: they surely have more.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>The trader sends a distress signal, and an Orchid military ship jumps in immediately to help with weapons online.</text>
          <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_ORCHID" hostile="true">
            <destroyed>
              <text>By the time you dealt with an Orchid military ship, the trading vessel has already escaped the system. You loot the destroyed ship, harvesting some useful scrap material.</text>
              <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
            </destroyed>
            <deadCrew>
              <text>By the time you dealt with an Orchid military ship, the trading vessel has already escaped the system. You loot the empty ship, harvesting all resources.</text>
              <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
            </deadCrew>
          </ship>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The Orchid ship sent a distress signal asking for help... But nobody came. They have to give up all of their goods to save their lives.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ORCHID_SLAVES" unique="true">
    <text>A rogue ship awaits you at the beacon. "Laborers for cheap! Can be used as oxygen emitters, cannon fodder, firewood, or healthy food."</text>
    <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_PIRATE" hostile="false">
      <surrender chance="0.2" max="4" min="2">
        <text>The slavers surrender. "You can take one of these for free! Use them for whatever purpose you want. Just let us go."</text>
        <choice>
          <text>Accept their offer.</text>
          <event>
            <crewMember amount="1"/>
            <ship hostile="false"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice>
          <text>Surrender is not an option.</text>
          <event/>
        </choice>
      </surrender>
      <escape chance="0.5" load="PIRATE_ESCAPE" max="4" min="2"/>
      <destroyed>
        <text>The slave ship is destroyed. They won't continue their evil trade, but many lives were probably lost on that ship.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      </destroyed>
      <deadCrewList>
        <event count="2">
          <text>The slavers are dead together with the Orchid slaves. You loot the ship.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>With all of the overlords dead, one of enslaved Orchids accepts an offer to join your crew.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1" class="orchid"/>
          <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
      </deadCrewList>
    </ship>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Save the enslaved Orchids!</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Buy one Orchid slave.</text>
      <event>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="orchid"/>
        <item_modify>
          <item max="-30" min="-40" type="scrap"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Decline and jump away.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ORCHID_SLUG_TAUNT" unique="true">
    <text>You are surprised to find a Slug ship in a system, mostly populated by Orchids. The Slugs are requesting to communicate using encrypted channel.</text>
    <ship hostile="false" load="JELLY"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Agree to talk with Slugs.</text>
      <event>
        <text>"Greetings, two-legged meatsssack. We have been looking for sssuch a fine ssspecimen for a century. You are truly the ugliessst human in the galaxy and deserve to be embalmed and shown in a museum. I only wonder what your mom looksss like."</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Attack!</text>
          <event>
            <text>You fire at the Slug ship and they immediately respond with evasive maneuvers. The Slug captain sends a distress message to nearby Orchid planet claiming to be attacked by pirates. To your surprise, the Orchids respond with locking Anti-ship battery onto your ship. It was all a part of Slug plan.</text>
            <ship hostile="true"/>
            <environment target="player" type="PDS"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Close communication and leave the beacon.</text>
          <event/>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Decline.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>