<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="BOSS_HOSTILE">
    <event load="BOSS_SCOUT" count="3"/>
    <event load="WOONA_BOSS_ARTILLERY_REBEL_EVENT"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="BOSS_SCOUT" unique="false">
    <textList name="BOSS_SCOUT">
      <text>Although this sector is still under Federation control, a small scout has slipped by the fleet. You move in to engage.</text>  <!--image- Fleet background-->
      <text>Long range scanners show this system is empty of any capital ships. Clearly it is not of strategic value. Wait... FTL signatures show a Rebel scout just jumped nearby!</text> <!--image-no fleets-->
      <text>Sensors indicate that the Rebels are setting up a forward Jump Beacon behind the nearby planet's moon. More importantly, a number of ships are passing by; prepare for a fight!</text> <!-- image- no fleet, empty planet-->
      <text>Federation ships are scarce in this region of space despite a number of civilian space stations. You see a small bomber squadron engaged with some Federation scouts and quickly move in to assist.</text>
      <text>As soon as you arrive at the beacon, a Rebel scout turns to engage. Power up the weapons!</text>
      <text>You scan the area, finding signatures for only a small trade vessel. However, as it approaches you see the silhouette of a Rebel scout! You run the scanners again and discover their registration is fake. You move in to attack.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship name="REBEL_AND_AUTO" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_REBEL_AND_AUTO" hostile="true">
      <destroyed load="DESTROYED_DEFAULT"/>
      <deadCrew load="DEAD_CREW_DEFAULT"/>
    </ship>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>New event: Rebel Artillery in Last Stand with unique enemy ship</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="WOONA_BOSS_ARTILLERY_REBEL_EVENT">
    <textList>
      <text>A Rebel ship of monstrous size with a giant artillery weapon mounted in front awaits you. They refuse to communicate and open fire.</text>
      <text>The Rebels are invading this sector in great numbers. As you jump in, an artillery ship turns around and attacks you.</text>
      <text>You arrive to the beacon to find the remains of several Federation cruisers. A giant Rebel ship armed to the teeth moves towards you.</text>
      <text>You hoped to find a smaller Rebel scout or even Federation allies on this beacon, but a Rebel battle cruiser of enormous proportions awaits you instead.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="BOSS_ARTILLERY_REBEL_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
  </event>
  <ship name="BOSS_ARTILLERY_REBEL_SHIP" auto_blueprint="REBEL_ARTILLERY_LIST">
    <destroyed load="DESTROYED_DEFAULT"/>
    <deadCrew load="DEAD_CREW_DEFAULT"/>
  </ship>
</FTL>