<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NEUTRAL_REBEL">
    <event load="AUTO_CIVILIAN"/>
    <event load="AUTO_DEFENSE_ITEM"/>
    <event load="AUTO_DEFENSE_MAP"/>
    <event load="AUTO_DEFENSE_RADAR"/>
    <event load="AUTO_LURE_HAZARD"/>
    <event load="BROKEN_REBEL_DRONE"/>
    <event load="REBEL_CHECKPOINT"/>
    <event load="REBEL_FIGHT_ASB"/>
    <event load="REBEL_HELPERS"/>
    <event load="REBEL_TRANSPORT"/>
    <event load="ROGUE_REBEL"/>
    <event load="SQUAT_REFUEL_STATION"/>
    <event load="STORE_REBELSIDE"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="AUTO_CIVILIAN">
    <text>You come across a Rebel automated scout ship pursuing a civilian ship, weapons engaged.</text>
    <choice>
      <text>Aid the civilian ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You power up your weapons and engage the automated ship.</text>
        <ship name="REBEL_AUTO_CIVILIAN" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_AUTO" hostile="true">
          <destroyed>
            <text>The ship breaks apart. You hasten to contact the civilian ship.</text>
            <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text>Contact the civilian ship.</text>
              <event load="SAVE_CIVILIAN_LIST"/>
            </choice>
          </destroyed>
          <deadCrew>
            <text>No more life signs detected on the pirate ship. You hasten to contact the civilian ship.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text>Contact the civilian ship.</text>
              <event load="SAVE_CIVILIAN_LIST"/>
            </choice>
          </deadCrew>
        </ship>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Stay out of it.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The fight brings them out of your immediate scanning range.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="AUTO_DEFENSE_ITEM" unique="true">
    <text>An advanced Rebel automated ship remains stationed near a small Rebel space-station. Sensors indicate it's a storage vessel for military goods.</text>
    <ship load="REBEL_AUTO_ITEM" hostile="false"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the automated ship to get to the storage cache.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Avoid provoking the ship.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="cloaking" hidden="true">
      <text>(Cloaking) Attempt to cloak and access the cache.</text>
      <eventList name="AUTO_DEFENSE_ITEM_CLOAK">
        <event>
          <text>The ship patrols wide around the area, successfully approaching the station while avoiding detection.</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text id="continue"/>
            <event load="DEFENSE_ITEM_LIST"/>
          </choice>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Before you can get close enough to scan the station, the automated ship detects you and moves in to attack!</text>
          <ship hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="AUTO_DEFENSE_MAP" unique="true">
    <img planet="PLANET_POPULATED"/>
    <text>You detect a Rebel automated ship nearby. It does not engage and seems to be patrolling around a long-range sensor station.</text>
    <ship name="REBEL_AUTO_MAP" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_AUTO" hostile="false">
      <destroyed>
        <text>You access the recent scans from the unguarded station. Your map has been updated with details of the surrounding area.</text>
        <reveal_map/>
        <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
      </destroyed>
    </ship>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the automated ship to get to the sensor station.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Avoid provoking the ship.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="sensors" lvl="3" hidden="true">
      <text>(Sensors) Use your sensors to attempt to access the data.</text>
      <eventList name="AUTO_DEFENSE_MAP_SENSORS">
        <event>
          <text>Your improved Sensors are able to remotely access and download the public radar station's local map data.</text>
          <reveal_map/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The automated ship must be remotely connected to the station; as soon as you attempt to log on, the ship activates and charges you.</text>
          <ship hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice req="teleporter" hidden="true">
      <text>(Teleporter) Beam directly onto the station to try to avoid detection.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Once on board, your crew is able to access and download the long-range scanner's archived information. Your map has been updated.</text>
        <reveal_map/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="AUTO_DEFENSE_RADAR" unique="true">
    <text>A Rebel automated ship sits dormant near a Rebel forward radar station.</text>
    <ship name="REBEL_AUTO_RADAR" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_AUTO" hostile="false">
      <destroyed>
        <text>You salvage what you can and approach the station. It is used to relay information to the Rebel Fleet. You could attempt to hack it to give the Rebels false information.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
        <choice>
          <text>Attempt to manually hack into the station.</text>
          <event load="DEFENSE_RADAR_LIST"/>
        </choice>
        <choice>
          <text>Don't risk it. Leave the station.</text>
          <event/>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true" req="hacking">
          <text>(Hacking) Use a drone to hack into the station.</text>
          <event>
            <text>You successfully hack into their system and transmit false information about your location. That should hold off the fleet for at least a little while. You also are able to download data about the surrounding beacons.</text>
            <reveal_map/>
            <modifyPursuit amount="-1"/>
            <item_modify>
              <item type="drones" min="-1" max="-1"/>
            </item_modify>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </destroyed>
    </ship>
    <choice>
      <text>Approach the station.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The ship powers up and targets you.</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Keep your distance and wait for the FTL to charge.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="COMBAT_DRONE_LIST" hidden="true">
      <text>(Combat Drone) Send a drone to distract the automated ship.</text>
      <eventList name="AUTO_DEFENSE_RADAR_COMBAT">
        <event>
          <text>Your combat drone attacks the automated ship and then retreats, luring it away. You quickly move up to the radar station to access it.</text>
          <choice>
            <text id="continue"/>
            <event load="DEFENSE_RADAR_LIST"/>
          </choice>
          <item_modify>
            <item type="drones" min="-1" max="-1"/>
          </item_modify>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Your combat drone repeatedly fires at the automated ship. It can't break through its shields, but is at least enough of a distraction to allow you to access the radar station.</text>
          <choice>
            <text id="continue"/>
            <event load="DEFENSE_RADAR_LIST"/>
          </choice>
          <item_modify>
            <item type="drones" min="-1" max="-1"/>
          </item_modify>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Before your drone has a chance to attack, the automated ship activates and shoots it down. It then detects your ship and moves in on your position.</text>
          <ship hostile="true"/>
          <item_modify>
            <item type="drones" min="-1" max="-1"/>
          </item_modify>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="DEFENSE_RADAR_LIST">
    <event>
      <text>You successfully hack into their system and transmit false information about your location. That should hold off the fleet for at least a little while.</text>
      <modifyPursuit amount="-1"/>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The firewalls prove too difficult to bypass. As you are about to disconnect, you stumble across unprotected information about the surrounding beacons. Your map is updated.</text>
      <reveal_map/>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>You are unable to penetrate the computer's defenses. You give up and return to the ship.</text>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>As you attempt to hack in, you set off a hidden alarm system. It seems that now the Rebels must surely be aware of your position! You hasten back to the ship to jump away.</text>
      <modifyPursuit amount="1"/>
    </event>
  </eventList>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Automated ship luring to hazard event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="AUTO_LURE_HAZARD" unique="true">
    <text>As you jump in, sensors detect an automated Rebel ship outside firing range. It immediately moves away from you, probably aiming to bring reinforcements.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attempt to follow the auto-ship and close the distance.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>In effort to escape, the autonomous Rebel scout tried to lure you closer to a pulsar. But one of the ionizing pulses disabled their engines, and you are able to finally catch them and engage in combat.</text>
          <ship hostile="true" load="REBEL_AUTO_WARNING"/>
          <environment type="pulsar"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The unmanned Rebel ship tried to cut the tail in the asteroid field. It backfired when they could not move through a dense area, had to slow down and fight your ship.</text>
          <ship hostile="true" load="REBEL_AUTO_WARNING"/>
          <environment type="asteroid"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The AI controlling the Rebel ship, piloted their vessel straight into local system's red giant. After the long chase, you finally catch them, but it is too late. The star is dangerously close, and your ship will overheat.</text>
          <ship hostile="true" load="REBEL_AUTO_WARNING"/>
          <environment type="sun"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" lvl="5" req="engines">
      <text>(Engines) Full thrust! Catch the enemy before they flee.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Your speed is unmatched. After a few minutes you reduce the distance enough to fire the weapons at the AI ship.</text>
        <ship hostile="true" load="REBEL_AUTO_WARNING"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Avoid combat.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The auto-ship moves away completely disappearing from radar after a few minutes. There is no doubt that they manage to relay information about your location to Rebel fleet.</text>
        <modifyPursuit amount="1"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="BROKEN_REBEL_DRONE" unique="true">
    <text>You find a Rebel automated scout floating near this beacon. Despite its pristine condition, it appears to be de-activated.</text>
    <ship load="REBEL_AUTO" hostile="false"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attempt to download the ship's data stores.</text>
      <eventList name="DOWNLOAD_DRONE_DATA">
        <event>
          <text>You are able to pull all of the ship's data about this sector. Your map has been updated.</text>
          <reveal_map/>
          <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You accidentally reactivate the ship's AI. Its weapons immediately go online; prepare for a fight!</text>
          <ship load="REBEL_AUTO" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Don't risk activating it, and just strip the ship for any useful scrap.</text>
      <event>
        <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="sensors" lvl="3" hidden="true">
      <text>(Sensors) Remotely scan the ship.</text>
      <eventList name="BROKEN_REBEL_DRONE_SENSORS">
        <event>
          <text>Your improved Sensors indicate that it's safe to hack into the drone. You upload its map data to your navigation system and strip the ship of useful materials.</text>
          <reveal_map/>
          <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Your improved Sensors indicate the ship is on standby, ready to activate at a moment's notice. Will you still attempt to access the ship's data?</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Yes.</text>
            <event load="DOWNLOAD_DRONE_DATA"/>
          </choice>
          <choice>
            <text>No.</text>
            <event>
              <text>You leave the ship alone and prepare to jump.</text>
            </event>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="REBEL_CHECKPOINT">
    <textList name="REBEL_CHECKPOINT_TEXT">
      <text>It looks like this beacon is home to a Rebel checkpoint. They're stopping and searching any ship that passes through. Civilians are being harassed, and Federation members are detained. The Rebels haven't noticed you yet.</text>
      <text>Another Rebel checkpoint is monitoring this location. A number of civilian ships are awaiting inspection, any of them could be Federation loyalists. The Rebels haven't noticed you yet.</text>
      <text>A Rebel space station and single fighter is monitoring this beacon for Federation activity. A number of civilian ships are docked, awaiting inspection by the Rebels and possible detainment if they are Federation loyalists. The Rebels haven't noticed you yet.</text>
      <text>A rather large fleet of civilian ships are held up at this beacon. It appears to be a Rebel checkpoint; everyone is being inspected for possible ties to the Federation. No one has noticed you yet.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="REBEL" hostile="false"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Fend for yourself, attack and escape.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Bribe the Rebels to release the civilian ships.</text>
      <event>
        <textList name="REBEL_BRIBE_TEXT">
          <text>These Rebels are easily swayed by the prospect of additional scrap. They release the civilian ships and everyone is free to go.</text>
          <text>Like most Rebels, these are just men trying to get by in a rough galaxy. They take your scrap and let everyone continue their journeys.</text>
          <text>As everyone currently awaiting inspection is human anyway, the Rebels let them go. They take your scrap and tell you to hurry along.</text>
          <text>They eagerly accept your bribe, obviously revolutionaries are under paid. The civilian ships all begin to jump away.</text>
        </textList>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-15" max="-10"/>
        </item_modify>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Contact the civilian ships.</text>
          <eventList name="REBEL_BRIBE_RESULT">
            <event>
              <text>The civilians are grateful. However, none of them seem eager to be mistaken as Federation loyalists so they quickly jump away.</text>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>Some of the civilians pool together their excess scrap to try to repay you for your help.</text>
              <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>One of the civilian ships quietly teleports over a crate of Federation military supplies.</text>
              <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>One of the civilian ships contacts you and reveals they are Federation loyalists. An eavesdropping Rebel swoops in, destroys the ship, and turns to attack you!</text>
              <ship hostile="true"/>
            </event>
          </eventList>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <textList name="GENERIC_HIDE_TEXT">
        <text>Fly behind a moon and stay hidden.</text>
        <text>Shut down all non-vital systems and stay hidden.</text>
        <text>Stay quiet and hope they don't notice you.</text>
        <text>Stay out of their way and charge your FTL drive.</text>
      </textList>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Rebel ASB fight event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="REBEL_FIGHT_ASB" unique="true">
    <text planet="PLANET_POPULATED">You arrive at the beacon to locate a small Rebel scout orbiting a heavily fortified planet nearby. Luckily, the Rebels haven't noticed your arrival yet but that can change in a moment.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Preemptively attack the Rebel ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>As soon as you lock on your weapons, the Rebel ship notices a threat and retaliates. To make matters worse, another danger is identified by your sensors. The planetary defense system has come online and is going to fire at you in a few moments!</text>
        <environment target="player" type="PDS"/>
        <ship hostile="true" load="REBEL"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Charge FTL drive.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Rebel scout does not notice your ship. You are ready to jump to next beacon.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="REBEL_HELPERS">
    <textList name="REBEL_HELPERS_TEXT">
      <text>You stumble across a Rebel ship distributing supplies to local civilian colonies. It's probably not anything military grade, but every little bit helps...</text>
      <text>You find a Rebel combat ship that has been reassigned as an emergency supply vessel. The local civilians are apparently in need of help, and the Rebels are rising to the occasion.</text>
      <text>The Rebels in this system are doing supply runs for the local space stations. These civilians have likely been out of supply for months due to the war and are in desperate need.</text>
      <text>Civilian colonists loyal to the Rebel cause are present on a nearby planet. It looks like they are currently receiving a supply shipment. Could be useful.</text>
      <text>Because of the war, thousands of colonists have had their supply lines disrupted and have found themselves in dire straits. It seems in this system, the Rebels are sympathetic and are distributing what little supplies they can spare.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="REBEL_HELPERS_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the Rebels.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Wait and steal the supplies from the civilians.</text>
      <eventList name="REBEL_HELPERS_SUPPLIES">
        <event>
          <text>The colonists hand over the supplies. It appears to be mostly equipment meant for automated farming, but you can make use of it. As you leave, you receive a message: "This is why the Rebels will always have support!"</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">droneparts</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The colonists hand over the supplies and you load it onto your ship. As you jump away, you crack it open and discover nothing more than vaccinations for a local plague.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You make the colonists teleport the supplies to your ship. It's nothing more than building construction supplies. Oh well, scrap is scrap.</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event count="3">
          <text>The colonists willingly give up their supplies. But as you make to jump away, an explosion rocks your ship. The cargo was booby trapped!</text>
          <damage amount="2" system="room" effect="random"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Leave them be.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <event name="REBEL_HELPER_NO_SUPPLIES">
    <textList name="REBEL_HELPER_NO_SUPPLIES_TEXT">
      <text>You make to preparations to leave. One of the civilian leaders contacts you: "That Rebel was our sole source of supplies. You have doomed us all."</text>
      <text>You leave the civilians with the supplies, though without the Rebel that was running supplies to them its unlikely they'll live long.</text>
      <text>You wonder if any more Rebels will be available to help these civilians on the edge of nowhere. Oh well, for you a few more dead Rebels matter more than the lives of a thousand colonists.</text>
      <text>Before your FTL drive charges, you receive a hail: "My son was on that ship. He only helped the Rebels because they cared enough to help us. Without him to find us supplies, we'll likely be forgotten and die out here."</text>
    </textList>
  </event>
  <ship name="REBEL_HELPERS_SHIP" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_REBEL">
    <destroyed>
      <text>With the Rebel ship destroyed, you take the time to collect what little scrap remains. They had already made their delivery to the civilians.</text>
      <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Steal the civilian supplies.</text>
        <event load="REBEL_HELPERS_SUPPLIES"/>
      </choice>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Leave the civilians alone.</text>
        <event load="REBEL_HELPER_NO_SUPPLIES"/>
      </choice>
    </destroyed>
    <deadCrew>
      <text>With the Rebel crew dead, you strip their ship for equipment. They had already made their delivery to the civilians.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Steal the civilian supplies.</text>
        <event load="REBEL_HELPERS_SUPPLIES"/>
      </choice>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Leave the civilians alone.</text>
        <event load="REBEL_HELPER_NO_SUPPLIES"/>
      </choice>
    </deadCrew>
  </ship>

  <event name="REBEL_TRANSPORT" unique="true">
    <img planet="NONE"/>
    <text>You spot a small Rebel ship nearby. It seems to have been re-fitted for transport rather than combat. It does not seem to want to engage you and your ship.</text>
    <choice>
      <text>Demand the surrender of their goods.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You prepare to secure their cargo by force.</text>
        <ship name="SQUAT_TRANSPORT" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_REBEL_TRANSPORT" hostile="true">
          <escape timer="40" min="14" max="14">
            <text>They look like they don't want to fight. They are trying to escape.</text>
            <ship hostile="true"/>
          </escape>
          <destroyed load="REBEL_TRANSPORT_DESTROYED"/>
          <deadCrew load="REBEL_TRANSPORT_CAPTURED"/>
        </ship>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Avoid the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>They stay outside your weapons range, and eventually jump away.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="REBEL_TRANSPORT_DESTROYED">
    <event>
      <text>You search the ship and discover that its cargo was new military-grade weaponry! It was somehow undamaged in the fight and can easily be mounted on the ship.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">weapon</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event count="2">
      <text>You search the remains of the ship, but only come across blueprints and debris from broken machinery. A shame, but you take what scrap you can salvage.</text>
      <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The ship was transporting weaponry. You find a piece still intact, despite the battle.</text>
      <autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event count="2">
      <text>The ship was apparently transporting weaponry; however, nothing seems to have survived the battle.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>Searching the remains, you find that the cargo was military-grade Drone Schematics! You bring them aboard to install in your ship.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">drone</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The debris implies that the ship was carrying Drone Schematics, but unfortunately nothing remains. You do find functioning Drone Parts, however.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">droneparts</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>This ship's cargo was not salvageable. However, they seem to have been surveying the region; they possess detailed maps and data. You download what you can to the ship's map.</text>
      <reveal_map/>
      <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>From the bits and pieces you find, you decide that this ship was gathering information. Nothing seems useful.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>You detect faint life signatures from an intact piece of the hull. They were transporting prisoners, and the sole survivor offers to join your crew, as a first step on his path to get revenge.</text>
      <crewMember amount="1"/>
      <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event count="2">
      <text>The ship appears to have been transporting prisoners. Unfortunately they were all killed in the battle. You salvage what you can.</text>
      <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The ship was carrying military supplies. You pick up anything that looks salvageable from the debris.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
    </event>
  </eventList>
  <eventList name="REBEL_TRANSPORT_CAPTURED">
    <event count="2">
      <text>With the crew dead, you search the ship. You find military-grade weaponry and take what looks most useful.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">weapon</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The ship refuses to fight, but you still detect life signatures. Apparently this was a prisoner transport. The single survivor offers to join your crew in exchange for their freedom.</text>
      <crewMember amount="1"/>
      <autoReward level="HIGH">scrap_only</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event count="2">
      <text>This ship was apparently carrying information about the surrounding beacons. You download what you can to the ship's map, and scrap the rest of the ship.</text>
      <reveal_map/>
      <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event count="2">
      <text>Searching the remains you find that the cargo was military-grade Drone Schematics! You bring them aboard to install on your ship.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">drone</autoReward>
    </event>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ROGUE_REBEL">
    <textList name="ROGUE_REBEL_TEXT">
      <text>You arrive at a beacon located in a civilian star system. A nearby colony contacts you: "We've got a rogue Rebel ship harassing this system. Do you have time to find it?"</text>
      <text>As soon as you arrive, you receive a Federation encrypted message: A Rebel ship has been terrorizing the local civilians in this system, please seek and destroy it.</text>
      <text>You begin charging your FTL drive, and do a quick scan of a local planet. You find the ruins of a recently destroyed Federation colony of the surface. There must be a Rebel ship in the vicinity...</text>
      <text>You jump into a field of debris. It appears a battle recently took place here, and the loser seems to have been a civilian ship. A message was left on repeat before it was destroyed: "Rebels attacking, please send aid!" The responsible Rebels are likely still nearby.</text>
    </textList>
    <choice>
      <text>Go looking for the Rebel ship.</text>
      <eventList name="ROGUE_REBEL_SEARCH">
        <event>
          <text>You spend some time looking around but your scanners cannot pick up any trace of the Rebel ship. You prepare to move on.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>After a short search you find the Rebel ship. Let's hope he's as easy to defeat in combat as he was to find.</text>
          <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You are able to quickly track down the Rebel. Let's hope he's as easy to defeat in combat as he was to find.</text>
          <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>After far too much time spent searching, you are finally able to track him down. You go into the fight pondering just how much of a head start you've lost on the Rebel Fleet...</text>
          <modifyPursuit amount="1"/>
          <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>No time to search, you prepare to jump away.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="sensors" lvl="2" max_group="0">
      <text>(Improved Sensors) Perform a scan of the area.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You quickly find the Rebel ship's location and move to intercept.</text>
        <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="sensors" lvl="3" max_group="0" hidden="true">
      <text>(Advanced Sensors) Pinpoint the Rebel's location.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You find the Rebel ship hiding on a nearby asteroid. You are able to get a shot off and permanently disable their engines before they notice you.</text>
        <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
        <status type="limit" target="enemy" system="engines" amount="0"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="SQUAT_REFUEL_STATION" unique="true">
    <img planet="PLANET_POPULATED_SMALL"/>
    <text>You detect a Rebel scout on an attack approach to a small refueling outpost. Their weapons are charged, but they're not firing yet.</text>
    <ship name="SQUAT_REFUEL_STATION" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_REBEL" hostile="false">
      <destroyed>
        <text>The ship breaks apart and you quickly salvage what you can.</text>
        <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <event>
            <text>The outpost hails you, "The pompous bastards expected free service just because they defeated the Federation. Take this for the help."</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">fuel</autoReward>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </destroyed>
      <deadCrew>
        <text>With the crew dead you quickly salvage what you can.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <event>
            <text>The outpost hails you, "The pompous bastards expected free service just because they defeated the Federation. Take this for the help."</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">fuel</autoReward>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </deadCrew>
    </ship>
    <choice>
      <text>Intervene to defend the outpost.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Rebel responds to your threat, "I don't know who you are, but no one defies the Rebel Fleet!" They move in to engage.</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Avoid the conflict.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Rebel ship fires some warning shots but eventually powers down their weapons. The outpost seems to have given them what they demanded.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="STORE_REBELSIDE" unique="true">
    <text>You come across a large trade station. However, as soon as you approach a warning goes out to all ships in the region: "Do not associate with the Federation sympathizer. All who oppose the Rebels will be punished."</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Search among the stores to see if someone will sell to you.</text>
      <eventList name="STORE_REBELSIDE_SEARCH">
        <event>
          <text>You find a single store that responds to your hails: "Don't open any wide band channels. We'll sell to you but we don't want to draw attention to ourselves."</text>
          <store/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Your search for a friendly marketplace yields no results but after a time a small shuttle approaches. They release some supplies in your direction with the message, "We are not all friends of the Rebel fleet. Stay strong."</text>
          <autoReward level="RANDOM">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event count="2">
          <text>You apparently spoke to the wrong person in your search for a store. Warnings go off and you detect an automated Rebel ship moving in to attack.</text>
          <ship load="REBEL_AUTO" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Leave.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You decide it's better to not push your luck and move on.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="mind" lvl="1" max_group="0">
      <text>(Mind Control) Alter the announcer's opinions.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You locate the source of the announcement and 'convince' the speaker to rescind his previous statement. Hopefully you will have enough time to shop before he can figure out what just happened.</text>
        <store/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="mind" lvl="2" max_group="0">
      <text>(Improved Mind Control) Alter the announcer's opinions.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You locate the source of the announcement and 'convince' the speaker to rescind his previous statement. In addition he apologizes by offering complimentary supplies. Hopefully you will have enough time to shop before he can figure out what just happened.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        <store/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="mind" lvl="3" max_group="0">
      <text>(Advanced Mind Control) Alter the announcer's opinions.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You locate the source of the announcement and 'convince' the speaker to rescind his previous statement. In addition he apologizes by offering considerable complimentary supplies. Hopefully you will have enough time to shop before he can figure out what just happened.</text>
        <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
        <store/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>