<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NEBULA_NEUTRAL_SECTOR1">
    <event load="NEBULA_TRADER"/>
    <event load="WRECKAGE_EVENT"/>
    <event load="STORM_ITEMS"/>
  </eventList>

  <eventList name="NEBULA_NEUTRAL_CIVILIAN">
    <event load="NEBULA_TRADER"/>
    <event load="WRECKAGE_EVENT"/>
    <event load="STORM_ITEMS"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="NEBULA_TRADER" unique="true">
    <text>It's hard to see why, but this beacon is apparently a tourist destination. One of the ships at the small station is offering a deal.</text>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Trade.</text>
      <event load="TRADER_LIST"/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Ignore.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="WRECKAGE_EVENT" unique="true">
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <textList name="WRECKAGE_TEXT">
      <text>What at first seems to be a simple nebula is actually filled with a good amount of debris from a brutal exchange between several ships. Wreckage drifts by your screens and tumbles into the depths of the nebula to be lost to sight. It's hard to determine who the combatants were without closer investigation.</text>
      <text>You have jumped into the aftermath of what seems to have been a brutal exchange between several ships. Wreckage drifts by your screens, and you can still see the remains of the dying ships sparking and breaking apart. It's hard to determine who the combatants were without closer investigation.</text>
    </textList>
    <choice req="sensors" lvl="2" max_group="0" hidden="true">
      <text>(Improved Sensors) Use your Sensors to scan the wreckage.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You scan the battlefield, and with the aid of your Sensors, you are able to salvage a moderate amount of material from the wreckage. You prepare to jump.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="sensors" lvl="3" max_group="0" hidden="true">
      <text>(Advanced Sensors) Use your Sensors to scan the wreckage.</text>
      <eventList name="WRECKAGE_SCANNED">
        <event>
          <text>You scan the battlefield, and with the aid of your Sensors, you are able to salvage a good amount of material from the wreckage. Well-stocked, you prepare to jump.</text>
          <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You scan the battlefield and find a prototype military vessel in the debris! The crew has been killed, but their working prototype weapon array is still intact! You salvage it and bring it aboard.</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Investigate the battlefield.</text>
      <eventList name="WRECKAGE_INVESTIGATE">
        <event count="4">
          <text>You scan the battlefield, and find little remains. Disappointed, you prepare to jump.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You scan the battlefield, and are able to salvage some useful material from the wreckage.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>As you approach the wreckage, a Mantis ship screams into the system... either sensing prey - or to finish the job its fellows started.</text>
          <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The wreckage appears to be a battle between Federation fighters and Rebel cruisers. Though outnumbered, it looks like the Federation fought valiantly. As you begin a more detailed scan of the wreckage, Rebel reinforcements arrive in the system and target your ship!</text>
          <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>As you approach the wreckage, a Zoltan ship makes its arrival. It immediately mistakes you for one of the attackers, declares you as hostile aggressors in violation of Zoltan space, and opens fire!</text>
          <ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>As you approach the wreckage, a Slug ship makes its arrival. It hesitates for a moment, as if surprised to see anyone remaining, and then jumps away without a word. You resume scanning the system, wary of any other visitors.</text>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Ignore the wreckage and continue on.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Removed STORM_BOARDING event</entry>
  </changelog>

  <event name="STORM_ITEMS" unique="true">
    <text>You jump into the middle of a plasma storm. Multiple recently incapacitated ships loom in the shadows, briefly illuminated by the lightning.</text>
    <environment type="storm"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Manually search the wreckage for survivors and equipment.</text>
      <eventList name="STORM_ITEMS_LIST">
        <event>
          <text>Despite your caution, the lack of detection equipment allows debris to crash into your ship, damaging the hull. You salvage what you can and prepare to jump before anything worse happens.</text>
          <damage amount="4"/>
          <damage amount="0" system="random" effect="breach"/>
          <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Within the ship graveyard you find one ship that seems relatively untouched. On board you find an unconscious passenger, and take them back to the ship. Once awake they offer to join your crew in thanks.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>While the crew is off the ship searching through the wrecks, two hulls crash into each other breaking the crew's tethers. You have no time to react as someone is knocked away, floating helplessly into the gaseous clouds...</text>
          <removeCrew>
            <clone>true</clone>
            <text>Fortunately, your crewmember was close enough to the ship for the Clone Bay to revive them.</text>
          </removeCrew>
          <autoReward level="LOW">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Among the junk and scrap you find a salvageable drone schematic. You decide to quit while ahead and prepare to jump with your recent find.</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">drone</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Most of the debris is hardly even usable as scrap. However, you eventually find an intact weapon that can be mounted on your ship.</text>
          <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Avoid the risk and wait to jump away unscathed.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="pilot" lvl="2" hidden="true">
      <text>(Piloting) Have your pilot carefully explore the debris.</text>
      <eventList name="STORM_ITEMS_PILOTING">
        <event>
          <text>Within the ship graveyard you find one ship that seems relatively untouched. On board you find an unconscious passenger and take him back to the ship. Once awake they offer to join your crew in thanks.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Among the junk and scrap you find a salvageable drone schematic. You decide to quit while ahead and prepare to jump with your recent find.</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">drone</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Most of the debris is hardly even usable as scrap. However, you eventually find an intact weapon that can be mounted on your ship.</text>
           <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Your pilot carefully explores the wrecks, but the storm has taken its toll. Any crew are long-since dead and the floating debris has been scorched beyond repair.</text>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>