<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Giant alien spider homeworld event</entry>
    <entry>Added Tentacle monster event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="DONOR_PONY" unique="true">
    <text>Scanners are showing intelligent life forms on a nearby planet. No match for them can be found in the database.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Investigate.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>You land a small shuttle in an enormous field, whose only occupants are small, brightly colored, six-legged, horse-like animals. Could they be what your scans picked up?</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Try to communicate peacefully.</text>
            <eventList name="DONOR_PONY_PEACE">
              <event>
                <text>None of your attempts to communicate seem to work: they just stare at you silently. As you prepare to leave, one of the creatures canters forward and forcefully nudges you away from the ship. He seems to want you to follow him. Eventually, they guide you to an old Engi ship's crash site. Inside you are able to find and reactivate an Engi!</text>
                <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
                <autoReward level="LOW">stuff</autoReward>
              </event>
              <event>
                <text>You try to communicate in every possible way you can but they just stand there, silently judging you with their large, expressionless eyes. You prepare to leave.</text>
              </event>
            </eventList>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Bring some of the creatures on board to sell.</text>
            <eventList name="DONOR_PONY_SELL">
              <event>
                <text>The seemingly docile creatures quickly turn violent when you reveal your hostile intentions. Their well-organized stampede forces you to draw weapons and make a rushed and shambolic retreat to the shuttle.</text>
              </event>
              <event>
                <text>The seemingly docile creatures quickly turn violent when you show your hostile intentions. They stampede with terrifying force, trampling one of your crew before you have time to react. You fight your way back to the shuttle and prepare to jump.</text>
                <removeCrew>
                  <clone>true</clone>
                  <text>The trampled crewmate's clone is already ready when you get back to your ship.</text>
                </removeCrew>
              </event>
            </eventList>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Leave.</text>
            <event>
              <text>This isn't the time for exobiology. You head back to the ship.</text>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true" req="slug">
            <text>(Slug) Attempt to communicate telepathically.</text>
            <event>
              <text>After a moment, your crew tells you that these are simple beings, who enjoy a peaceful life. However, this isn't the first time a ship has landed here. They inform you of a nearby crash site.</text>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text id="continue"/>
                <event>
                  <text>You follow their directions and discover an ancient Engi ship. You find a deactivated Engi inside and reroute power from your shuttle to resuscitate it. After a while it reboots, rebuilds itself, and offers to join your crew.</text>
                  <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
                </event>
              </choice>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true" req="orchid">
            <text>(Orchid) Attract the herbivore creatures and carefully lead them to your hold to sell.</text>
            <event>
              <text>Your crewmember easily herds primitive animals into the cargo hold. You sell the creatures to the exotic restaurant on a nearby planet.</text>
              <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
            </event>
          </choice>
        </event>
        <event load="ALIEN_SPIDERS"/>
        <event load="TENTACLE_MONSTER"/>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Ignore it.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You ignore the readings and prepare to move on.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ALIEN_SPIDERS">
    <text>You send a small shuttle to a lit side of the planet, but thick clouds hardly let light through, and it is hard to navigate.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event>
        <text>The shuttle could not reach the surface: it got stuck in a giant web of ropes. They are all sticky and it is impossible to get out even with engines on full thrust. Red dots fill the radar. Giant alien spiders greet you with open jaws.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Send a crewmember to distract giant alien spiders while the rest of the team frees the shuttle from web.</text>
          <event>
            <text>A volunteer takes all heavy weapons from the shuttle and moves towards the swarm of giant arthropods, trying to distract them. The hero does not survive for long but their sacrifice is enough to buy time to free the shuttle from web.</text>
            <removeCrew>
              <clone>true</clone>
              <text>The clone of lost crewmember awaits you on the ship.</text>
            </removeCrew>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice req="BATTLE_LIST">
          <text>(Anti-Personnel Drone) Distract giant alien spiders with a drone.</text>
          <event>
            <text>The drone is quickly constructed on site from spare parts. As soon as it is ready, it plunges into a swarm of arachnids, making an excellent distraction while the crew frees the shuttle from sticky web.</text>
            <item_modify>
              <item max="-1" min="-1" type="drones"/>
            </item_modify>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true" req="WEAPONS_BEAM_DAMAGE">
          <text>(Beam) Carefully free the shuttle from orbit.</text>
          <event>
            <text>The team stays in the shuttle, shooting at incoming arachnids with handguns and throwing grenades. One of engineers left on ship aims the menacing beam at the web surrounding the shuttle, frying giant alien spiders at the same time. Everyone returns home safely with some alien fiber stuck to shuttle.</text>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <event name="TENTACLE_MONSTER">
    <text>You send a small shuttle with a part of the crew to explore the surface of planet. On arrival, it is clear that the whole planet is covered with liquid water. The intelligent life probably lives deep in the ocean.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Submerge the shuttle.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>On the seabed, you find ruins of lost civilization. Metallic dwellings, vehicles and factories are everywhere. There is no one to stop you from looting the place and bring the best materials back to the orbit.</text>
          <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>As the shuttle moves through the water, you notice growing shapes on the radar. They appear to be similar to giant worms and move very quickly in your direction. When a giant tentacle slams your shuttle, you quickly realize the mistake of diving into the ocean.</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text id="continue"/>
            <event>
              <text>You are too deep to establish contact with the ship on the orbit. A member of your crew lies dead, crushed by a tentacle. Water fills the shuttle. Thankfully, the engines are untouched. The pilot turns on the boost and the shuttle rapidly moves towards the surface.</text>
              <removeCrew>
                <clone>true</clone>
                <text>You return to the ship shaken and are delighted to see a clone of crewmember who was lost in the deep.</text>
              </removeCrew>
            </event>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Leave the planet.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event count="2">
          <text>You return back to the ship safely and prepare to charge FTL drive.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You pilot the shuttle upwards as the waves are starting to sprawl out below, creating a deep chasm. A giant tentacle comes out from the ocean and strikes the shuttle, damaging the engine and sending the shuttle down into abyss.</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Hope for the best.</text>
            <event>
              <text>The team grabs every weapon installed on the shuttle and aims for tentacle. As the shuttle drops down, one of your crewmembers falls out into the the chasm with a million black teeth. In the last moment, the pilot manages to regain control of the engine and boosts the shuttle into stratosphere. Could have been worse.</text>
              <removeCrew>
                <clone>true</clone>
                <text>The clone of lost crewmember already awaits on the ship when you return from the planet.</text>
              </removeCrew>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true" req="WEAPONS_BEAM_DAMAGE">
            <text>(Beam) Orbital strike!</text>
            <event>
              <text>Scarlet red pierces the sky as the deadly beam fries the tentacle monster. The creature winces in pain and moves into the ocean to lick its wounds. The pilot repairs the engine and the team returns back to ship, saved from the brink of death. You promise to never sell that beam.</text>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true" req="teleporter">
            <text>(Teleporter) Save the crew by teleporting them back.</text>
            <event>
              <text>You press the button and everyone returns safely to your ship, drifting in space. The last thing they remember is the stink from the monster's mouth. There was no way to save the shuttle. You put a remainder to never return to this planet again.</text>
            </event>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>