<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NEBULA_NEUTRAL">
    <event load="NEBULA_AUTO_DEFENSE_ITEM"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_LOST_SHIP"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_MANTIS_CHOICE"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_PIRATE_SMUGGLE"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_TRADER"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_REBEL_CHASE"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_REBEL_UNDETECTED"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_WEAPONS_TRADER"/>
    <event load="WOONA_DEAL_DEVIL"/>
    <event load="WOONA_NEBULA_STARVING_MANTIS"/>
  </eventList>

  <eventList name="NEBULA_HAZARD_NEUTRAL">
    <event load="NEBULA_ROCK_RACIST"/>
    <event load="STORM_ITEMS"/>
    <event load="WOONA_STORM_MONSTER"/>
  </eventList>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Removed NEBULA_BOARDING event</entry>
  </changelog>

  <event name="NEBULA_TRADER" unique="true">
    <text>It's hard to see why, but this beacon is apparently a tourist destination. One of the ships at the small station is offering a deal.</text>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Trade.</text>
      <event load="TRADER_LIST"/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Ignore.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="NEBULA_REBEL_UNDETECTED" unique="true">
    <text>Your ship emerges quite far away from the beacon. You see a Rebel ship waiting nearby, undoubtedly stationed to look for you.</text>
    <ship load="REBEL" hostile="false"/>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Attempt to remain concealed.</text>
      <event load="NEBULA_REBEL_UNDETECTED_LIST"/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="cloaking" hidden="true">
      <text>(Cloaking) Cloak to stay hidden.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You use your cloaking system to slip further into the nebula undetected.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="NEBULA_REBEL_UNDETECTED_LIST">
    <event>
      <text>You immediately slip further into the clouds, but not quickly enough. The Rebel catches sight of you and moves in to engage!</text>
      <choice>
        <text>Prepare to fight.</text>
        <event>
          <ship hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </choice>
      <choice req="engines" lvl="4" hidden="true">
        <text>(Engines) Fully power the engines to out-run them.</text>
        <event>
          <text>Your powerful engines allow you to out-distance the ship and eventually lose it within the nebula.</text>
        </event>
      </choice>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>You power down non-essential systems and slip into the cloud. The ship never noticed you.</text>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The ship spots you and gives chase. After some quick maneuvering you were able to lose your pursuers in the clouds. You expect they warned the fleet of your position, however.</text>
      <modifyPursuit amount="1"/>
    </event>
  </eventList>

  <event name="NEBULA_PIRATE_SMUGGLE">
    <text>A pirate ship arrives shortly after you. Judging from the fact that it is attempting to avoid your ship, you assume that it's a smuggler trying to stay away from beacons.</text>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the pirate.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You power up your weapons and move in to engage.</text>
        <ship load="PIRATE_SMUGGLE" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Ignore the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>It jumps away after a time.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="weapons" lvl="6" hidden="true">
      <text>(Weapons) Activate your advanced weapons threateningly.</text>
      <event>
        <text>They hail you, "There's no need for aggression... Perhaps this would convince you to look the other way?"</text>
        <choice>
          <text>Take their bribe.</text>
          <event>
            <autoReward level="MED">fuel</autoReward>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice>
          <text>Ignore their bribe and attack.</text>
          <event>
            <ship load="PIRATE_SMUGGLE" hostile="true"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <ship name="PIRATE_SMUGGLE" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_PIRATE">
    <surrender chance="0.5" min="2" max="4">
      <text>They hail you, "We realize our ship is no match for yours. If you let us go we can make it worth your while."</text>
      <choice>
        <text>Accept their offer.</text>
        <event>
          <ship hostile="false"/>
          <autoReward level="RANDOM">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
      </choice>
      <choice>
        <text>Ignore their pleas and attack.</text>
        <event/>
      </choice>
    </surrender>
    <escape timer="35" min="3" max="4">
      <text>They look like they don't want to fight. They are trying to escape.</text>
      <ship hostile="true"/>
    </escape>
    <gotaway>
      <text>The smuggler jumped away with their goods intact.</text>
    </gotaway>
    <destroyed load="PIRATE_SMUGGLE_DESTROYED"/>
    <deadCrew load="PIRATE_SMUGGLE_CAPTURED"/>
  </ship>
  <eventList name="PIRATE_SMUGGLE_DESTROYED">
    <event>
      <text>You search the ship and discover that its cargo was new military-grade weaponry! It was somehow undamaged in the fight and can easily be mounted on the ship.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">weapon</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>You search the remains of the ship, but only come across blueprints and debris from broken machinery. A shame, but you take what scrap you can salvage.</text>
      <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The ship was transporting weaponry. You find a piece still intact, despite the battle.</text>
      <autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The ship was apparently transporting weaponry; however, nothing seems to have survived the battle.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>Searching the remains, you find that the cargo was military-grade Drone Schematics! You bring them aboard to install in your ship.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">drone</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The debris implies that the ship was carrying Drone Schematics, but unfortunately nothing remains. You do find functioning Drone Parts, however.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">droneparts</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The ship was carrying military supplies. You pick up anything that looks salvageable from the debris.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
    </event>
  </eventList>
  <eventList name="PIRATE_SMUGGLE_CAPTURED">
    <event>
      <text>With the crew dead, you search the ship. You find military-grade weaponry and take what looks most useful.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">weapon</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>Searching the remains you find that the cargo was military-grade Drone Schematics! You bring them aboard to install on your ship.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">drone</autoReward>
    </event>
  </eventList>

  <event name="NEBULA_LOST_SHIP" unique="false">
    <text>A heavily damaged Federation ship is hiding in the nebula at this beacon. Before you have time to make contact with them, they fade into the nebula.</text>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attempt to follow and help them.</text>
      <eventList name="NEBULA_LOST_SHIP_LIST">
        <event count="2">
          <text>Your search is hopeless. Your sensors can't pick up anything in the nebula.</text>
        </event>
        <event count="2">
          <text>While searching fruitlessly through the nebula, you stumble upon the Rebel ship which the Federation loyalists were likely hiding from. You prepare for a fight.</text>
          <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You get lucky and find them floating not too deep into the nebula. Thrilled to be found by friendlies, they come on board and abandon their wrecked ship.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Keep your position, they can handle themselves.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="teleporter" hidden="true">
      <text>(Teleporter) Lock onto their life-signs with your teleporter.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You beam the Federation crew aboard. One gladly joins your crew, the rest wait to be dropped off at the next station.</text>
        <crewMember amount="1"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="ADV_SCANNERS" hidden="true">
      <text>(Long-ranged Scanners) Pump extra power into your sensors and try to track them.</text>
      <eventList name="NEBULA_LOST_SHIP_LIST2">
        <event>
          <text>Your local radar flickers, periodically showing signs of a large object in the clouds nearby. However it's enough to get coordinates and you find the ship... an empty hull, long since stripped of functioning components.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You follow the faint signatures and find them floating not too far away into the nebula. Thrilled to be found by friendlies, they come on board and abandon their wrecked ship.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="NEBULA_WEAPONS_TRADER" unique="false">
    <text>A black market weapons trader spins you a tale of the dangers of the nebula before pushing his wares.</text>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <ship load="PIRATE" hostile="false"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Ignore the ship.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Purchase an unknown weapon for 45 scrap.</text>
      <event load="NEBULA_WEAPONS_TRADER_LIST"/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="mind" hidden="true">
      <text>(Mind Control) Convince him to make it a better deal.</text>
      <event load="NEBULA_WEAPONS_TRADER_LIST2"/>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="NEBULA_WEAPONS_TRADER_LIST">
    <event>
      <text>You transfer the scrap and receive a weapon in return. Lets hope it was worth it.</text>
      <item_modify>
        <item type="scrap" min="-45" max="-45"/>
      </item_modify>
      <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>You transfer over the scrap, but he reneges on the agreement. "I told you this was a dangerous place!"</text>
      <item_modify>
        <item type="scrap" min="-45" max="-45"/>
      </item_modify>
      <choice>
        <text>Attack the ship!</text>
        <event>
          <ship hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </choice>
      <choice>
        <text>Learn a valuable lesson and move on.</text>
        <event/>
      </choice>
    </event>
  </eventList>
  <eventList name="NEBULA_WEAPONS_TRADER_LIST2">
    <event>
      <text>Once "convinced" to help he lowers the price and describes the weapon. However, he eventually comes to his senses and confusedly takes back his discount. He is clearly unsure why he offered it in the first place.</text>
      <choice>
        <text>Buy the weapon.</text>
        <event>
          <text>You purchase the weapon and thank him for his help.</text>
          <item_modify>
            <item type="scrap" min="-45" max="-45"/>
          </item_modify>
          <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
        </event>
      </choice>
      <choice>
        <text>Decline.</text>
        <event>
          <text>You thank him for his offer and prepare to move on.</text>
        </event>
      </choice>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>Once "convinced" to help, he casually states that his offer was actually a lie and that they planned to attack your ship. By the time he returns to his senses you've already prepared your ship to fight.</text>
      <ship hostile="true"/>
    </event>
  </eventList>

  <event name="NEBULA_ROCK_RACIST" unique="true">
    <text>A Rock armoured transport nearby looks to have lost its bearings, but when you hail they grow suspicious: "Whatever life-form you are, we find you repugnant. We seek no aid. Leave. Now."</text>
    <ship load="ROCK_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
    <environment type="storm"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Leave.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Repugnant?! Arm the weapons!</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="rock">
      <text>(Rock crewmember) Offer to lead them out of the nebula.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Rock grudgingly transfer control of their helm to you and you steer them to a thinner part of the nebula. They're not sure what to think, but transfer over some supplies all the same.</text>
        <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="NEBULA_MANTIS_CHOICE" unique="true">
    <text>Navigating the fog blind, you practically bump hulls with a Mantis ship. They hail you: "Pah! This transgression will be overlooked. Nebula, very dangerous. Next time, humans all die."</text>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="false"/>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <choice>
      <text>There won't be a next time. Open fire!</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>This place is dangerous enough. Move on.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="NEBULA_REBEL_CHASE" unique="true">
    <text>You spot a Rebel ship in the nebula ahead and stay off their radar. Try to engage?</text>
    <ship load="REBEL" hostile="false"/>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Stay hidden.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You try and stay out of sight. You doubt they saw you.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Prepare to chase them!</text>
      <event load="NEBULA_REBEL_CHASE_LIST"/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="sensors" lvl="3">
      <text>(Advanced Sensors) Try to track them as you move to engage.</text>
      <event>
        <text>As soon as they see you they make a run for it. You squeeze what you can out of the malfunctioning sensors and are able to keep track of them long enough to get in firing range.</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="ADV_SCANNERS" hidden="true">
      <text>(Long-ranged Scanners) Try to track them as you move to engage.</text>
      <event>
        <text>As soon as they see you they make a run for it. You squeeze what you can out of the malfunctioning sensors and are able to keep track of them long enough to get in firing range.</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="LIFE_SCANNER" hidden="true">
      <text>(Lifeform Scanner) Use their life signatures to follow.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Your augment's ability to keep track of their life signatures within the nebula proves useful. You catch up to the ship and prepare for a fight.</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="NEBULA_REBEL_CHASE_LIST">
    <event>
      <text>You follow their vapour trails and surf onto their six o'clock, weapons hot.</text>
      <ship hostile="true"/>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>Without sensors you can't maintain a lock for long. The Rebels slip away.</text>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>You get disoriented in the nebula and lose your bearings completely. It takes some time to get back to the beacon. It's likely the fleet has had time to advance closer to your position.</text>
      <modifyPursuit amount="1"/>
    </event>
  </eventList>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Removed STORM_BOARDING event</entry>
  </changelog>

  <event name="STORM_ITEMS" unique="true">
    <text>You jump into the middle of a plasma storm. Multiple recently incapacitated ships loom in the shadows, briefly illuminated by the lightning.</text>
    <environment type="storm"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Manually search the wreckage for survivors and equipment.</text>
      <eventList name="STORM_ITEMS_LIST">
        <event>
          <text>Despite your caution, the lack of detection equipment allows debris to crash into your ship, damaging the hull. You salvage what you can and prepare to jump before anything worse happens.</text>
          <damage amount="4"/>
          <damage amount="0" system="random" effect="breach"/>
          <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Within the ship graveyard you find one ship that seems relatively untouched. On board you find an unconscious passenger, and take them back to the ship. Once awake they offer to join your crew in thanks.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1"/>
          <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>While the crew is off the ship searching through the wrecks, two hulls crash into each other breaking the crew's tethers. You have no time to react as someone is knocked away, floating helplessly into the gaseous clouds...</text>
          <removeCrew>
            <clone>true</clone>
            <text>Fortunately, your crewmember was close enough to the ship for the Clone Bay to revive them.</text>
          </removeCrew>
          <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Among the junk and scrap you find a salvageable drone schematic. You decide to quit while ahead and prepare to jump with your recent find.</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">drone</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Most of the debris is hardly even usable as scrap. However, you eventually find an intact weapon that can be mounted on your ship.</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Avoid the risk and wait to jump away unscathed.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="pilot" lvl="2" hidden="true">
      <text>(Piloting) Have your pilot carefully explore the debris.</text>
      <eventList name="STORM_ITEMS_PILOTING">
        <event>
          <text>Within the ship graveyard you find one ship that seems relatively untouched. On board you find an unconscious passenger and take him back to the ship. Once awake they offer to join your crew in thanks.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1"/>
          <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Among the junk and scrap you find a salvageable drone schematic. You decide to quit while ahead and prepare to jump with your recent find.</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">drone</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Most of the debris is hardly even usable as scrap. However, you eventually find an intact weapon that can be mounted on your ship.</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Your pilot carefully explores the wrecks, but the storm has taken its toll. Any crew are long-since dead and the floating debris has been scorched beyond repair.</text>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Deal with the devil event to nebula</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="WOONA_DEAL_DEVIL" unique="true">
    <text>You enter the peaceful section of nebula with no ships in sight. Suddenly, you hear the loud voice inside your head. "I know what you desire. I can fulfill your darkest wishes. The price is simple - I want your soul."</text>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Learn more.</text>
      <event>
        <text>"Oh, you do not need the soul to live. In fact, I lived without it in this nebula for millions of years. Just sign the contract, and your every wish will come true." A piece of paper materializes on the bridge. It's covered in incomprehensible symbols, the only thing you can read is: "Sign here" above the rectangle.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Sign.</text>
          <eventList name="WOONA_DEAL_DEVIL_SIGN">
            <event>
              <text>As you sign the paper, a weapon appears right in your weapon bay. It's an upgraded Burst Laser Mark II. Reliable and powerful. Exactly what you wanted.</text>
              <weapon name="LASER_BURST_3_UPGRADED"/>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text id="continue"/>
                <event load="WOONA_DEAL_DEVIL_PRICE"/>
              </choice>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>As you sign the paper, a weapon appears right in your weapon bay. It's a upgraded Halberd Beam. Slow but deadly. Exactly what you wanted.</text>
              <weapon name="BEAM_2_UPGRADED"/>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text id="continue"/>
                <event load="WOONA_DEAL_DEVIL_PRICE"/>
              </choice>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>As you sign the paper, an augmentation appears on your ship. It's a Weapon Pre-Igniter. You cannot believe your eyes. That's exactly what you wanted.</text>
              <augment name="WEAPON_PREIGNITE"/>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text id="continue"/>
                <event load="WOONA_DEAL_DEVIL_PRICE"/>
              </choice>
            </event>
          </eventList>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Do not sign.</text>
          <event/>
        </choice>
        <choice req="warped" hidden="true">
          <text>(Warped) Ask for advice.</text>
          <event>
            <text>Your crewmember happens to know this creature personally. "This creature is full of malice and contempt. The deal won't bring you anything good." Your Warped comes up with a better idea: they suggest to sign a deal instead of you.</text>
            <choice>
              <text>Agree for Warped to sign the contract.</text>
              <event>
                <text>Your Warped crewmember presses their hand on the paper and bursts up in flames. The voice inside your head turns into a chilling scream. You lose consciousness.</text>
                <crewMember class="warped" amount="-1"/>
                <choice hidden="true">
                  <text id="continue"/>
                  <eventList>
                    <event>
                      <text>After you come to senses, you find a new weapon installed in your weapon bay. It's an upgraded Burst Laser Mark II. Reliable and powerful.</text>
                      <weapon name="LASER_BURST_3_UPGRADED"/>
                    </event>
                    <event>
                      <text>After you come to senses, you find a new weapon installed in your weapon bay. It's a upgraded Halberd Beam. Slow but deadly.</text>
                      <weapon name="BEAM_2_UPGRADED"/>
                    </event>
                    <event>
                      <text>After you come to senses, you find a new augmentation on your ship. It's a Weapon Pre-Igniter. You cannot believe your eyes.</text>
                      <augment name="WEAPON_PREIGNITE"/>
                    </event>
                  </eventList>
                </choice>
              </event>
            </choice>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text>Sign the contract yourself anyway.</text>
              <event load="WOONA_DEAL_DEVIL_SIGN"/>
            </choice>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text>Nobody signs the contract. Charge FTL drive.</text>
              <event/>
            </choice>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Resist the temptation.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="WOONA_DEAL_DEVIL_PRICE">
    <event>
      <text>You start charging FTL drive, but cannot. It seems that the creature did not want your soul, but they took all fuel reserves instead. Or did they take your soul too?</text>
      <item_modify>
        <item max="-99" min="-99" type="fuel"/>
      </item_modify>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>You hear shouts and gunshots on the ship. It seems that the creature did not want your soul, but instead they took the souls of your crewmembers. Former friends attack everyone on sight.</text>
      <crewMember amount="-1" class="traitor"/>
      <choice>
        <text id="continue"/>
        <event>
          <text>More of your former crewmembers turn hostile.</text>
          <crewMember amount="-1" class="traitor"/>
        </event>
      </choice>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>A powerful explosion shakes your ship. Looks like the creature did not want your soul. Instead they haunted your ship and try to destroy it from inside.</text>
      <damage amount="5" effect="fire" system="random"/>
      <damage amount="5" effect="fire" system="random"/>
      <damage amount="5" effect="fire" system="room"/>
      <damage amount="5" effect="fire" system="room"/>
    </event>
  </eventList>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Nebula monster event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="WOONA_STORM_MONSTER" unique="true">
    <text>The nebula is particularly thick at this beacon. The sensors have gone offline, as well as half of high-tech equipment on the ship. The ship can hardly move through the dense gases. The best decision would probably be to charge the FTL drive and hope to leave the dangerous area as soon as possible.</text>
    <environment type="storm"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="slug">
      <text>(Slug) Detect life signatures.</text>
      <event load="WOONA_STORM_MONSTER_DETECTED"/>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="LIFE_SCANNER">
      <text>(Lifeform Scanner) Detect life signatures.</text>
      <event load="WOONA_STORM_MONSTER_DETECTED"/>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <event name="WOONA_STORM_MONSTER_DETECTED">
    <text>A colossal monster with a size of a planet lies ahead of you. It seems to be dormant, but alive, hidden from everyone by dense nebula.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Fire at the monster.</text>
      <event>
        <text>It is hard to miss the giant head of the creature in front of your ship. A shot connects and an eye of enormous size opens. Then another. Then a thousand more. A monster just opens it mouth and that's enough to send your ship flying away towards the local star. It was impossible to see anything with your own eyes, but you will never forget this experience.</text>
        <damage amount="4" effect="breach" system="random"/>
        <damage amount="3" effect="breach" system="random"/>
        <damage amount="3" effect="breach" system="room"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Leave immediately.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="BEAM_3_LIST">
      <text>(Glaive Beam) Make a hole in its head.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The monster's skin is thick but not enough to resist the sheer power of the Glaive Beam. The brain of the creature was completely destroyed by one lucky shot from tiny starship, leaving planet-sized monster dead in space. There is no reward for this feat, since nobody will believe the story, but you know that you saved the galaxy once again.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Starving Mantis event to nebula</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="WOONA_NEBULA_STARVING_MANTIS" unique="true">
    <text>After finishing the jump, you bumped a floating cargo pod located on the beacon. It would be impossible to find it otherwise, without functioning sensors.</text>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
    <choice blue="false" hidden="true" lvl="0" max_group="0" req="mantis">
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice blue="false" hidden="true" lvl="1" max_group="0" req="mantis">
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event>
        <text>A Mantis on your ship is grumpy. To stay alive, Mantis race needs food eight times per day, preferably still moving. You found some cargo but there was no organic food there, just some metal, and the Mantis is starving.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Tell them to wait patiently.</text>
          <event>
            <text>After another hour of waiting, the starving Mantis turns on your crew!</text>
            <crewMember amount="-1" class="mantis"/>
            <boarders class="mantis" max="1" min="1"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true" req="human">
          <text>(Human) Feed them a healthy dinner.</text>
          <event>
            <text>You lure an unaware human to Mantis quarters. The hungry Mantis plunges at them and tears them apart. The whole crew is watching from afar, hoping not to become the next meal.</text>
            <removeCrew class="human">
              <clone>false</clone>
              <text>You are lacking biological materials to make a new clone. The Mantis ate them all.</text>
            </removeCrew>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice req="slug">
          <text>(Slug) Telepathically calm them.</text>
          <event>
            <text>After a few hours of being conditioned by a Slug, the starving Mantis accepts to change the diet. Instead of being a carnivore, they will become a "ferrovore". To calm the stomach, the Mantis eats some of scrap material from the hold of your ship.</text>
            <item_modify>
              <item max="-5" min="-8" type="scrap"/>
            </item_modify>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice req="engi">
          <text>(Engi) Find an unorthodox solution.</text>
          <event>
            <text>Few people know how exactly FTL fuel is synthesized. It seems that your Engi is one of them. With reverse engineering, they manage to make some kind of nutrient paste out of fuel. The Mantis does not like the taste, but feels full and energetic at the same time.</text>
            <item_modify>
              <item max="-2" min="-4" type="fuel"/>
            </item_modify>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>