<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NEBULA">
    <event load="NEBULA_AUTO"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_AUTO_WARNING"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_MANTIS_FIGHT"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_PIRATE"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_REBEL"/>
    <event load="STORM_AUTO"/>
    <event load="STORM_REBEL"/>
  </eventList>

  <eventList name="NEBULA_HOSTILE">
    <event load="NEBULA_AUTO"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_AUTO_WARNING"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_MANTIS_FIGHT"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_PIRATE"/>
    <event load="NEBULA_REBEL"/>
  </eventList>

  <eventList name="NEBULA_HAZARD_HOSTILE">
    <event load="STORM_AUTO"/>
    <event load="STORM_REBEL"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="NEBULA_REBEL">
    <textList name="NEBULA_REBEL_LIST">
      <text>You cross paths with an advance scout of the Rebel fleet searching this section of the nebula for your ship.</text>
      <text>A ship bearing Rebel colors can be seen waiting near the beacon. They must have been waiting for you, since they engage immediately.</text>
      <text>The Rebels must have anticipated you would try to lose them within the nebula. A scout is waiting for you at the beacon.</text>
      <text>It looks like you will be unable to avoid the Rebels by traveling through the nebula. A Rebel ship is waiting for you near the beacon.</text>
      <text>Shortly after you arrive, a Rebel ship jumps nearby. There looks to be no escape. Prepare for a fight!</text>
      <text>Newton-knows what brings this Rebel ship so far out; its captain hails, but does a double take when he identifies your ship. They open fire.</text>
      <text>A Rebel ship hails, but you don't take chances in conditions like this. You block the frequency and prepare to engage.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
  </event>

  <event name="NEBULA_AUTO">
    <textList name="NEBULA_AUTO_LIST">
      <text>You cross paths with an advance scout of the Rebel fleet searching this section of the nebula for your ship.</text>
      <text>You jump into a calmer part of the nebula. However, your relief fades as a Rebel scout jumps to the beacon and moves in to attack.</text>
      <text>The tangled wrecks of many ships wait in dormancy here. You see lights flicker on what looks like debris. A Rebel scout bursts out of the wreckage!</text>
      <text>This drone isn't looking for you. Perhaps it's scouting ahead for the Rebel expansion or maybe they're seeking to use this nebula for cover. Regardless, it identifies you as hostile.</text>
      <text>It's worrying that the Rebels have penetrated so deep into uncharted space, even if it is only an unmanned craft. It arms its weapons; you should do the same.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="REBEL_AUTO" hostile="true"/>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
  </event>

  <event name="NEBULA_AUTO_WARNING" unique="true">
    <text>It appears that an automated Rebel scout was positioned within the nebula to warn of your passing.</text>
    <ship load="REBEL_AUTO_WARNING" hostile="true"/>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
  </event>

  <event name="NEBULA_PIRATE">
    <textList name="NEBULA_PIRATE">
      <text>As you drift through the nebula an unmarked vessel descends from the clouds and into your wake. Their weapons come online.</text>
      <text>A pirate ship pulls out of the ether and hails: "You know what I love about this part of the galaxy? The explorers! You always carry such fine loot." They lock weapons.</text>
      <text>As you coast through the nebula a pirate ship matches your course and closes the distance. Better to pick your battleground, but beggars can't be choosers.</text>
      <text>A hostile vessel descends from out of the nebula. Combat stations!</text>
      <text>You try to read the ID of a ship ahead in the fog, but it's too thick to penetrate. You have your answer when the ship turns, weapons hot!</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="NEBULA_MANTIS_FIGHT" unique="false">
    <textList name="NEBULA_MANTIS_FIGHT">
      <text>Nebulas are known to be popular Mantis hunting grounds. Information you would have done well to heed here.</text>
      <text>You detect a Mantis expedition vessel returning home with its haul. So determined are they, in fact, that they don't wait to see if you're hostile before firing.</text>
      <text>A Mantis ship, lost in the storm, hails you. "Sensors are out. We have no local telemetry. We will take yours." You detect a power increase in their weapons systems.</text>
      <text>A Mantis ship hails you through the storm: "These are sacred Urggghtnag clan hunting grounds. You are prey." Shields up!</text>
      <text>You notice a Mantis attack ship ducking between the clouds of swirling space stuff; it's hunting you. You try to get the jump and move in to attack.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
  </event>

  <event name="STORM_AUTO" unique="false">
    <text>You jump into a sector of the nebula beset by a plasma storm. An automated Rebel scout stationed at the beacon moves in to attack.</text>
    <environment type="storm"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Prepare to fight.</text>
      <event>
        <ship load="REBEL_AUTO" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="engines" lvl="3" max_group="0" hidden="true">
      <text>(Engines) Attempt to out-run it.</text>
      <event load="STORM_AUTO_ESCAPE"/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="engines" lvl="6" max_group="0" hidden="true">
      <text>(Improved Engines) Attempt to out-run it.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You successfully lose the ship in the storm.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="cloaking" hidden="true">
      <text>(Cloaking) Use your cloaking to escape.</text>
      <event>
        <text>By using your advanced cloaking system you easily lose your pursuer in the storm.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <eventList name="STORM_AUTO_ESCAPE">
    <event>
      <text>You successfully lose the ship in the storm.</text>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>Despite your advanced engines you are unable to shake them; you turn and prepare for a fight.</text>
      <ship load="REBEL_AUTO" hostile="true"/>
    </event>
  </eventList>

  <event name="STORM_REBEL" unique="false">
    <text>You arrive in the middle of a plasma storm. Despite the harsh conditions, a Rebel scout seems to be waiting for you.</text>
    <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
    <environment type="storm"/>
  </event>
</FTL>