<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <event name="DONOR_MANTIS_CHASE" unique="true">
    <text>You are immediately hailed by an impressive looking Mantis ship, "Your ship would make a mighty fine prize. Prepare for battle!"</text>
    <ship name="DONOR_MANTIS_CHASE1" auto_blueprint="MANTIS_PRIZE_LIST" hostile="true">
      <escape timer="5" min="5" max="5">
        <text>You pick up more chatter from the enemy ship, "You know what... Forget this. Prepare for retreat!" Looks like they're preparing to make a hasty get away!</text>
      </escape>
      <gotaway>
        <text>The ship made an emergency FTL jump, but it looks like they didn't mask their signatures. You could easily follow them if you want.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>After them!</text>
          <event>
            <text>You input their coordinates into your map and prepare to follow.</text>
            <quest event="DONOR_MANTIS_CHASE2"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Forget it.</text>
          <event>
            <text>They're not worth the trouble. You prepare to leave.</text>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </gotaway>
      <destroyed>
        <text>Their ship breaks apart and you move in to scrap the remains.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      </destroyed>
      <deadCrew>
        <text>With no more crew on board you are free to salvage what you can from the remains.</text>
        <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
      </deadCrew>
      <crew>
        <crewMember type="mantis" prop="0.80"/>
        <crewMember type="engi" prop="0.20"/>
      </crew>
    </ship>
  </event>
  <event name="DONOR_MANTIS_CHASE2">
    <text>You catch up with the Mantis ship that escaped before, only to see them transferring their crew into an even bigger ship!</text>
    <ship name="DONOR_MANTIS_CHASE2" auto_blueprint="MANTIS_TROPHY_LIST" hostile="true">
      <escape timer="12" min="6" max="6">
        <text>They appear to be trying to get away again. You doubt they'll forget to mask their jump signature this time.</text>
      </escape>
      <gotaway>
        <text>Looks like they got away. At least you're able to scrap their abandoned fighter.</text>
        <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
      </gotaway>
      <surrender min="2" max="2">
        <text>"Look, you proved your point. We don't want to die... Take this and let us go. Please?"</text>
        <choice>
          <text>Let them live.</text>
          <event>
            <text>"Thank you. But do you have any idea how much repairing TWO ships will set us back?..." What an odd Mantis. You prepare to leave.</text>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
            <ship hostile="false"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice>
          <text>Finish them off.</text>
          <event>
            <text>"No! Hurry up, get us out of here! They're crazy!" You cut transmissions.</text>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </surrender>
      <destroyed>
        <text>Their ship breaks apart and you salvage the two ships.</text>
        <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
        <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      </destroyed>
      <deadCrew>
        <text>You find an intact weapon on their now empty ship. You take as much scrap from the ships as possible.</text>
        <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
        <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
      </deadCrew>
      <crew>
        <crewMember type="mantis" prop="0.80"/>
        <crewMember type="engi" prop="0.20"/>
      </crew>
    </ship>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event>
        <text>"Not YOU again! Do you know how much these repairs are going to cost me? Time to take out the big guns."</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>