<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NEUTRAL_MANTIS">
    <event load="MANTIS_FIGHT_CHOICE"/>
    <event load="MANTIS_CIVILIAN"/>
    <event load="MANTIS_SLAVER_SELLING"/>
    <event load="MANTIS_ZOLTAN_OUT_OF_FUEL"/>
    <event load="MANTIS_SAVE_ENGI_SLAVES_MINES"/>
  </eventList>

  <eventList name="NEUTRAL_MANTIS_BROOD">
    <event load="MANTIS_FIGHT_WITH_BOARDERS_CHOICE"/>
    <event load="MANTIS_EGGS"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="MANTIS_FIGHT_CHOICE">
    <textList name="MANTIS_FIGHT_CHOICE">
      <text>You're greeted by a rare sight: a Mantis ship that appears not to have noticed you.</text>
      <text>For once, you see the Mantis before they see you.</text>
      <text>When they see the Mantis warship waiting in ambush at your intended coordinates, your crew is relieved to note you've jumped someway off the mark.</text>
      <text>You overhear Mantis comm chatter: "Negative, I have killed more humans!" You gulp noticeably, but luckily they don't see you yet.</text>
      <text>You overhear Mantis comm chatter: "The one on the right is starting to rot. Take him down. Take off his fingers. Put him out of the airlock." They certainly don't seem to be friendly...</text>
      <text>You overhear Mantis comm chatter: "Agreed. Next ship is your turn. Good hunting." They don't see you yet.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="MANTIS_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attack the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Attempt to remain concealed.</text>
      <eventList name="MANTIS_FIGHT_CHOICE_AVOID">
        <event>
          <text>You power down non-essential systems and wait for the FTL drive to charge. They either don't want to fight or have failed to notice your ship, the latter being more likely.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Before you have a chance to slink away the Mantis ship notices you and powers up their weapons.</text>
          <ship hostile="true"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You power down non-essential systems in an attempt to remain unnoticed. It looks like they are about to leave when suddenly they turn and set course toward you, weapons powered.</text>
          <ship hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="cloaking" lvl="1">
      <text>(Cloaking) Cloak to stay hidden.</text>
      <eventList name="MANTIS_FIGHT_CHOICE_CLOAK">
        <event>
          <text>You quickly cloak the ship and move out of immediate scanning range. You appear to have gotten away undetected.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You cloak and shut down non-essential systems. In a short time the Mantis ship jumps away, no doubt in search of prey.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You quickly cloak the ship, but not quickly enough. They spot you and move in to engage.</text>
          <ship hostile="true"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="MANTIS_FIGHT_WITH_BOARDERS_CHOICE">
    <textList>
      <text>You jump in to find a lonely Mantis ship in the distance. They have not detected you yet, and you still have a chance to avoid bloodshed.</text>
      <text planet="PLANET_POPULATED">A Mantis ship is slowly orbiting a nearby moon. They're probably resting, feeling safe deep inside their territory.</text>
      <text>While the Mantis are rarely that careless when it comes to prey, this ship doesn't seem to notice your arrival.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="MANTIS_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attack the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>As soon as you start charging the weapons, intruders board your ship.</text>
        <boarders min="2" max="3" class="mantis"/>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Avoid the conflict.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="MANTIS_CIVILIAN">
    <textList name="MANTIS_CIVILIAN">
      <text>A Mantis vessel flashes past your view-screen, weapons and engines at full. A tiny blip on the sensor readout marks its quarry.</text>
      <text>You spot a Mantis ship hunting in the distance.</text>
      <text>A Mantis ship engaging a civilian hails you. Sparks fly about his cockpit as he yells, "Stay out of this human! Else you are next!"</text>
      <text>Local sensors pick up two ships engaged in a heated battle. It seems the Mantis military ship will surely defeat its prey.</text>
      <text>You pick up a distress call from a civilian ship. It's being chased by a Mantis ship!</text>
    </textList>
    <ship name="MANTIS_CIVILIAN" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_MANTIS" hostile="false">
      <destroyed>
        <text>The Mantis ship breaks apart.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Attempt to contact the civilian ship.</text>
          <event load="SAVE_CIVILIAN_LIST"/>
        </choice>
      </destroyed>
      <deadCrew>
        <text>No more life signs detected on the pirate ship. You hasten to contact the civilian ship.</text>
        <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Attempt to contact the civilian ship.</text>
          <event load="SAVE_CIVILIAN_LIST"/>
        </choice>
      </deadCrew>
      <crew>
        <crewMember type="mantis" prop="0.80"/>
        <crewMember type="engi" prop="0.20"/>
      </crew>
    </ship>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Aid the civilian ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You frown, power up the weapons and prepare to engage the Mantis ship. Not today.</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Stay out of it.</text>
      <event>
        <textList name="MANTIS_CIVILIAN_AVOID">
          <text>Smoking, the civilian ship limps on. You set your sights on the future.</text>
          <text>The noise of the FTL spinning up almost drowns out the explosions. Almost.</text>
          <text>You let them pass and try not to think about it.</text>
        </textList>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="MANTIS_SLAVER_SELLING" unique="true">
    <text>There are several Mantis ships at the beacon, no doubt returning from a successful raid with loot and slaves. One of the Mantis ships moves away from the group and offers you a selection of slaves to buy.</text>
    <ship load="MANTIS_SHIP_SLAVER" hostile="false"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Buy a human.</text>
      <event>
        <text>A frightened slave cannot believe how lucky they are to be on a Federation ship. But learning about your mission makes them stressed again.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-35" max="-30"/>
        </item_modify>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="human"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Buy an Engi.</text>
      <event>
        <text>An Engi slave is emancipated by Federation rules. Having no emotions themselves, it doesn't change anything for the Engi, but the crew is more comfortable knowing that everyone is technically free.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-45" max="-40"/>
        </item_modify>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attack the slavers.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Decline.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Zoltan ship ran out of fuel in hostile sector event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="MANTIS_ZOLTAN_OUT_OF_FUEL" unique="true">
    <text>As you arrive to the next beacon, the captain of the Zoltan ship immediately contacts you. "Our ship ran out of fuel in hostile Mantis territory. I am willing to purchase your excess fuel for scrap."</text>
    <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_ZOLTAN" hostile="false">
      <destroyed>
        <text>The Zoltan ship breaks apart. It seems they did not have any resources. You scrap the remains of the ship.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      </destroyed>
      <deadCrew>
        <text>No more life signs detected on the Zoltan ship. It turns out Zoltans were carrying a drone schematic to their homeworlds.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">drone</autoReward>
      </deadCrew>
    </ship>
    <choice>
      <text>Agree to the trade.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Zoltan captain is grateful. "Thanks a lot. I realize I have robbed you but there was no other way. I have to get to the home system as soon as possible."</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item max="-3" min="-5" type="fuel"/>
          <item max="6" min="4" type="scrap"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Politely decline.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Zoltan captain is irritated. "You don't understand. I can't take no for an answer." The weapons are extended from their ship's hull.</text>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice lvl="1" req="mind">
      <text>(Mind Control) Suggest a better deal.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You hasten to leave the beacon before the Zoltan captain realizes that he was fooled.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
        <item_modify>
          <item max="-1" min="-1" type="fuel"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="WEAPONS_ALL_FIRE">
      <text>(Fire weapon) Start a fire as a distraction.</text>
      <event>
        <text>After successfully starting a fire in Mantis command structures, you were able to get very close to Mantis mines without being detected, send a shuttle and liberate one of the Engi. The Mantis have noticed their loss and send a fighter to stop you!</text>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
        <ship load="MANTIS_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="MANTIS_SAVE_ENGI_SLAVES_MINES" unique="true">
    <img back="BACKGROUND" planet="PLANET_POPULATED"/>
    <text>A nearby Mantis mining operation is clearly using heavy Engi slave labor. The Mantis presence here is very formidable, but you could still liberate some of the Engi if you play you cards right.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Launch a direct attack.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Mantis were ready for combat. As soon as they see your ship, a fighter moves out of hangar to confront you. The Anti-ship battery is firing at your ship from a nearby planet. There is no way you would be able to save the Engi without subterfuge.</text>
        <environment target="player" type="PDS"/>
        <ship load="MANTIS_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>We will save them another time.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="cloaking">
      <text>(Cloaking) Launch a surprise attack.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Using cloaking technology, you were able to get very close to Mantis mines without being detected, send a shuttle and liberate one of the Engi. The Mantis have noticed their loss and send a fighter to stop you!</text>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
        <ship load="MANTIS_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="sensors" lvl="2">
      <text>(Advanced Sensors) Scan the system to find the least protected area.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Scans show that in addition to the main mining operation, there is a new smaller site, still in construction and almost unprotected. You get closer, but are spotted by a Mantis fighter which wastes no time and attacks.</text>
        <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_MANTIS" hostile="true">
          <destroyed>
            <text>The ship explodes, leaving behind a substantial collection of useful scrap material. You hurry to save the Engi from slavery.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event>
                <text>One of the liberated slaves agrees to join your crew. The others take a Mantis ship and head for their home system.</text>
                <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
              </event>
            </choice>
          </destroyed>
          <deadCrew>
            <text>There are no more life-signs remaining on the ship. You strip it of useful materials. You hurry to save the Engi from slavery.</text>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event>
                <text>One of the liberated slaves agrees to join your crew. The others take a Mantis ship and head for their home system.</text>
                <crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
              </event>
            </choice>
          </deadCrew>
          <crew>
            <crewMember type="mantis" prop="0.80"/>
            <crewMember type="engi" prop="0.20"/>
          </crew>
        </ship>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="MANTIS_EGGS" unique="true">
    <text>You've always wondered where the numerous Mantis fighters and pirates come from to spread across the galaxy. Scan show, that this is the place: there are billions of eggs deposited underground the surface of local planet. You have no chance of landing there, but maybe you can do some population control from orbit.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Locate and attack biggest clutches.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Even before you're able to strike, a Mantis ship starts moving towards you rapidly. Soon, you're boarded by a brood of size you've never could imagine.</text>
        <boarders min="4" max="5" class="mantis"/>
        <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_MANTIS" hostile="true">
          <surrender chance="0" min="4" max="6">
            <text>The Mantis see that they're losing the battle, and afraid to lose any eggs, send reinforcements.</text>
            <boarders min="4" max="5" class="mantis"/>
          </surrender>
          <destroyed>
            <text>The ship explodes, leaving behind a substantial collection of useful scrap material. Afraid to deal with any more intruders, you jump away.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
          </destroyed>
          <deadCrew>
            <text>There are no more life-signs remaining on the ship. You strip it of useful materials. Afraid to deal with any more intruders, you jump away.</text>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
          </deadCrew>
        </ship>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Jump away. You're not suicidal.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>