<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="HOSTILE_MANTIS">
    <event load="MANTIS_FIGHT"/>
    <event load="MANTIS_FIGHT_WITH_BOARDERS"/>
    <event load="MANTIS_BOARDERS_SWARM"/>
    <event load="MANTIS_STRIDER_FIGHT"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="MANTIS_FIGHT">
    <textList name="MANTIS_FIGHT">
      <text>A Mantis military ship appears on local radar alongside the remains of a human freighter. Prepare for a hostile encounter!</text>
      <text>A Mantis military scout hails your ship. "Foolish alien! Your kind has stifled our greatness for too long! You will rue the day you backed the Federation!"</text>
      <text>A small Mantis cruiser is broadcasting a repeating message on a wide-band frequency, "All non-Mantis ships that enter our territory are forfeit. Lower your shields and surrender if you value your lives."</text>
      <text>You detect a small military outpost and a few freighters nearby. This mineral rich planet in an isolated location would be perfect for an illegal Mantis mining operation. As you consider your options, a ship launches from the outpost. Prepare for a fight.</text>
      <text>You discover yet another unlicensed and uncharted Mantis colony. They certainly waste no time expanding their claims. A Mantis ship moves to intercept you before you can jump away.</text>
      <text>A Mantis military scout seems to have just finished a salvage op on a nearby wreck. They have no time to waste with warnings and appear to wish to fight.</text>
      <text>A small military craft hails you and a Mantis captain appears on your receiver. "All local human colonies have been punished for the Federation's transgressions. Submit to processing."</text>
      <text>A nearby Mantis ship begins aggressive maneuvers. You prepare for the worst.</text>
      <text>A stream of clicks and gurgling comes on the comm from a hostile Mantis scout. The universal translator might be on the blink, but his intent is obvious.</text>
      <text>The Mantis ship is pleased to see you, and fires up its weapon systems.</text>
      <text>You recognize the outline of a Mantis ship against the blackness. Engage!</text>
      <text>Something red looms. It's the Mantis.</text>
      <text>A Mantis vessel hails you. "This hail is merely a distraction!" You notice their shields and weapons have come online.</text>
      <text>You notice a flurry of laser fire glance by the port window. The Mantis are upon you.</text>
      <text>The Mantis hail you. Their captain says, "I claim this vessel for my clan. Good hunting!"</text>
      <text>A Mantis female comes on the vidscreen. The females don't make it to authority unless they're particularly vicious. You power the weapons.</text>
      <text>A Mantis ship with the markings of a warrior tribe breaks position and attacks!</text>
      <text>A Mantis ship hails: "Ah! Fine prey. Fine prey! We honor you with our most eviscerating arsenal!" You sense a cloud to this silver lining and power the weapons.</text>
      <text>Children on Earth are told terrible tales of the blood red Mantis invasion ships - much like the one bearing down on you now - which once threatened the planet. You order weapons free!</text>
      <text>A youthful-looking Mantis captain hails. "You, prey, must know. Your death, Kaaazthwak's final kill before maturity. Kaaazthwak pay respects." Seems respects in Mantis culture are paid with lasers.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="MANTIS_FIGHT_WITH_BOARDERS">
    <textList>
      <text>As the jump is completed, everything plunges into chaos. The Mantis, appearing from nowhere, are swarming your ship. A small hunting vessel is arming ints weapons, ready to strike.</text>
      <text>The Mantis are screeching. Some - just from the comm, but some are already on board and attacking your crew.</text>
      <text>Your world, all of a sudden, changes. The Mantis are on board your ship. To make things worse, a Mantis ship approaches.</text>
      <text>You hear a grating rattle and a soft clicking. You reach for your pistol. The Mantis are boarding and their military vessel is charging its weapons.</text>
      <text>All alerts trigger (except fire alert) as the Mantis ship is upon you and the intruders are already on board and sabotaging your critical systems.</text>
    </textList>
    <boarders min="2" max="3" class="mantis"/>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="MANTIS_BOARDERS_SWARM" unique="true">
    <text>It seems that the entire Mantis hive has teleported on your ship from nearby station. A small military ship is attacking while your ship is filled with screeches and gunshots.</text>
    <boarders min="4" max="5" class="mantis"/>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="MANTIS_STRIDER_FIGHT" unique="true">
    <text>You fancy you see something moving in the shadow of the beacon, but all remains still.</text>
    <choice>
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event>
        <text>Suddenly, a Strider ship appears out of nowhere and attacks you. It seems they were waiting in ambush to hunt the Mantis, but you disrupted their plan.</text>
        <ship load="STRIDER_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>