<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <event name="START_BEACON_PAVONIAN">
    <text>This sector is marked as Pavonian on your star map. Valuing their personal freedom above everything else, Pavonian ships and colonies rarely engage in politics and do very little to control their sector.</text>
  </event>

  <event name="STORE_PAVONIAN">
    <textList>
      <text>An automated trading station controlled by various drones awaits at the beacon. You can resupply here, as there are no Pavonian ships present at the moment.</text>
      <text>The pirates were bold enough to start trading weapons at this beacon. Apparently there are no trading regulations in Pavonian space at all. You briefly consider fighting the pirates but trading seems preferable given the urgency of your mission.</text>
    </textList>
    <store/>
  </event>

  <ship name="PAVONIAN_SHIP" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_PAVONIAN">
    <surrender chance="0.3" min="3" max="5" load="PAVONIAN_SURRENDER"/>
    <escape chance="0.5" min="4" max="6" load="PIRATE_ESCAPE"/>
    <destroyed load="DESTROYED_DEFAULT"/>
    <deadCrew load="DEAD_CREW_DEFAULT"/>
  </ship>

  <event name="PAVONIAN_SURRENDER">
    <textList>
      <text>The Pavonian captain appears on the screen begging for mercy: "It was a misunderstanding. Please cease fire. I promise to do the same. Nobody has to die here."</text>
      <text>The Pavonian ship has stopped firing: "Please be merciful. We will never trouble you ever again. Accept our gift, it's all we have."</text>
      <text>"Chill out, pal! Let's just forget about this. Here is some scrap if you need it." The Pavonians have turned their weapons off and are begging you to spare their lives.</text>
    </textList>
    <choice>
      <text>Accept their offer.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="false"/>
        <autoReward level="RANDOM">stuff</autoReward>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>We will not accept surrender!</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>
