<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NEUTRAL_PAVONIAN">
    <event load="PAVONIAN_FIGHT_CHOICE"/>
    <event load="PAVONIAN_SELLING_DRUGS"/>
    <event load="PAVONIAN_RACE_TO_FREE_WEAPON"/>
    <event load="PAVONIAN_DO_NOT_CARE"/>
    <event load="PAVONIAN_DRONE_FACTORY"/>
    <event load="PAVONIAN_TWO_MANTIS"/>
    <event load="PAVONIAN_LANIUS"/>
    <event load="PAVONIAN_WASTE"/>
    <event load="PAVONIAN_BEGGAR"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="PAVONIAN_FIGHT_CHOICE">
    <textList>
      <text>A Pavonian scout is harvesting debris of a destroyed pirate ship. You could make use of those remains too, but the Pavonians are unlikely to let you.</text>
      <text>A Pavonian vessel is busy dispatching an inactive automated Rebel ship. You would like to take some scrap for yourself, but the Pavonians aren't willing to share.</text>
      <text>You jump in to witness a Pavonian fighter dealing last hit to an unidentified ship, probably civilian. They move on to collect the remains, but you have a chance to intercept them.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="PAVONIAN_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attack the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Avoid the conflict.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="PAVONIAN_SELLING_DRUGS" unique="true">
    <text>A particularly annoying Pavonian ship is bothering you: "You have to buy this stuff, it will open your mind! You will see the rainbow that is flowing deep inside you and become one with the universe. You won't regret it!"</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attack the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <ship load="PAVONIAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Buy some stuff.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You've decided to buy one dose of the Pavonian drugs. Apparently, for them to have effect, you have to inject the suspicious liquid substance of uncertain color directly into your eyeballs. After doing that, you wait for the drugs to take effect.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-18" max="-12"/>
        </item_modify>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <eventList>
            <event>
              <text>A giant space whale comes to visit you in a dream. It changes color from vibrant magenta to plain brown and back again. You have a mind-shattering conversation with the whale. After you come to your senses, you know exactly how to defeat the Rebels and bring peace to the galaxy once again. A weapon will help you with that!</text>
              <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>I wish I had more of this stuff.</text>
                <event/>
              </choice>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>After some time, your mind wanders away, and you start talking with some green people about the nature of existence and your place in the universe. After a while, you realize that those green men are Zoltans and they're real! "Possession of hard drugs is illegal. We will have to apply force!" The Pavonian dealers are long gone.</text>
              <ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
            </event>
          </eventList>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Ignore them.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="PAVONIAN_RACE_TO_FREE_WEAPON" unique="true">
    <text>Scans show there is a weapon just floating in the local system. You haste to grab it but detect a Pavonian ship jumping in and going in the same direction as you. It looks like they want to race you.</text>
    <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_PAVONIAN" hostile="false">
      <escape timer="40" min="22" max="22">
        <text>The Pavonians clearly don't want to fight. They forget about the race and prepare to jump away.</text>
      </escape>
      <gotaway>
        <text>The Pavonian ship jumps away. You grab the drifting weapon, unopposed.</text>
        <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
      </gotaway>
      <destroyed>
        <text>The ship explodes, leaving behind a substantial collection of useful scrap material.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <event>
            <text>You collect the weapon which the Pavonians gave their lives for.</text>
            <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </destroyed>
      <deadCrew>
        <text>There are no more life-signs remaining on the ship. You strip it of useful materials.</text>
        <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <event>
            <text>You collect the weapon which the Pavonians gave their lives for.</text>
            <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </deadCrew>
    </ship>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Race them.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>You have some advantage at first, but the Pavonian ship is closing in. Thankfully, you reached the weapon before they overtook your ship, but that was close. You were clearly slower than them.</text>
          <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The Pavonian ship overtakes you immediately and is swiftly moving towards the weapon. There is no way you could lose to them!</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Attack them!</text>
            <event>
              <ship hostile="true"/>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Let them win.</text>
            <event/>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>The weapon is rightfully yours. Attack the Pavonians!</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Let the Pavonians have the weapon.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="engines" lvl="4">
      <text>(Improved Engines) Full thrust!</text>
      <event>
        <text>You outrun the Pavonians with ease and collect the weapon. The Pavonian ship contacts you: "That was fast! Have you ever considered participating in Rainbow Races?" They transfer the coordinates where the main event is going to take place.</text>
        <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
        <quest event="PAVONIAN_RAINBOW_RACE"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <event name="PAVONIAN_RAINBOW_RACE">
    <text>This is it, the famous Rainbow Race is going to take place here. Hundreds of ships are waiting for it to begin. There are no rules or audience. Everyone is participating and everything is allowed! That's going to be a great distraction from Galactic War. Hopefully, it won't take too much time.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Go to start line.</text>
      <event name="PAVONIAN_RAINBOW_RACE_START">
        <text>The race starts, your thrust engines are unrestricted and you rush towards the finish line like everyone else. You're in a leading group, but there are still some ships ahead of you. Time to think of a winning strategy.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Slow and steady wins the race.</text>
          <event>
            <text>Turns out, that strategy doesn't work in spaceship races. You lose, and receive nothing from the Pavonians.</text>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Target everyone ahead with weapons.</text>
          <event>
            <text>You quickly make way with your superior weaponry. There are few vessels ready for battle here, and most of them behind you. You win the race, but the Pavonians do not offer any rewards. Instead, they bury the killed and tend to wounded.</text>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true" req="engines" lvl="6">
          <text>(Advanced Engines) Rely on pure speed.</text>
          <event>
            <text>Redirecting all spare power to engines, you accelerate and overtake every opponent one by one. You reached the finish line first. The Pavonians are offering an augmentation, and a weapon for this spectacular performance.</text>
            <augment name="SYSTEM_CASING"/>
            <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true" req="mind">
          <text>(Mind Control) Take control of a pilot on the ship ahead of you.</text>
          <event>
            <text>The leader of the race suddenly turns and moves into opposite direction! Many ships turn around and follow them like a flock of Arcturus sheep! It takes time to clarify where should they actually go. You reached the finish line first. The Pavonians are offering an augmentation, and a weapon for this spectacular performance.</text>
            <augment name="SYSTEM_CASING"/>
            <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true" req="ROCK_ARMOR">
          <text>(Rock Plating) Ram everyone around so they would make some space.</text>
          <event>
            <text>One by one, all of the opponents drop out after you ram them. After a few ships become unfit not just for racing but moving at all, every ship ahead retires. You reached the finish line first. The Pavonians are offering an augmentation, and a weapon for this spectacular performance.</text>
            <augment name="SYSTEM_CASING"/>
            <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true" req="ENGINE_DISABLER">
          <text>(Engine Disabler) Disable the engines of ships ahead of you.</text>
          <event>
            <text>Suddenly, the engine power of the ships ahead of you is dropping. Without constant acceleration, they got overtaken by you first and all outsiders afterwards. You reached the finish line first. The Pavonians are offering an augmentation, and a weapon for this spectacular performance.</text>
            <augment name="SYSTEM_CASING"/>
            <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Prepare to jump away.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You realize that the long-distance travel from this area is restricted until the race ends. This seems logical but awfully inconvenient. You prepare to participate in the race with everyone.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <event load="PAVONIAN_RAINBOW_RACE_START"/>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="PAVONIAN_DO_NOT_CARE" unique="true">
    <text>The Pavonian ship at the beacon just stays at the same spot without paying you any attention.</text>
    <ship hostile="false" load="PAVONIAN_SHIP"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Attack the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Greet the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You send a brief greeting message to Pavonian ship but there is no answer.</text>
        <choice>
          <text>Attack the ship.</text>
          <event>
            <ship hostile="true"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice>
          <text>Ask if they support the Rebels or Federation.</text>
          <event>
            <text>You ask about Pavonian allegiance but there is no answer. It seems that they're either neutral or wait for you to uncover your allegiance first.</text>
            <choice>
              <text>Attack the ship.</text>
              <event>
                <ship hostile="true"/>
              </event>
            </choice>
            <choice>
              <text>Tell about your mission without going into details.</text>
              <event>
                <text>You explained to Pavonian ship how you intend to defeat the Rebellion with one swift strike. The Pavonians pay you no notice.</text>
                <choice>
                  <text>Attack the ship.</text>
                  <event>
                    <ship hostile="true"/>
                  </event>
                </choice>
                <choice>
                  <text>Tell the Pavonians about incoming Rebel fleet.</text>
                  <event>
                    <text>You explain at length about the Rebel threat and how the Rebels are capturing whole sectors just looking for your ship. The Pavonian ship doesn't seem to care.</text>
                    <choice>
                      <text>Attack the ship.</text>
                      <event>
                        <ship hostile="true"/>
                      </event>
                    </choice>
                    <choice>
                      <text>Ask if there is anyone alive on the ship.</text>
                      <event>
                        <text>The Pavonian ship finally responds: "Yes. Now could you kindly go away?" The ship arms the weapons. Looks like they won't take no for an answer.</text>
                        <ship hostile="true"/>
                      </event>
                    </choice>
                    <choice>
                      <text>Ignore the ship.</text>
                      <event/>
                    </choice>
                  </event>
                </choice>
                <choice>
                  <text>Ignore the ship.</text>
                  <event/>
                </choice>
              </event>
            </choice>
            <choice>
              <text>Ignore the ship.</text>
              <event/>
            </choice>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice>
          <text>Ignore the ship.</text>
          <event/>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Ignore the ship.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="PAVONIAN_DRONE_FACTORY" unique="true">
    <text>You stumble upon an automated drone factory. Its structure resembles Pavonian designs. Scans show it is unarmed and completely defenseless not counting the drones swarming inside.</text>
    <choice hidden="false">
      <text>Take one of the drones to your ship. You may find some use for it.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>You board the station and steal one of the drones. There are no security systems, so you think about just leaving the factory.</text>
          <drone name="RANDOM"/>
          <choice hidden="false">
            <text>Grab some drone parts, too!</text>
            <eventList>
              <event>
                <text>You take some spare drone parts and make your leave. The station continues working while you undock as if nothing happened. You could loot the whole factory, but you can't risk the Rebel fleet finding you.</text>
                <item_modify>
                  <item type="drones" min="5" max="6"/>
                </item_modify>
              </event>
              <event>
                <text>You take some spare drone parts and make your leave. But while you were occupied, a Pavonian ship has jumped into the system and is rapidly moving towards your ship with hostile intentions.</text>
                <item_modify>
                  <item type="drones" min="5" max="6"/>
                </item_modify>
                <ship load="PAVONIAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <text>As you grab spare drone parts, the alarms go off. An explosion shakes your ship, still docked to the station. The pirate ship, the true owner of the drone factory, has jumped into the system and moves towards your ship with weapons online.</text>
                <item_modify>
                  <item type="drones" min="5" max="6"/>
                </item_modify>
                <ship load="PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
                <damage amount="5"/>
              </event>
            </eventList>
          </choice>
          <choice>
            <text>Leave with just a drone.</text>
            <event/>
          </choice>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You board the station and steal one of the drones. But while you were occupied, a Pavonian ship has jumped into the system and is rapidly moving towards your ship with hostile intentions.</text>
          <drone name="RANDOM"/>
          <ship load="PAVONIAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>As you grab the drone schematic, the alarms go off. An explosion shakes your ship, still docked to the station. The pirate ship, the true owner of the drone factory, has jumped into the system and moves towards your ship with weapons online.</text>
          <drone name="RANDOM"/>
          <ship load="PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
          <damage amount="5"/>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Leave the factory alone.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="PAVONIAN_TWO_MANTIS" unique="true">
    <text>You arrive at the beacon and witness an ongoing battle between two Mantis ships. A lonely Pavonian ship is drifting through space, just far enough from the fight not to catch a stray shot.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attack one of the Mantis ships.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Just as you decided to make a move against one of the Mantis ships, its opponent exploded. The remaining Mantis ship moves into combat position, locking weapons on your ship.</text>
        <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_MANTIS" hostile="true">
          <destroyed>
            <text>With both Mantis ships destroyed, you harvest useful scrap material from the remains. You contact the Pavonians expecting a reward for helping them.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event>
                <text>The Pavonians pay you no notice. They didn't even consider themselves in danger.</text>
              </event>
            </choice>
          </destroyed>
          <deadCrew>
            <text>With one of the Mantis ships destroyed, and another disabled, you loot the ships. You contact the Pavonians expecting a reward for helping them.</text>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event>
                <text>The Pavonians pay you no notice. They didn't even consider themselves in danger.</text>
              </event>
            </choice>
          </deadCrew>
          <crew>
            <crewMember type="mantis" prop="0.80"/>
            <crewMember type="engi" prop="0.20"/>
          </crew>
        </ship>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Warn the Pavonians about possible danger.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You explain that after destroying its opponent, the winning Mantis ship might go after the Pavonians. "Oh..." The Pavonian ship jumps away.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Attack one of the Mantis ships.</text>
          <event>
            <text>Just as you decided to make a move against one of the Mantis ships, its opponent exploded. The remaining Mantis ship moves into combat position, locking weapons on your ship.</text>
            <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_MANTIS" hostile="true">
              <destroyed>
                <text>With both Mantis ships destroyed, you harvest useful scrap material from the remains.</text>
                <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
              </destroyed>
              <deadCrew>
                <text>With one of the Mantis ships destroyed, and another disabled, you loot the ships.</text>
                <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
              </deadCrew>
              <crew>
                <crewMember type="mantis" prop="0.80"/>
                <crewMember type="engi" prop="0.20"/>
              </crew>
            </ship>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Ignore the battle and jump away.</text>
          <event/>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Ignore the battle and jump away.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="PAVONIAN_LANIUS" unique="true">
    <text>A Lanius ship, rare guest outside of few sectors, is absorbing the wreck of some ship that's too late to identify. The Pavonian vessels are moving in the distance, without paying attention to either you or the Lanius.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attack the Lanius, someone has to stop them.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Acknowledging you as a threat, the Lanius ship stops collecting scrap metal and locks its weapons on your ship.</text>
        <ship load="LANIUS_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Leave the Lanius alone.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="PAVONIAN_WASTE" unique="true">
    <text>A lonely Pavonian ship awaits you at the beacon. It completely ignores you, drifting through space. Suddenly, its airlocks open, and a huge pile of waste is ejected. It is flying right at your ship!</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Evasive maneuvers!</text>
      <event>
        <text>Your pilot tried their best, but the pile of waste still manages to hit your ship. No serious damage was done to the hull, but the Pavonians must still pay for that.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Confront the Pavonian ship.</text>
          <event load="PAVONIAN_WASTE_CONFRONT"/>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="engines" lvl="4">
      <text>(Improved Engines) Full thrust!</text>
      <event>
        <text>The pile of waste misses your cruiser. But just dumping your waste into space is gross and unacceptable.</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Confront the Pavonian ship.</text>
          <event load="PAVONIAN_WASTE_CONFRONT"/>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Collect the waste, there could be something useful there.</text>
          <eventList>
            <event>
              <text>To your surprise, you managed to find a functioning weapon and some scrap in the pile of junk.</text>
              <autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>To your disappointment, all of the waste turned out to be biological. No scrap metal was found.</text>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text>Confront the Pavonian ship.</text>
                <event load="PAVONIAN_WASTE_CONFRONT"/>
              </choice>
              <choice hidden="true" req="WEAPONS_FLAK">
                <text>(Flak Gun) Load the waste as ammunition and launch it into Pavonian ship.</text>
                <event>
                  <text>The Pavonians were not expecting THAT. A chunk of their ship's hull has fallen off, and they turn towards you, arming their weapons.</text>
                  <ship hostile="true" load="PAVONIAN_SHIP"/>
                </event>
              </choice>
            </event>
          </eventList>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <event name="PAVONIAN_WASTE_CONFRONT">
    <text>There are no words "illegal", "outlawed" or "consequence" in Pavonian language, and they struggle to understand that they did something wrong. They don't even apologize and completely ignore your demands to pay for the damage their waste has done to your ship and, most importantly, your feelings.</text>
    <ship hostile="false" load="PAVONIAN_SHIP"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attack the ship.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Let the Pavonians go this time.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="PAVONIAN_BEGGAR" unique="true">
    <text>The only ship at the beacon is controlled by Pavonians. Their negotiator appears on the comm: "Scrap. We need it. Please give us some scrap."</text>
    <ship load="PAVONIAN_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Send them some scrap.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The Pavonians look pleased. "Thank you so much, mystery benefactor. We don't have anything to pay you with, but please follow us. You won't be disappointed." The Pavonian ship jumps away.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="scrap" min="-14" max="-9"/>
        </item_modify>
        <quest event="PAVONIAN_REWARD_QUEST"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Attack the extortioners.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Ignore the ship.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>
