<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="HOSTILE_ZOLTAN">
    <event load="ZOLTAN_FIGHT" count="2"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_PIRATE"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_MANTIS"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_ENGI"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS_MANTIS"/>

    <event load="REBEL"/>
    <event load="REBEL_AUTO"/>
  </eventList>

  <eventList name="HOSTILE_HAZARD_ZOLTAN">
    <event load="ZOLTAN_ASTEROID"/>
    <event load="AUTO_ASTEROID"/>
    <event load="REBEL_PULSAR"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_FIGHT">
    <textList name="ZOLTAN_FIGHT">
      <text>A Zoltan ship makes contact. "The nature of the day is rotational. The fever is emaciated. The reason is-" They've caught some nasty deep space dementia. Before you can consider finding help for them, they open fire.</text>
      <text>You're surprised when a stationary Zoltan ship opens fire. It appears there are aggressive pugilists even among the 'enlightened'.</text>
      <text>You receive a message, "This area is off limits. Submit your ship to processing." It's only one guard ship in a lonely beacon. You decide to fight your way out.</text>
      <text>You discover a number of Zoltan civilian ships fighting off pirates. Unfortunately one ship mistakes your purpose and moves in to attack! They are refusing all communication; you have no choice but to fight.</text>
      <text>Like many areas in Zoltan space, the residents of this sector prepared well for Galactic war. The military here seem to have given up reasoning with foreigners, preferring instead to attack on sight!</text>
      <text>A Zoltan ship is waiting at this beacon. They request your identification, but radiation from the sun in this system is disrupting your communications. They take your silence for aggression and move in to attack.</text>
      <text>The Zoltan ship patrolling this area hails you: "This area is off limits. Secrecy is vital." They power their weapons.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_PIRATE">
    <textList name="ZOLTAN_PIRATE">
      <text>"Emergency, all ships in range, we are under attack!" The frequency matches a nearby Zoltan ship; you move in on their pursuer. They take your intervention as a cue to jump away. Cowards.</text>
      <text>You jump just in time to witness a Zoltan ship's FTL drive overload. In his final moments their captain implores you not to get involved, but it's too late - their attacker is already upon you!</text>
      <text>Despite their precautions, pirates have begun to harass the local Zoltan settlements across this sector. One such pirate spots your ship and moves in to attack.</text>
      <text>A ship with pirate markings demands your surrender. These are sad times when even Zoltan space is beset by pirates. You doubt these fools will be missed.</text>
      <text>You spot a pirate ship looting a small Zoltan cruiser. They spot you and move in to attack before your FTL drive has a chance to recharge.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_MANTIS" unique="true">
    <text>You pick up the last broadcast from a rupturing Zoltan freighter: "The Mantis, they're here, please-" You're interrupted by fire off the port bow!</text>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_ENGI" unique="true">
    <text>You jump into a debris field that used to be a Zoltan cruiser. Unfortunately, its Engi escort takes you for the attacker and retaliates! They refuse all hails.</text>
    <ship load="ENGI_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_ASTEROID" unique="false">
    <text>You arrive in an asteroid field and are greeted by a Zoltan guard, "By attempting to access these closed mining fields, you are in violation of the Natural Mineral Protection Act. Your weaponry will be confiscated for processing." You don't have time for this.</text>
    <environment type="asteroid"/>
    <ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS" unique="true">
    <text>There are few more zealous in their customs checks than the Zoltan. A team of border police beam on board. There's just a little confusion over your weapons licences, but things escalate rapidly from heated discussion to gunfire!</text>
    <ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
    <boarders min="3" max="4" class="energy"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS_MANTIS" unique="true">
    <text>The Mantis outcasts sometimes make the mistake of taking the Zoltan for easy game. A scout moves in to attack while a boarding party beams aboard from a nearby transport!</text>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
    <boarders min="2" max="3" class="mantis"/>
  </event>
</FTL>