<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <event name="START_BEACON_ZOLTAN_INSPECTION">
    <textList>
      <text>You've entered Zoltan territory. This species is not renowned for giving anything for nothing, but you can always be assured a fair hearing.</text>
      <text>The Zoltan patrol their borders but let you pass when you ID as Federation. Let's hope they won't be so courteous to the Rebels.</text>
      <text>You arrive in Zoltan space. From what you have heard they anticipated the coming war and made preparations to hold their borders.</text>
      <text>You're far from Federation home space here in Zoltan territory, and it's not clear whether the authorities will have any goodwill remaining. Still, you have to push forward.</text>
    </textList>
  </event>

  <event name="START_BEACON_ZOLTAN_HAZARD">
    <text>This sector is notorious as a place where spaceships get lost. The nebula is particularly unstable here, making any attempt to transit dangerous. The Zoltans can tolerate the harsh conditions but even they have difficulty controlling the most isolated worlds.</text>
  </event>

  <event name="STORE_ZOLTAN">
    <textList>
      <text>The Zoltan are fascinated by other species, and have set up something of an alien knick-knack shop here. Why not take a look?</text>
      <text>A human ship hails: "My friends! Please, there is nothing I don't have, and there is nothing worth wanting that I can't get. Why not take a look around my shop?"</text>
    </textList>
    <store/>
  </event>

  <event name="NEBULA_STORE_ZOLTAN">
    <text>A Mantis crew here has hunkered down in the abdomen of a long-dead space-whale - the only way, presumably, for them to operate their black-market trade without detection. Worth a look?</text>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <store/>
  </event>

  <event name="NOTHING_ZOLTAN">
    <textList name="NOTHING_ZOLTAN">
      <text>There are some mineral-rich asteroids here that the Zoltan have left idle, but you've none of the necessary equipment to mine them.</text>
      <text>You have to admit - Zoltan space is a beautiful and peaceful place indeed. However, re-engaging the FTL and finishing your mission is your priority, not sight-seeing.</text>
      <text>A light asteroid field is entering the atmosphere of a nearby planet - a fireworks show on a galactic scale. There's little for it but to take in the ambience and program the next jump.</text>
      <text>You stumble upon some Zoltan military vessels engaging in combat training. Their Energy Shields are impressive, but you note how quickly beam and ion weaponry take them down.</text>
      <text>You don't have time to hail the Zoltan ship that was waiting at this beacon before it jumps away. They are a careful race.</text>
      <text>A Zoltan shipyard is stationed at this beacon. You admire the display of hundreds of glowing Zoltan performing delicate exterior work on a massive transport ship.</text>
      <text>A message broadcast from a nearby planet announces the presence of an ancient Zoltan monastery available for visiting. Likely just a tourist trap, but still too bad you don't have the time to visit.</text>
    </textList>
  </event>

  <ship name="ZOLTAN_SHIP" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_ZOLTAN">
    <surrender chance="0.5" min="3" max="4" load="ZOLTAN_SURRENDER"/>
    <escape chance="0.5" min="2" max="4" load="PIRATE_ESCAPE"/>
    <destroyed load="DESTROYED_DEFAULT"/>
    <deadCrew load="DEAD_CREW_DEFAULT"/>
  </ship>

  <ship name="ZOLTAN_PIRATE" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_ZOLTAN_PIRATE">
    <surrender chance="0.5" min="3" max="4" load="PIRATE_SURRENDER"/>
    <escape chance="0.5" min="2" max="4" load="PIRATE_ESCAPE"/>
    <destroyed load="DESTROYED_DEFAULT"/>
    <gotaway>
      <text>The pirate jumped away.</text>
    </gotaway>
    <deadCrew load="DEAD_CREW_DEFAULT"/>
  </ship>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_SURRENDER">
    <textList name="ZOLTAN_SURRENDER">
      <text>"Yes, yes, you've demonstrated your species' capacity for violence quite extensively, well done. If we reward your efforts will you bother someone else?"</text>
      <text>The enemy ship hails; the vidscreen shows their bridge showered in sparks from malfunctioning equipment - it's safe to assume they're trying to surrender. Accept their offer?</text>
      <text>Communications report that the Zoltan are broadcasting on all frequencies. The captain appears on screen and says, "Yes, I am not surprised, your species hardly looks enlightened. Fine. Take what you wish."</text>
      <text>The Zoltan captain hails and mutters something about the border patrol force catching up with you someday; you're more interested in his offer of surrender.</text>
      <text>"We assumed that your species' intelligence was directly proportional to your brute strength. We yield."</text>
      <text>"You have bested us. If only your species' efforts were put to use improving the galaxy rather than your military might."</text>
    </textList>
    <choice>
      <text>Accept their offer.</text>
      <event>
        <ship hostile="false"/>
        <autoReward level="RANDOM">stuff</autoReward>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>We will not accept surrender!</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>