<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="HOSTILE_ZOLTAN">
    <event load="ZOLTAN_FIGHT"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_PIRATE"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_MANTIS"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_ENGI"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS_MANTIS"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_CREW_SCAN"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_FIGHT"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_FIGHT">
    <textList name="ZOLTAN_FIGHT">
      <text>A Zoltan ship makes contact. "The nature of the day is rotational. The fever is emaciated. The reason is-" They've caught some nasty deep space dementia. Before you can consider finding help for them, they open fire.</text>
      <text>You're surprised when a stationary Zoltan ship opens fire. It appears there are aggressive pugilists even among the 'enlightened'.</text>
      <text>You receive a message, "This area is off limits. Submit your ship to processing." It's only one guard ship in a lonely beacon. You decide to fight your way out.</text>
      <text>You discover a number of Zoltan civilian ships fighting off pirates. Unfortunately one ship mistakes your purpose and moves in to attack! They are refusing all communication; you have no choice but to fight.</text>
      <text>Like many areas in Zoltan space, the residents of this sector prepared well for Galactic war. The military here seem to have given up reasoning with foreigners, preferring instead to attack on sight!</text>
      <text>A Zoltan ship is waiting at this beacon. They request your identification, but radiation from the sun in this system is disrupting your communications. They take your silence for aggression and move in to attack.</text>
      <text>The Zoltan ship patrolling this area hails you: "This area is off limits. Secrecy is vital." They power their weapons.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_PIRATE">
    <textList name="ZOLTAN_PIRATE">
      <text>"Emergency, all ships in range, we are under attack!" The frequency matches a nearby Zoltan ship; you move in on their pursuer. They take your intervention as a cue to jump away. Cowards.</text>
      <text>You jump just in time to witness a Zoltan ship's FTL drive overload. In his final moments their captain implores you not to get involved, but it's too late - their attacker is already upon you!</text>
      <text>Despite their precautions, pirates have begun to harass the local Zoltan settlements across this sector. One such pirate spots your ship and moves in to attack.</text>
      <text>A ship with pirate markings demands your surrender. These are sad times when even Zoltan space is beset by pirates. You doubt these fools will be missed.</text>
      <text>You spot a pirate ship looting a small Zoltan cruiser. They spot you and move in to attack before your FTL drive has a chance to recharge.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_MANTIS" unique="true">
    <text>You pick up the last broadcast from a rupturing Zoltan freighter: "The Mantis, they're here, please-" You're interrupted by fire off the port bow!</text>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_ENGI" unique="true">
    <text>You jump into a debris field that used to be a Zoltan cruiser. Unfortunately, its Engi escort takes you for the attacker and retaliates! They refuse all hails.</text>
    <ship load="ENGI_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS" unique="true">
    <text>There are few more zealous in their customs checks than the Zoltan. A team of border police beam on board. There's just a little confusion over your weapons licences, but things escalate rapidly from heated discussion to gunfire!</text>
    <ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
    <boarders min="3" max="3" class="energy"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS_MANTIS" unique="true">
    <text>The Mantis outcasts sometimes make the mistake of taking the Zoltan for easy game. A scout moves in to attack while a boarding party beams aboard from a nearby transport!</text>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
    <boarders min="2" max="3" class="mantis"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_CREW_SCAN" unique="true">
    <text>You arrive at a Zoltan security checkpoint set up in a perimeter around the beacon. "Travelling vessel, you will submit to crew profiling to identify fugitives of the empire."</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>You don't have time for this nonsense. Attack!</text>
      <event>
        <text>Expecting resistance, their Energy Shield is raised and ready for combat.</text>
        <ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Submit to profiling.</text>
      <eventList name="ZOLTAN_CREW_SCAN_LIST">
        <event>
          <text>The Zoltan security staff board your ship and scan the crew's faces into a computer. After a few tense moments of uncertainty they allow your ship to pass.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The Zoltan security staff board your ship and begin scanning the crew's faces into a computer. Suddenly alarms go off and the Zoltan leap on one of your crew! "This person is wanted on five charges of Utter Villainy! Surrender them to us!"</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Give up your crewmember.</text>
            <event>
              <text>It's a tough call, but Zoltan law holds sway here. Besides, that one always seemed a bit shifty.</text>
              <removeCrew>
                <clone>false</clone>
                <text>Unfortunately your crewmember was taken away unharmed so your Clone Bay was unable to retrieve them.</text>
              </removeCrew>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Refuse and fight.</text>
            <event>
              <text>You're not going to leave anyone behind. You pull away from the station with the enemy guards on board. Unfortunately, they are able to sabotage your weapon system in the chaos. It's time to leave!</text>
              <ship name="ZOLTAN_CREW_SCAN" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_ZOLTAN" hostile="true">
                <destroyed>
                  <text>You scrap what you can and prepare to jump before the other guards arrive.</text>
                  <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
                  <status type="clear" target="player" system="weapons" amount="100"/>
                </destroyed>
                <deadCrew>
                  <text>You scrap what you can and prepare to jump before the other guards arrive.</text>
                  <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
                  <status type="clear" target="player" system="weapons" amount="100"/>
                </deadCrew>
              </ship>
              <boarders min="2" max="3" class="energy"/>
              <status type="divide" target="player" system="weapons" amount="2"/>
            </event>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="slug">
      <text>(Slug Crew) Have your Slug talk them into letting you go.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You give the guards permission to dock with the ship, but before they come on board your crewmember slowly advances to meet them. As far as you can tell no words were exchanged, but the guards offer you some supplies and say the ship checks out. Best to not ask questions.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">fuel_only</autoReward>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="mind">
      <text>(Mind Control) Make the guards believe they have already checked your crew today.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The captain of the guard appears on the vid screen "Back so soon friend! Well, no need to waste your time further. Here, take these spare fuel canisters and get on with your mission." Your ship is cleared to pass.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">fuel_only</autoReward>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_RIFT_FIGHT" unique="true">
    <text>You come to a quiet part of Zoltan space and encounter an ancient Zoltan wise man who has managed to harness the power of a spatial rift, but seems to have been driven completely mad by the power. "Choose your doom," he demands. This is all part of a day's work.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Mantis.</text>
      <event>
        <text>"You like a challenge. So be it!" A wormhole forms and a confused, angry Mantis ship hurtles toward you!</text>
        <ship name="ZOLTAN_RIFT_MANTIS" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_MANTIS" hostile="true">
          <destroyed>
            <text>You salvage the remains and contact the wise man.</text>
            <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_SUCCESS"/>
            </choice>
          </destroyed>
          <deadCrew>
            <text>You salvage the ship and contact the wise man.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_SUCCESS"/>
            </choice>
          </deadCrew>
          <crew>
            <crewMember type="mantis" prop="0.80"/>
            <crewMember type="engi" prop="0.20"/>
          </crew>
        </ship>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Slug.</text>
      <event>
        <text>"Do not be fooled, Federation, by a soft underbelly." You detect a wormhole opening up, and seconds later a Slug ship is attacking from the other direction!</text>
        <ship name="ZOLTAN_RIFT_SLUG" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_JELLY" hostile="true">
          <destroyed>
            <text>You salvage the remains and contact the wise man.</text>
            <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_SUCCESS"/>
            </choice>
          </destroyed>
          <deadCrew>
            <text>You salvage the ship and contact the wise man.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_SUCCESS"/>
            </choice>
          </deadCrew>
        </ship>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Rockmen.</text>
      <event>
        <text>"A hardened foe for a hardened veteran." You detect a wormhole opening up, and a Rock ship appears with guns blazing. It appears they were in combat when they were thrust across space-time.</text>
        <ship name="ZOLTAN_RIFT_ROCK" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_ROCK" hostile="true">
          <destroyed>
            <text>You salvage the remains and contact the wise man.</text>
            <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_SUCCESS"/>
            </choice>
          </destroyed>
          <deadCrew>
            <text>You salvage the ship and contact the wise man.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
            <choice hidden="true">
              <text id="continue"/>
              <event load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_SUCCESS"/>
            </choice>
          </deadCrew>
        </ship>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <event name="ZOLTAN_RIFT_SUCCESS">
    <text>When he sees you have emerged victorious, the Zoltan wise man enters a rage. Rifts threaten to tear space apart until, instead, the Zoltan implodes, sending a blast wave of scrap and salvage dragged here from distant worlds in your direction.</text>
    <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
  </event>
</FTL>