<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="ITEMS_ZOLTAN">
    <event load="ZOLTAN_FREE_AUGMENT"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_FREE_MAP"/>
    <event load="ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_FREE_AUGMENT" unique="true">
    <text>A Zoltan academy sits docked just outside the beacon perimeter. They're happy to show you the fruits of their labor, and offer something to take home with you.</text>
    <autoReward level="LOW">augment</autoReward>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_FREE_MAP" unique="true">
    <text>The Zoltan stationed near this beacon are happy to receive you. As they give you the formal tour of their ship you spy some local star charts and mentally log the details.</text>
    <reveal_map/>
    <ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
  </event>

  <event name="ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON" unique="true">
    <text>Something strikes you as odd about a moon in the distance.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Check it out.</text>
      <eventList name="ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON_CHECK">
        <event>
          <text>A closer inspection reveals signs of habitation on the surface, but nothing else particularly interesting.</text>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Sending a shuttle to explore a beckoning cave system you discover signs of a battle - and a still-functioning weapon!</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>A deep scan of the surface reveals a cave system that runs for miles, and what looks like a scrap heap left over from some heavy-duty construction.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>It looks as if a team could break through the fragile layer of the moon's surface into a hidden cavern.</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text>Attempt to detonate some explosives to break through the surface. [ Missiles: -1 ]</text>
            <eventList name="ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON_EXPLOSION">
              <event>
                <text>A portion of the surface layer is destroyed in an impressive display, revealing miles of caves. You don't have time to fully explore them, but you find some remains of an old subterranean base that could be useful.</text>
                <item_modify>
                  <item type="missiles" min="-1" max="-1"/>
                </item_modify>
                <autoReward level="RANDOM">scrap_only</autoReward>
              </event>
              <event>
                <text>The explosives are set remotely, but the detonation achieves nothing. What a waste.</text>
                <item_modify>
                  <item type="missiles" min="-1" max="-1"/>
                </item_modify>
              </event>
              <event>
                <text>Your explosives reveal the 'cave' is actually a secret base, located in a network of bunkers just under the surface. Everyone inside is dead; some Mantis clearly came through here recently. It looks like the Zoltan were researching advanced ship weaponry. You take one of their better examples back to your ship.</text>
                <autoReward level="RANDOM">weapon</autoReward>
                <item_modify>
                  <item type="missiles" min="-1" max="-1"/>
                </item_modify>
              </event>
            </eventList>
          </choice>
          <choice>
            <text>Explosives are too valuable to waste on excavation work. Let's get out of here.</text>
            <event/>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Leave it be.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You try not to fixate on the moon in the aft scanner as you set the coordinates for the next jump.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="BOARDER_LIST">
      <text>(Boarding Drone) Send a drone to probe the surface.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Initial scans indicate a network of caves not far underground. You launch a boarding drone and it breaks through the surface into the cavern below.</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="drones" min="-1" max="-1"/>
        </item_modify>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text id="continue"/>
          <event>
            <text>Your drone discovers a vast cave network and evidence of excavation. Buried deep below you find a Zoltan scientist, still hard at work. He tells you that all his colleagues are long dead. You decide not to ask questions and offer to let him join your crew.</text>
            <crewMember amount="1" class="energy"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>