<metadata>
  <title>First Contact</title>
  <threadUrl>none</threadUrl>
  <author>Woona</author>
  <version>0.1</version>
  <description>REQUIRES HYPERSPACE 0.5+ (https://subsetgames.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=35095)

THIS MOD IS NOT COMPATIBLE WITH ANYTHING (except Hyperspace, and minor cosmetic mods)
(even if some mod is recommended below, it's not compatible with this one)

CREDITS:
* SwiftTiger, Winderps: making Hyperspace (https://subsetgames.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=35095)
* Vhati: making Slipstream Mod Manager (https://subsetgames.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=17102)
* kartoFlane: making Superluminal 2 (https://subsetgames.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=24901)
* Laythe: enemy sprites (1 Crystal enemy, 1 Lanius enemy, 1 Zoltan enemy, 1 Orchid enemy, 1 Pavonian enemy) from Multiverse (https://subsetgames.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=35332)
* kix: miniships, ship layouts
* Twinge: balance mod that had some parts included (https://subsetgames.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=26269)
* Mike: bugfix mod that had some parts included (https://subsetgames.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=35599)
* Snorlaxxo: Orchid recolors
* AgentTheKat: flat sprites, ideas, feedback
* SallySpartan: ideas, feedback (also try Eldrich Horrors http://www.subsetgames.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=35928)
* bamalf, KBa3u: testing, ideas, feedback (еще попробуйте Arsenal+ https://vk.com/topic-69423402_31433485)
* Markus: ideas, feedback

FEATURE OVERVIEW:
* New content: 4 new races!, playable ships, enemy ships, sectors, events, all kinds of equipment
* Game is rebalanced and became harder overall
* Enemies switch to other weapons after running out of missiles (but they have fewer missiles)
* Simple but rewarding weapon/drone upgrade system
* No empty beacons!

DETAILED FEATURES:
1. Weapons
1.1. A new upgrade system, each weapon that costs 2 power or more can be upgraded, cutting its power cost by 1, and dropping charge time a bit as a bonus, weapons can be upgraded on special upgrade beacons which are marked on the map. Common enemies cannot use upgraded weapons. Upgraded weapons won't be just sold at the store or randomly dropped, but many playable ships start with them.
1.2. Nerfed some of more powerful weapons, for example, burst laser 2 has its charge time increased to 13, and power cost increased to 3. You have to upgrade it to get the good old one. On the bright side, the enemies can only use the weak version.
1.3. Rebalanced flak weapons: now all of them have a very long charge time, but more projectiles. For example, flak 1 has 18 seconds charge time, but 4 projectiles. Flak weapons synergize well with long-charging beams. This change makes them differ from fast-charging lasers that fire fewer projectiles.
1.4. Crystal weapons were changed to differentiate them from lasers, too. Every crystal deals 2 damage and causes a hull breach.
1.5. Many of ion weapons got buffed. Basic ion and Ion charger stayed the same as before, all of the other weapons got stronger.
1.6. Bombs are rebalanced according to new rules: 1 bomb, 1 power, 1 effect (with some rare exceptions). Many bombs also recharge much faster to fit their boarding support role better. For example, fire bomb costs 1 power and doesn't do anything but start a fire, charges 10 seconds. Small bomb just does 2 system damage, and nothing else.
1.7. Missile weapons got many buffs. Only Artemis (which can be bought now) and Swarm stayed the same. Many missile launchers have useful secondary effects now. But what about the enemies? Won't they harass me with overpowered missiles and bombs at no cost now?

2. Enemies
2.1. Each enemy class has a fixed loadout now, they don't just get completely random weapons like before. For example, Rebel Fighter will always have 2 lasers and a missile. But which missile or which laser they get is still random.
2.2. Enemy strategy regarding missiles changed: they have more weapons than they could possibly power, they will use the missile weapons until they run out of resources, then start using one of conventional weapons which don't use resources. Our Rebel Fighter example will start the battle with 1 laser, 1 missile and then switch to 2 lasers.
2.3. Every enemy that uses missile weapons has much less missile resources than before. In sector 1 every enemy has just 1. They will fire their only missile and switch to something else without ruining your run. In late game, enemies can have more, especially Rockmen. Enemies that use bomb weapons can have more missile resources, too.
2.4. Since there's a lot less randomness regarding enemy weapon loadouts, there are more enemy classes now. Each with a new hull design, room layout and personality.
2.5. You can encounter special enemies at some events, for example, Black Raven belonging to Captain Nights.
2.6. All of Rebel Elites got much stronger than before. They took their time to upgrade ALL of their weapons and drones, so you should think twice before diving.
2.7. Because of big changes to enemy generation mechanics, easy and normal difficulties became much harder. You still get more scrap rewards on those difficulties, but enemies are much deadlier now.

3. Drones
3.1. Drones can be upgraded the same way the weapons can. Upgraded drones require 1 less power (no other buffs).
3.2. New powerful drones to make the drone control system more desirable in general, for example, anti-ship ion drone.
3.3. Most drones were heavily discounted to make them more viable (no drones are more expensive than before).
3.4. In addition, drones got indirect buffs through Drone recovery arm and ion weapon buffs (drones can't be buffed directly not to make them too powerful on enemies)

4. Augmentations
4.1. Most augmentations in FTL suck. You get them as a random drop, and sell them at the nearest store. This had to be changed.
4.2. Those augmentations that can be improved by making them a bit stronger, were buffed: Crystal vengeance, Drone reactor booster, FTL Recharge booster, and others.
4.3. Most augmentations were discounted. They're either cheaper or stayed the same, none got more expensive.
4.4. Those augmentations that allow interesting strategies like Explosive replicator or are Drone recovery arm easier to find. Those that can only be used for selling like Hacking stun, are harder to find.
4.5. Starting augmentations can't be sold. In addition, many ships start with upgraded weapons and drones, so selling starting equipment became much less viable.
4.6. Advanced FTL Navigation can be used to travel to any beacon on the sector map (instead of just previously visited beacons) at no additional cost. It's very powerful in combination with early full sector map, useful for diving, and for bad sector layouts, but not that great without these synergies.
4.7. Drone reactor booster buffed and made obtainable.
4.8. Long ranged scanners are unobtainable and unique for race focused on stealth. This is meant to make stealth ship gameplay even more unique.
4.9. Scrap recovery arm is made unique for Lanius ships that start with them. This is done to make Lanius stand out from other races, and to enhance their scrap hoarder theme.
4.10. Repair arm made unobtainable and unique for new race focused on regeneration. This augmentation was often sold, unless the ship was already fully upgraded. Now, you either start with repair arm, can't get rid of it and plan accordingly, or you just never find it.
4.11. New augmentation: Nanobot Defense System (deals damage to boarders on your ship) - added by Hyperspace.
4.12. New augmentation: Missile Recycler (additional 2 missiles for each defeated ship) - added to make missiles more viable, as an alternative to Explosive replicator
4.13. New augmentation: Engine Disabler (limits enemy engines to 1) - added as a weak alternative to pilot hack/mind control

5. Artillery
5.1. Artillery always seemed a bit underwhelming. The beam broke the rules of the game a bit by piercing all shields, but was still very low damage. Flak artillery seemed like Flak 2 but way worse.
5.2. Artillery got MUCH stronger, it should win the battle after first shot. To compensate, it's more expensive to upgrade.
5.3. Fed A and Fed B have different artillery weapons to make those ships feel different from each other.

6. Races and their preferred strategies
6.1. To make room for more new fun races, some of the old races got their strategies narrowed down a bit. I made an effort to make a strong theme for each race - new and old.
6.2. Engi - defensive drones (combat and internal drones will be used by new races)
6.3. Mantis - teleporter and bomb weapons
6.4. Rockmen - heavy hitting missiles and heavy lasers (no piercing weapons, those are saved for Crystals)
6.5. Zoltan - 0 shields to make use of energy shield, 0 reactor to make use of innate power, strong beam and ion weaponry
6.6. Slugs - mind control and anti-bio weapons to make use of their signature lifeform detection
6.7. Crystals - shield-piercing crystal weapons, lockdown
6.8. Lanius - hacking, Lanius didn't really have a strong theme, now they went all-in with hacking

7. Other balance changes
7.1. Hacking drone depowering exploit was fixed in Hyperspace. The drone just gets destroyed when depowered.
7.2. It was a very common strategy to just wait for several minutes on weaker enemies to train your crew. To combat this without changing how training works, there should be fewer enemies that cannot damage you.
7.3. Many systems are more expensive to buy or upgrade: artillery, hacking, shields, engines, piloting.
7.4. Backup battery can be upgraded up to level 3 to provide a fun alternative to reactor upgrades.
7.5. Rebel Flagship is a bit harder now: all of its rooms are connected including artillery rooms on all difficulty levels, and Flagship lasers do 2 damage instead of 1.

8. Events
8.1. We can all agree that hitting an empty beacon is a bit disappointing. So, most of them are removed.
8.2. Boarding events are just as boring as empty beacons. Once you dealt with them a couple times, there is no challenge or variety. Most boarding events are removed, with rare exceptions.
8.3. Weapon upgrade beacons serve as a partial replacement for empty beacons and boarding events. They're marked on the map, so you do not have to visit those unless you need an upgrade (with rare exceptions of bad sector generation).
8.4. Many more new events, new blue options for old events, more possible outcomes for old events.

9. Sectors
9.1. We can all agree that going into the same sector type 2 (or more) times in a row makes the game less exciting.
9.2. Most of the sector types are unique now. There are 3 filler sector types: civilian, rebel controlled and uncharted nebula (they're needed to prevent game crashes). All of the other sectors can be visited only once per game.
9.3. There are 2 sectors in the pool per race: for example, Engi Research Hub is a more peaceful sector, with more opportunities for trading and ship upgrades. Engi Contested Worlds is a war zone, Mantis and Rebels are invading, and the Engis living in the sector are in need of your help.
9.4. Events are more dependant on sector type. Generic events are contained to generic sectors (like sector one).

CHANGELOG</description>
</metadata>