<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <changelog>
    <entry>Unique Black Raven ship for DONOR_BLACK_RAVEN event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="DONOR_BLACK_RAVEN" unique="true">
    <text>As you jump in, you immediately see an impressive Slug pirate ship with "The Black Raven" painted on one side. They hail you, "Greetingsss. I am the dreaded pirate, Captain Nights. You mussst be full of fear, no? You have heard of me... no?"</text>
    <environment type="nebula"/>
    <ship name="DONOR_BLACK_RAVEN" auto_blueprint="SLUG_BLACK_RAVEN_LIST" hostile="false">
      <surrender chance="0" min="3" max="4">
        <text>"I see the rumorsss are true. I yield, we are no match for you. Take this and let us leave in ssshame."</text>
        <choice>
          <text>Accept his surrender.</text>
          <event>
            <text>He transfers over the goods and starts to repair his ship.</text>
            <ship hostile="false"/>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice>
          <text>Ignore him and attack.</text>
          <event>
            <text>"Wait! There is no need to be...." You cut off the transmission and prepare to fire.</text>
          </event>
        </choice>
      </surrender>
      <destroyed>
        <text>"The Black Raven" breaks apart and you salvage the remains.</text>
        <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      </destroyed>
      <deadCrew>
        <text>The once-dreaded pirate Nights has been killed and you proceed to loot his ship.</text>
        <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
      </deadCrew>
    </ship>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>No.</text>
      <event>
        <text>"Well I have heard of you and I must see if you are as dangerousss as they say. I challenge you!"</text>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Accept his challenge.</text>
          <event>
            <ship hostile="true"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true">
          <text>Decline.</text>
          <event>
            <text>"I sssee... However you have no choice in the matter!" They move in to attack.</text>
            <ship hostile="true"/>
          </event>
        </choice>
        <choice hidden="true" req="slug">
          <text>(Slug Crew) Engage in a duel of the mind.</text>
          <eventList name="DONOR_BLACK_RAVEN_SLUG">
            <event>
              <text>Your Slug crewman's eyes glaze over as the two telepaths concentrate. You can only wonder what is happening. After a short time your comrade grunts in pain and collapses onto the floor, stunned. Nights responds, "Hah! It'll take more than that to defeat me! Let the real battle begin!"</text>
              <ship hostile="true"/>
              <boarders min="1" max="2" class="slug"/>
            </event>
            <event>
              <text>Your Slug crewman's eyes glaze over as the two telepaths concentrate. You are powerless to help, but after a short time your comrade shakes off the daze and appears victorious.</text>
              <choice hidden="true">
                <text id="continue"/>
                <event>
                  <text>His face contorted with pain, Nights concedes his defeat: "If this is the caliber of subordinatesss you keep, there iss no way we can defeat you. Take thisss and let us leave in shame."</text>
                  <autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
                </event>
              </choice>
            </event>
          </eventList>
        </choice>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>