<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="HOSTILE_SLUG">
    <event load="SLUG_FIGHT"/>
    <event load="SLUG_FREE_WEAPON_TRAP"/>
    <event load="SLUG_MANTIS"/>
    <event load="SLUG_PIRATE"/>
    <event load="SLUG_REBEL"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="SLUG_FIGHT" unique="true">
    <text>It's rare for the Slugs to stay exposed in open space for long periods - the ship here may be lost, or just passing through, but either way he moves in to attack!</text>
    <ship load="JELLY" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="SLUG_MANTIS" unique="true">
    <text>You intercept comm chatter from an incoming Mantis ship. "Look. This ship appears not to be owned by the squishy ones. Maybe they won't smell so bad when we cut them open." They move in on your position.</text>
    <ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="SLUG_PIRATE">
    <textList name="SLUG_PIRATE">
      <text>There appears to be a pirate ship nearby. Be on your guard; anyone trying to hunt in Slug territory is either formidable or deeply stupid, and in space, either can be dangerous.</text>
      <text>"We knew anyone foolish enough to try and sneak through a Slug nebula would stick to open space. Yield your goods and we may let you live." You cut the transmission in lieu of a response.</text>
      <text>Before you can take a moment's rest from the ever present nebulas in this sector, a pirate ship appears behind you and opens fire.</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <event name="SLUG_REBEL">
    <textList name="SLUG_REBEL">
      <text>As you arrive at the beacon, a hostile ship immediately registers on your scanners. You didn't expect to see Rebels extending their reach into Slug territory. Charge the weapons!</text>
      <text>You jump into empty space and are relieved to see your sensors blink back to life. However, you are less pleased to see them immediately register a rebel ship on an approach vector!</text>
      <text>You receive a message from a nearby ship, "Looks like our intelligence was correct! Sneaking through the clouds with the Slugs... No one can hide from the rebellion!"</text>
    </textList>
    <ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Slug free weapon trap event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="SLUG_FREE_WEAPON_TRAP" unique="true">
    <text planet="NONE">Holy crap! A weapon is just floating in space!</text>
    <autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text id="continue"/>
      <event>
        <text>As soon as you install the new gun, your weapon bay goes offline. It turns out that the weapon was booby trapped! A Slug ship outfitted for combat is detected by your sensors.</text>
        <ship hostile="true" load="SLUG_FREE_WEAPON_TRAP_SHIP"/>
        <status amount="0" system="weapons" target="player" type="limit"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="slug">
      <text>(Slug) Your crewmember senses that something is wrong.</text>
      <event>
        <text>Before installing the new weapon, your Slug crewmember checks it thoroughly, and finds a hidden device meant to disable your system. A Slug ship appears on a radar, with an intention to return the trapped weapon back.</text>
        <ship hostile="true" load="SLUG_FREE_WEAPON_TRAP_SHIP"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <ship auto_blueprint="SHIPS_JELLY" name="SLUG_FREE_WEAPON_TRAP_SHIP">
    <destroyed>
      <text>The Slug ship breaks apart and your systems return to normal. You collect what you can.</text>
      <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
      <status amount="100" system="weapons" target="player" type="clear"/>
    </destroyed>
    <deadCrew>
      <text>With their crew dead, your systems return to normal. You strip the ship.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      <status amount="100" system="weapons" target="player" type="clear"/>
    </deadCrew>
  </ship>
</FTL>