<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <event name="PIRATE_SURRENDER_CIVILAN">
    <text>The pirates must not have been fully committed to the assault; they have been charging their FTL. They jump away, presumably to repair their ship.</text>
    <ship hostile="false"/>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Hail the civilian ship.</text>
      <event load="SAVE_CIVILIAN_LIST"/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <event name="PIRATE_CIVILIAN" unique="false">
    <textList name="PIRATE_CIVILIAN">
      <text planet="PLANET_POPULATED_SMALL">You arrive in the system to see a pirate ship pursuing a civilian ship. You detect messages from the civilian ship on a distress frequency.</text>
      <text>Scanners indicate that a battle is taking place nearby. It seems that someone is under attack by space pirates.</text>
      <text>You detect two ships, one chasing the other... Scanners show the pursuer is a pirate!</text>
      <text>There are only two ships within range and they seem to be engaged in battle. One of them has the markings of a space pirate.</text>
      <text>You arrive at the next beacon only to be immediately hailed by a small shuttle. "Help us! We are being attacked by pirates!"</text>
      <text>You come out of the jump to see laser blasts coming from the other side of the beacon. It looks like someone is under attack from pirates.</text>
    </textList>
    <img back="BACKGROUND" planet="PLANET_POPULATED"/>
    <choice>
      <text>Aid the civilian ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You power up your weapons and engage the pirate ship.</text>
        <ship load="PIRATE_CIVILIAN" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Stay out of it.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The fight brings them out of your immediate scanning range. After a time the distress calls stop.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added distress beacon to PIRATE_CIVILIAN_BEACON event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="PIRATE_CIVILIAN_BEACON">
    <text>The distress beacon is coming from a civilian ship. It appears it is being chased by a pirate.</text>
    <distressBeacon/>
    <choice>
      <text>Aid the civilian ship.</text>
      <event>
        <text>You power up your weapons and engage the pirate ship.</text>
        <ship load="PIRATE_CIVILIAN" hostile="true"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Stay out of it.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The fight brings them out of your immediate scanning range; however, after a time the distress calls stop.</text>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="weapons" lvl="6" hidden="true">
      <text>(Improved Weapons) Fire a warning shot from your strongest weapon.</text>
      <eventList name="PIRATE_CIVILIAN_BEACON_BEAM">
        <event>
          <text>Detecting the greater threat (and potential reward), they turn and engage your ship.</text>
          <ship load="PIRATE_CIVILIAN" hostile="true"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>It seems the pirate wasn't looking for a fight with someone who could fight back. They leave and you move to contact the civilian ship.</text>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text id="continue"/>
            <event load="SAVE_CIVILIAN_LIST"/>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
  </event>
  <ship name="PIRATE_CIVILIAN" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_PIRATE">
    <destroyed>
      <text>The pirate ship breaks apart. You hasten to contact the civilian ship.</text>
      <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Contact the civilian ship.</text>
        <event load="SAVE_CIVILIAN_LIST"/>
      </choice>
    </destroyed>
    <deadCrew>
      <text>No more life signs detected on the pirate ship. You hasten to contact the civilian ship.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
      <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Contact the civilian ship.</text>
        <event load="SAVE_CIVILIAN_LIST"/>
      </choice>
    </deadCrew>
  </ship>

  <eventList name="SAVE_CIVILIAN_LIST">
    <event>
      <text>The ship you saved was badly damaged in the battle. Most of the crew accepts your offer to be dropped off at a nearby station. One offers to join your crew.</text>
      <choice>
        <text>Welcome aboard!</text>
        <event>
          <text>The survivor gets on board the ship.</text>
          <crewMember amount="1"/>
        </event>
      </choice>
      <choice>
        <text>Decline their request.</text>
        <event/>
      </choice>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>Apparently the ship that was being assaulted was a science vessel. They thank you for saving them and offer a small reward.</text>
      <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>It seems the crew did not survive the assault. You take what you can from the remains of the ship.</text>
      <autoReward level="LOW">stuff</autoReward>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>They respond, "It's a good thing you came when you did; we'd be dead now otherwise. I'm a shipwright and I'd like to help you like you helped me."</text>
      <choice>
        <text>The captain offers to install a piece of equipment on your ship.</text>
        <event>
          <weapon name="RANDOM"/>
        </event>
      </choice>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>"This sector has become increasingly dangerous for friends of the Federation. I think my crew can patch up some of your hull damage as thanks."</text>
      <damage amount="-5"/>
    </event>
    <event>
      <text>The civilian ship wisely made a fast retreat while you distracted the hostile ship.</text>
    </event>
  </eventList>
</FTL>