<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FTL>
  <eventList name="NOSHIP_PIRATE">
    <event load="PIRATE_FREE_ITEMS"/>
    <event load="SELL_MISSILES_STATION"/>
    <event load="HITCHHIKER"/>
    <event load="DEAD_KESTREL"/>
  </eventList>

  <event name="PIRATE_FREE_ITEMS">
    <!-- text taken from FREE_ITEMS -->
    <text>You arrive in a system and immediately discover a pirate ship nearby. Strangely, scans indicate there are no lifeforms aboard. You salvage anything useful, but find no clue as to the whereabouts of the former crew.</text>
    <autoReward level="LOW">stuff</autoReward>
  </event>

  <event name="SELL_MISSILES_STATION" unique="true">
    <text>There is a black market hub here. You receive a message, "These are dangerous times. If you have extra military-grade explosives, we'll gladly pay you for them."</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Sell 5 missiles for 12 scrap.</text>
      <event>
        <text>"Thank you, this will help."</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="missiles" min="-5" max="-5"/>
          <item type="scrap" min="12" max="12"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Sell 10 missiles for 24 scrap.</text>
      <event>
        <text>"Thank you, this will help greatly."</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="missiles" min="-10" max="-10"/>
          <item type="scrap" min="24" max="24"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Sell 15 missiles for 36 scrap.</text>
      <event>
        <text>"Thank you, this will help greatly."</text>
        <item_modify>
          <item type="missiles" min="-15" max="-15"/>
          <item type="scrap" min="36" max="36"/>
        </item_modify>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>Ignore the station.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Hitchhiker event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="HITCHHIKER" unique="true">
    <text>You arrive to the beacon, but there are no ships or stations in sight. After a while, a human teleports to your bridge from somewhere. They are holding nothing but a towel in their hands. Claiming to be a hitchhiker, they offer to travel with you for some time.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Accept them into your crew.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The hitchhiker is reluctant to do any real work. Hopefully that will change the next time your ship goes on fire, or is swarmed by Mantis boarders.</text>
        <crewMember amount="1" class="human"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
      <text>This is Federation military, no hitchhikers allowed.</text>
      <event>
        <text>The hitchhiker refuses to leave your ship. Perhaps it is one of the Rebel agents and you have to kill them.</text>
        <boarders class="human" max="1" min="1"/>
      </event>
    </choice>
  </event>

  <changelog>
    <entry>Added Kestrel dead in space event</entry>
  </changelog>
  <event name="DEAD_KESTREL" unique="true">
    <text>You cannot believe what you see. A Kestrel-class ship! You hail them, but there is no response. Scans show no activity. Your crew is anxious to know what happened to our Federation allies.</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Board the ship.</text>
      <eventList>
        <event>
          <text>As you get closer to the Kestrel, some humans teleport into your ship. They are being aggressive and start damaging your systems. One of your crewmembers spots Rebel badges on unwanted passengers.</text>
          <boarders class="human" max="4" min="3"/>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You board the Kestrel with a support team. You search the ship and find out that the oxygen generation system is out of order. You search for crew, but find only several skeletons hugging in the medbay. Presumably they died of starvation.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Your team boards the Kestrel. The ship is relatively intact, the only system that took serious damage is a teleporter. The crew is nowhere to be found. One of your teammates suggests that they abandoned their ship for another.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You enter the Kestrel through the airlock. Surprisingly, it is open. Turns out that every single door on the ship is open. Your team finds the door control system, but it is blown up. What an unfortunate situation former crew found themselves in. You scrap the remains of the ship.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The boarding team enter deactivated Kestrel searching for anyone alive. All they find is half-eaten remains of several humans. You cannot imagine the horrors that had happened on a Federation ship.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>Closer examination shows that the Kestrel spaceship's hull is not intact. Its edges are torn up like they were eaten. Both from inside and outside. There is no explanation what had happened here. You harvest all resources that can be found.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>There is nobody alive on the Kestrel. Your team found the remains of former crew: two Mantis corpses with bad burns struggling to repair the life support system. You loot the ship and hope not to have similar fate.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>You board the Kestrel and find several bodies starved to death. The ship is intact, but completely lacks any FTL fuel. You collect the resources from the ship and leave a note to buy some fuel in the next store.</text>
          <autoReward level="LOW">missiles</autoReward>
        </event>
        <event>
          <text>The boarding team enters the inactive Kestrel. There are no people on board, but the ship is relatively undamaged. As you search the ship for resources, you find a malfunctioning clonebay. The system is of modern design, and even has a backup bank installed.</text>
          <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
          <choice hidden="true" req="clonebay">
            <text>(Clonebay) Copy data to your system and create a clone.</text>
            <event>
              <text>A Federation soldier steps out of the clonebay. "Our ship was overrun by boarders, they killed everyone, and destroyed a clonebay. I "lived" in a backup bank for months!" They agree to join your crew and help your mission.</text>
              <crewMember amount="1"/>
            </event>
          </choice>
          <choice hidden="true">
            <text id="continue"/>
            <event/>
          </choice>
        </event>
      </eventList>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
      <text>Give a ship a wide berth. It is probably a Rebel trap.</text>
      <event/>
    </choice>
  </event>
</FTL>